[Music]
[音乐]
When I grew up, everyone said to me that
我长大后，每个人都对我说：
to generate wealth, get a job, get
为了创造财富，找份工作，获得
money, then get a mortgage.
先攒够钱，然后申请抵押贷款。
&gt;&gt; That's one of the worst pieces of advice
这是最糟糕的建议之一。
you can give somebody. Your future self
你可以给别人。未来的自己
is going to be poorer because of it.
因此，他/她会变得更穷。
&gt;&gt; But that's what everyone's doing because
但大家都在这么做，因为
we're not taught this stuff. So, what do
我们没有学过这些东西。那么，该怎么办？
you think the biggest money mistake the
你认为最大的金钱错误是什么？
average person makes is?
普通人平均收入是多少？
&gt;&gt; Being a saver.
做一个储蓄者。
&gt;&gt; So, just having your money sat in a bank
所以，只是把钱存在银行里而已。
account.
帐户。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. It's a guaranteed loss. You're
是的。这是必然的损失。你是
becoming poor every single day. But
每天都在变得更穷。但
there are plenty of ways to retire early
有很多方法可以提前退休。
and be financially independent.
并实现经济独立。
&gt;&gt; And that's including secret hack that
这其中就包括秘密黑客攻击。
makes people fortunes. So, let's talk
使人一夜暴富。那么，我们来谈谈吧。
about making more money. This is the
关于如何赚更多钱。这是
ultimate money-making master class
终极赚钱大师班
&gt;&gt; as we are joined by three financial
我们还有三位金融界人士加入。
gurus
大师们
&gt;&gt; with very different opinions and methods
观点和方法截然不同
to build future wealth. So, I want to
积累未来财富。所以，我想
talk about pensions, credit cards,
谈谈养老金、信用卡，
renting, bad money habits, debt, passive
租房、不良理财习惯、债务、被动收入
income, spending money to look rich. But
收入，花钱让自己看起来很富有。但
first, what is it that rich people know
首先，富人究竟知道些什么？
that the average person doesn't know?
普通人不知道的？
&gt;&gt; Rich people are more disciplined and
富人更有自律性，
they're doing the little things that
他们正在做一些小事，
compound into huge results like
累积效应会产生巨大的结果，例如
investing. But for example, the average
投资。但例如，平均
American spend more money on Netflix
美国人在 Netflix 上花费更多
than they do on their investments. And
比他们在投资上的投入要多。和
if I invest $1,000 a month for 30 years
如果我每月投资 1000 美元，持续 30 年
in something like the S&amp;P 500, I will
如果是像标普500指数这样的指数，我会
have about $1.9 million.
拥有约190万美元。
&gt;&gt; Or there's no asset in all human history
或者说，整个人类历史上根本没有资产。
that's ever generated as much wealth in
这曾经创造过如此多的财富
a short period of time than Bitcoin.
比比特币的时间短得多。
&gt;&gt; There's one problem. Bitcoin is high
但有一个问题。比特币价格高
risk. And if any of those risks happen,
风险。如果这些风险中的任何一个发生，
I don't
我不
&gt;&gt; Let me let me finish. Do you want to
让我说完。你想要_____吗
have hope that you have the Bitcoin or
希望你拥有比特币或
would you rather have more security?
你更希望拥有更高的安全性吗？
&gt;&gt; You can reduce risk. It's our job to
你可以降低风险。我们的职责是
educate them. So, if someone was $1,000,
教育他们。所以，如果有人有1000美元，
what would you suggest they did?
你建议他们怎么做？
&gt;&gt; I have a different take on this. If
我对此有不同的看法。如果
you're trying to make more money, I
你想赚更多钱，我
would. And
会。和
&gt;&gt; what about bad money habits? Because
不良的理财习惯呢？因为
when you look at the stats, money is the
从统计数据来看，金钱是……
number one source of stress for
压力的首要来源
Americans, topping work, family, and
美国人，工作、家庭和……都比不上他们。
health. There's a three-step framework,
健康。这是一个三步框架：
cuz I want to get into that. Number one,
因为我想深入了解那个领域。第一，
&gt;&gt; I see messages all the time in the
我经常在……中看到消息
comments section that some of you didn't
评论区里有些人没看到。
realize you didn't subscribe. So, if you
意识到你没有订阅。所以，如果你
could do me a favor and double check if
能不能帮我个忙，再确认一下？
you're a subscriber to this channel,
您是本频道的订阅者，
that would be tremendously appreciated.
非常感谢。
It's the simple, it's the free thing
它很简单，而且是免费的。
that anybody that watches this show
任何观看这档节目的人
frequently can do to help us here to
通常情况下，他们可以在这里帮助我们。
keep everything going in this show in
让这个节目继续下去
the trajectory it's on. So, please do
它所处的轨迹。所以，请务必这样做。
double check if you've subscribed and uh
请再次确认您是否已订阅，呃……
thank you so much because in a strange
非常感谢，因为在一个奇怪的
way you are you're part of our history
你就是历史的一部分
and you're on this journey with us and I
你和我们一起踏上这段旅程，我
appreciate you for that. So, yeah, thank
谢谢你。是的，谢谢
you.
你。
I think the the first place to start is
我认为首先应该着手的是
people want to know how they can make
人们想知道他们如何才能制作
more money because if you don't feel
更多钱，因为如果你没有感觉
like you have money, saving and
就像你有钱、储蓄和
investing in these kinds of things
投资这类事物
appear to be pointless. I also
似乎毫无意义。我
understand that that's not necessarily
要明白，这未必如此。
true. I think you can you can start
真的。我认为你可以开始
investing and saving with a very small
投资和储蓄金额非常小
amounts of money. But for those people
金额。但对于那些人来说……
that are asking that question, if
问这个问题的人，如果
they're listening to this now and going,
他们现在正在听这个，然后说：
"How does one make money?" Like, you
如何赚钱？比如，你
know, I've got this job. I'm working a 9
我知道，我已经找到这份工作了。我正在上9班。
to5. it's paying me £30,000 a year or
至5。它每年给我支付 3 万英镑，或者
£40,000 a year, whatever it might be, is
每年4万英镑，不管是什么，都是
the right question to be asking. How do
问对了问题。如何
I make more money? And if so, how do I
我赚更多钱吗？如果是这样，我该怎么做？
do that?
这样做吗？
&gt;&gt; I always think it's it's a combination
我一直认为这是多种因素共同作用的结果。
of making more money and also saving
既能赚更多钱，又能省钱
more money. But let's talk about the
更多钱。但我们来谈谈……
making more money piece. I think that
赚取更多收入。我认为
everyone is unique in their own way,
每个人都有自己独特的一面。
right? You've probably spent more hours
正确的？你可能已经花费了更多时间
doing some sort of hobby that I have no
做一些我没有的爱好
idea about. You play paddle, for
关于这个想法。你玩桨板，因为
example. I've never played paddle in my
例子。我从来没在我的……打过板式网球
life. So, let's say you were Steve
生活。假设你是史蒂夫
Steven from age 20 and you're a really
史蒂文从20岁起就认识你，你真是个很棒的人
good paddle player. You can start to
优秀的桨板运动员。你可以开始
monetize this type of skill, which you
将这种技能变现，你
have that I don't, but perhaps you know
我没有，但也许你知道
more than me. I could take lessons from
比我多。我可以从中学习。
you. Even if you're not, let's say, the
你。即使你不是，比如说，那个
pro paddle player that you are, I might
以你这位职业桨板球选手的水平，我或许会……
still be willing to pay you 20 25 an
仍然愿意支付你 20 25 美元
hour for a lesson, right? Just cuz
一节课一个小时，对吧？就因为
you're naturally better than I am. And
你天生就比我强。和
so, I would encourage people to to kind
所以，我鼓励大家友善待人。
of lean into what makes them unique and
充分发挥他们的独特之处
where where they've spent a lot of their
他们花了很多时间的地方
time. I think everyone has something
时间。我认为每个人都有自己的故事。
that they're good at inherently.
他们天生就擅长这些。
Figuring out what skills you have
弄清楚你拥有哪些技能
internally and how you can kind of
从内部来看，以及你可以如何做到某种程度上
monetize those.
将这些信息变现。
&gt;&gt; What you think?
你认为呢？
&gt;&gt; I think one of the the hidden things to
我认为其中隐藏的一点是……
do is you really are a function of who
你所做的，实际上取决于你是谁。
you're surrounded by. Invest in your
你被……包围着。投资自己
network. And I don't mean that in a kind
网络。我的意思并非是那种
of coldhearted, you know, I want to
冷酷无情，你知道，我想
network with these people, but just
与这些人建立联系，但仅此而已
surround yourself by people who are who
让自己身边围绕着这样的人：
are also trying to push themselves to
他们也在努力鞭策自己
push their income, push their
提高他们的收入，提高他们的
opportunity set, and it makes it so much
机会很多，这使得它变得如此重要。
easier. If you're the only one doing it
更轻松。如果你是唯一这么做的人
and you're around a group of friends,
你身边有一群朋友，
you're the odd one out and you're
你是个异类，而且你是
castigated for it. Find other people who
为此受到严厉批评。寻找其他愿意……的人
want to do the same thing and you kind
我也想做同样的事情，你真是太好了
of help each other in that journey. So
在这一过程中互相帮助。所以
at an early stage, that's just one of
在早期阶段，这只是其中之一
the key things is to find people who
关键在于找到那些
also want the same journey as you. M
也想和你走同样的路。 M
&gt;&gt; uh that really helps. Then it's still
嗯，这真的很有帮助。那它仍然是
about the best leverage of your skill
如何最大程度地发挥你的技能
set and being honest with what your
设定目标并诚实面对你的
skill set is. Just because you you're a
技能是。仅仅因为你是一个
doctor doesn't mean you should be a
医生并不意味着你应该成为一名医生
doctor just because you've graduated
仅仅因为你毕业了，就想当医生？
because you can do other things. And
因为你可以做其他事情。和
it's it's figuring that out. That's not
它正在弄清楚这一点。那不是
an easy bit, but you figure out over
这部分很简单，但你慢慢就会明白。
time by trying stuff. You know, we've
花时间尝试各种方法。你知道，我们已经
all done multiple jobs and we know what
我们都做过很多工作，我们知道什么
we're terrible at and what we've been
我们在这方面做得非常糟糕，而且我们一直以来都是这样。
good at and you kind of overindex on the
你擅长，而且在这方面有点过头了
things you you're better at and that
你擅长的事情，以及……
works. So if you're if you're early,
作品。所以如果你来得早的话，
it's the time to make bets in yourself
是时候对自己下注了。
&gt;&gt; and your network and that gives you the
以及你的人脉网络，这能给你带来
foundational tools to then earn more
掌握基础工具，从而赚取更多收入
income and then invest more.
增加收入，然后进行更多投资。
&gt;&gt; Was there a pointless seemingly
是否存在看似毫无意义的
pointless job you did that ended up in
你做的那份毫无意义的工作最终导致了
hindsight making you the most money? And
事后诸葛亮式的决策是否最能让你赚钱？和
what I mean by that is I think about my
我的意思是，我会想到我的
experience doing teley sales between the
有从事电视销售的经验
age of 16 and 19 as probably the most
16岁和19岁可能是最主要的年龄段。
important thing I ever did. Like not
我做过的最重要的事。不像
only do I spend a lot of time talking
我只是花了很多时间说话。
now, but sales is a transferable skill
现在是这样，但销售是一项可迁移的技能。
across raising investment persuading
筹集投资说服
employees to come and join you. And I
员工们可以来加入你们。我
think there's nothing I did that was
我觉得我没做什么错事
more important than telly sales.
比电视机销量更重要。
&gt;&gt; The single best skill you can acquire in
你能掌握的最好的技能是
life is is to learn how to sell. To be
人生就是学习如何销售。成为
comfortable around people and to be able
善于与人相处，并且能够
to get a message across is the single
传达信息是唯一的
most powerful tool you can have in life.
人生中最强大的工具。
Everything you do finding a partner in
你所做的一切都是为了找到伴侣
life doing anything you do is basically
无论你做什么，生活基本上都是如此。
sales.
销售量。
&gt;&gt; And it's all people.
而且全是人。
&gt;&gt; It's all people. So if I'm this 24 year
都是人。所以如果我今年24岁
old and I a 25-year-old and I'm
我年纪大了，而我25岁，我是
ambitious. I want something big.
雄心勃勃。我想要个大东西。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; You got to find more income. You got to
你得想办法增加收入。你必须
have more income to do it. If I'm a
有更多收入去做这件事。如果我是一个
25-year-old and I just want to be okay,
我25岁了，我只希望一切都好。
I don't mind my job. I just want to
我不讨厌我的工作。我只想
invest, you know, whatever. You got to
投资什么的，你知道的。你必须
find the right investments. You got to
找到合适的投资。你必须
have a system for your money. And then
建立一套理财系统。进而
you got to create a plan. Anytime you
你得制定一个计划。任何时候你
get paid, you know how much money you're
拿到工资后，你知道自己有多少钱。
going to save. You know how much money
准备存钱。你知道多少钱
you're going to invest. And then you
你要投资。然后你
spend what's left. Because the
花掉剩下的钱。因为
difference between the person that
这个人与其他人之间的区别
becomes wealthy and everybody else is
变得富有，而其他人都是
wealthy people save and invest their
富人储蓄和投资
money first. Everybody else, especially
先付钱。其他人，尤其是
in America, I spend all my money. I
在美国，我把所有的钱都花光了。我
wonder where all my money went
真想知道我的钱都去哪儿了
&gt;&gt; and then if there's anything left, I'll
如果还有剩余的话，我会……
try to save and maybe invest and
尽量存钱，也许还可以投资。
hopefully I'll get rich.
希望我能发财。
&gt;&gt; For me, it's all around based around
对我来说，一切都围绕着……
what is your vision of your future self.
你对未来的自己有何憧憬？
&gt;&gt; You know, how do you see yourself
你知道，你是如何看待自己的？
living? Because that is what we do. It's
活的？因为这就是我们所做的。它是
one of the sources of unhappiness is if
不快乐的根源之一是……
your current state is not moving on the
你目前的状态没有进展。
path of where your future self wants to
你未来想要去往的道路
be, how you imagine yourself. So
做你自己，就像你想象中的自己一样。所以
practically and tactically, how do they
从实际操作和战术层面来说，他们是如何做的？
do that? How do they create this this
这样做吗？他们是如何创造出这个的
financial vision board? Is there do they
财务愿景板？有吗？
need to know certain numbers? Do they
需要知道某些数字吗？他们会吗？
should they get clear on if they want to
他们应该先明确自己是否想要
be on a private jet or easy jet? Like
乘坐私人飞机还是易捷航空？喜欢
&gt;&gt; oh man, I think I think you know if if
哦，老兄，我想，我想你知道如果
if you have to ask yourself, hm, do I
如果你需要问自己，“嗯，我是否应该这样做？”
want to fly on Spirit Airlines or do I
我想乘坐精神航空公司的航班，还是我应该乘坐其他航空公司的航班？
want to fly on a private jet? I think
想乘坐私人飞机吗？我认为
you already know that question.
你已经知道答案了。
&gt;&gt; But is it important to be explicitly
但明确表达出来是否重要呢？
clear with yourself? Because actually,
你自己想清楚了吗？因为实际上，
if I think of most of my life, I I
如果我回顾我人生的大部分时间，我
wasn't entirely clear. And so you either
不太清楚。所以你要么
end up chasing
最终追逐
&gt;&gt; because more and more
因为越来越多的
&gt;&gt; because it's generally not a
因为它通常不是一个
materialistic outcome. It's generally an
物质结果。这通常是一个
emotional outcome.
情绪结果。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; And that's why it's hard to to pinpoint
这就是为什么很难准确指出原因。
exactly what it is. But you need to
它到底是什么。但你需要
position yourself in that future self
让自己处于未来的自己之中。
and say, "What does it feel like? Do I
然后问：“感觉如何？我……”
feel secure? Do I feel this? Do I feel
感到安全吗？我真的有这种感觉吗？我感觉
that?" So it's it's an emotional thing
是吗？所以这是一种情感因素。
and not a material thing.
而且不是物质的东西。
&gt;&gt; Is that is that central to a lot of
这是否对很多事情都至关重要？
this? You talked about emotional
这？你谈到了情绪方面的问题。
elements. is being okay with
元素。能够接受
what other people think of you.
别人对你的看法。
&gt;&gt; Yeah, that's the other thing is social
是的，社交也是一方面。
pressure, right? So, you may have the
压力很大，对吧？所以，你可能拥有
vision of yourself and you just say, "I
想象自己的样子，然后你只需说：“我
want the the three bed house, you know,
想要那套三居室的房子，你知道的。
with a little strip of lawn and your
一小块草坪和你的
barbecue and that's great
烧烤真棒！
&gt;&gt; and around you people like you should
你周围的人应该像你一样。
try harder."
再努力一点。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; So, they're questioning your own sense
所以，他们是在质疑你自己的感觉。
of happiness and society does that at
幸福和社会是如何做到这一点的
scale. And then even the whole media
规模。然后甚至整个媒体也受到影响。
complex is about kind of how unhappy and
复杂之处在于它关乎不快乐和
how miserable you are and should be. It
你现在和你都应该感到多么痛苦。它
doesn't make it an easy place.
但这并不意味着这里是个容易的地方。
&gt;&gt; We're talking about emotional and
我们谈论的是情感和
psychological barriers here. How do we
这里存在心理障碍。我们如何
get over people not just being scared of
克服人们不仅仅是害怕的心理障碍
what other people will think, but so
别人怎么想我不在乎，但……
many people are scared of their own
许多人害怕自己
money? When you look at the stats around
钱？当你查看相关统计数据时
avoidance, 82% of Americans admit they
回避行为，82%的美国人承认他们
avoid thinking about their own finances.
避免考虑自己的财务状况。
And one in four Americans have avoided
四分之一的美国人避免了
medical care because they're afraid of
因为他们害怕就医
the the bill and thinking about how much
看着账单，想着要付多少钱
it might cost. For Gen Z's, 67% of Gen Z
可能需要花费一些钱。对于Z世代来说，67%的Z世代
and 58% of millennials say they avoid
58%的千禧一代表示他们会避免
checking their own bank account because
他们查看自己的银行账户，因为
it's too stressful, which is compared to
压力太大了，相比之下……
only 30% of boomers. And on in terms of
只有30%的婴儿潮一代。就此而言
mental health, money is the number one
心理健康，金钱是第一位的。
source of stress for Americans topping
美国人压力的来源之一
work, family, and health.
工作、家庭和健康。
36% of people with debt experience
36%有债务经历的人
clinical anxiety and 23% depression. So
临床焦虑症和 23% 的抑郁症。所以
people avoid their own money. A lot of
人们总是逃避花自己的钱。很多
people avoid it because the financial
人们避而远之，是因为经济原因。
world's full of jargon.
世界充满了行话。
&gt;&gt; Y
是
&gt;&gt; you need to go to a professional for
你需要去找专业人士。
advice. That's what people think.
建议。人们就是这么想的。
&gt;&gt; It's intimidating. You don't feel like
这令人望而生畏。你感觉不到
you've got enough money. You're going to
你的钱足够了。你要去
let them down, yourself down, your
让他们失望，让自己失望，你的
family down. So, there's this whole kind
一家人倒下了。所以，这整个系列都是这样。
of thing around it.
周围的事物。
&gt;&gt; It's the confidence that you can learn
这是你能够学习的自信
because a lot of people say, "No, no,
因为很多人会说，“不，不，
unless you're from an investment bank or
除非你来自投资银行或
you're in a RAIA or something, you can't
如果你加入了 RAIA 之类的组织，你就不能……
do this."
这样做。
&gt;&gt; Right? but just a little bit of
正确的？但只有一点点
confidence to say, "Yeah, you can do
有信心说：“是的，你可以做到。”
this."
这。”
&gt;&gt; A simple tip that I think people can do
一个我认为人们可以做到的简单建议
is just kind of figure out how much they
就是弄清楚他们到底有多少
spend on a monthly basis. Track your
按月支出。追踪你的
expenses for 30 days, 60 days, or 90
30天、60天或90天的费用
days. And you're going to learn so much
天。你会学到很多东西。
more about just your personal habits of
更多的是关于你的个人习惯
what you do. Cuz sometimes I'll forget
你做什么。因为有时候我会忘记
that I door dash something for $30. Or
我通过 DoorDash 送了 30 美元的东西。或者
I'll forget that $15 or $20 Uber charge
我会忘记那15美元或20美元的优步费用。
and I'll just kind of file it away
我就把它存档吧。
because I'm swiping my credit card. I
因为我正在刷信用卡。我
don't really I'm not aware of it. It's
我真的不知道。它是
like if you're going to the gym and
比如你去健身房的时候
you're not aware of your weight, how are
你不知道自己的体重，那你该怎么办？
you going to where where's your starting
你要去哪里？你的起点在哪里？
point? So you I like to give people a
观点？所以我喜欢给人们一个
starting point because then they can
这是起点，因为那样他们就可以
kind of have that small step to kind of
有点像迈出那一小步……
start working towards their finances in
开始着手改善他们的财务状况
that sort of way.
就是那种方式。
&gt;&gt; 65% of Americans have no idea what they
65%的美国人不知道他们
spent in the last month according to the
根据上个月的支出情况，
US Bank. And 60% underestimate their
美国银行。 60%的人低估了他们的
monthly spending by a significant
每月支出相当可观
margin.
利润。
&gt;&gt; Right? And that's exactly what I found.
正确的？而这正是我发现的。
I track my expenses for a month in 2014.
我记录了2014年一个月的开支。
I thought I was spending 1,500 bucks a
我以为我要花1500美元。
month. Guess what? I was spending $2,800
月。你猜怎么着？我当时花了2800美元。
and I wasn't making that much and I was
我当时收入并不高，而且
like, how am I off by an order of
比如，我怎么会差了这么多？
magnitude of I don't know 60 70%. And I
我不知道 60 70% 的幅度。我
find that even like all my friends I
我发现，即使像我所有的朋友一样，我
issue this challenge to mo most of them
向他们中的大多数人提出这一挑战
don't make it to the 3 months. But I
坚持不到三个月。但我
think as long as you have an
想想只要你有一个
approximation of what you're spending
你的支出估算
that can help because that that means
那会有帮助，因为这意味着
then you're going to have a little bit
然后你就会有点
of a difference of what you make and
你所赚的钱和收入之间的差异
what you spend and then you can save
你花的钱，然后你就可以省钱了。
that money and I think that's one of the
那笔钱，我认为那是其中之一
bad money habits of Americans is they
美国人的不良理财习惯是
don't save right. So,
保存不正确。所以，
&gt;&gt; it's a really good point which is a a
这是一个非常好的观点，这是一个……
practical step to just heighten one's
采取切实可行的步骤来提升自身能力
awareness because you need to have sort
意识到这一点，因为你需要有所了解。
of informationational awareness of where
对信息感知的了解程度
you're at to even understand what you
你甚至都无法理解你
need to do to get to where you want to
为了达到目标，你需要做什么？
go. So,
去。所以，
&gt;&gt; yeah, I think you need to start with the
是的，我认为你需要从……开始。
mindset. You have to build the basics.
心态。你必须先打好基础。
You got to get rid of the credit card
你必须注销信用卡。
debt. You got to save a little bit of
债务。你得省下一点钱。
money, but you got to have some
钱，但你得有点钱。
breathing room because investing is all
留点喘息空间，因为投资就是一切
about taking the extra money that you
关于拿走额外的钱
have,
有，
&gt;&gt; throwing it somewhere to grow that
把它扔到某个地方让它生长。
money. And this is where uh there's a
钱。而这里，呃，有一个
three-step framework that I'll talk
我将要谈到的三步框架
about because there's a lot of ways to
因为有很多方法可以……
invest. At the very simplest is I could
投资。最简单的说法是我可以
be completely hands-off. I can work with
完全不干预。我可以与
a financial adviser. I can give them my
财务顾问。我可以给他们我的
money and they can do everything for me.
只要有钱，他们就能为我做任何事。
If you don't have a lot of money, you're
如果你没有很多钱，你
not going to get a very good adviser.
恐怕找不到很好的顾问。
But there's a con and a cost to a
但这样做也有弊端和代价。
financial adviser, which is the amount
财务顾问，也就是金额
of money you have to pay because they're
你必须支付的钱，因为他们是
going to charge a fee. So, if I invest
将收取费用。所以，如果我投资
my money, $1,000 a month with a
我的钱，每月1000美元，
financial adviser, I get a good
财务顾问，我得到了很好的
financial adviser who beats the market.
业绩超越市场的理财顾问。
They get 11% a year, but I have to pay
他们每年能拿到11%的收益，但我却要付钱。
1.5% a year. After 30 years, I'm going
每年1.5%。 30年后，我要走了
to have $1.8 million after paying
支付后剩余180万美元
$600,000 to my adviser. Stage number two
给我的顾问60万美元。第二阶段
is I can be a completely passive
我可以完全被动
investor. It's a little bit more
投资者。稍微多一点
involved than an adviser, but I can just
比顾问更投入，但我只能
put my money into the stock market,
我把钱投入股市。
something like the S&amp;P 500, which is a
类似标普500指数那样的指数，它就是一个
group of the 500 largest companies in
由500家最大的公司组成的集团
the stock market. It's kind of like
股票市场。有点像
investing your money into the United
把你的钱投资到美国
States economy. This has historically
国家经济。历史上，这种情况一直存在
averaged 10% a year, which means if I
平均每年10%，这意味着如果我
invest $1,000 a month for 30 years, I
每月投资1000美元，持续30年，我
will have about $1.9 million. a little
大约会有190万美元。一点
bit more work than completely hands-off
比完全放任不管要多花些功夫。
but still pretty passive. Then we have
但仍然相当被动。然后我们有
the people that want to be more
那些想要变得更好的人
involved. What we call is a active
涉及。我们称之为积极的
investor. And an active investor is
投资者。而积极的投资者是
somebody who now wants to invest their
现在有人想投资
money themselves. And I don't mean
金钱本身。我的意思并非如此。
trading. I mean actually investing their
贸易。我的意思是，实际上他们投资了
money. And now I'm going to be doing the
钱。现在我要去做……
research to find which investments I
研究找出我应该进行的投资
want to own. Maybe it's real estate that
想要拥有。或许是房地产
I want to own. Maybe I want to invest in
我想拥有它。或许我想投资
individual companies. So it's more risk
各个公司。所以风险更大。
for more potential return. A small edge
为了获得更大的潜在回报。一个小边缘
can give you outsized return.
可以给你带来超额回报。
Because if now I don't get a 10% return,
因为如果我现在得不到10%的回报，
I can get a 13% return, which you know,
我可以获得13%的回报，你知道的，
we're not talking about 200 or 50%
我们说的不是200%或50%。
returns. A 13% annual return means that
返回。 13%的年回报率意味着
my $1,000 a month over 30 years is now
我每月1000美元，持续30年，现在
going to grow to $3.5 million. So about
预计将增长至350万美元。所以，大概
$1.6 $6 million more than before just
比以前多了160万美元。
with this slight edge. And you got to
凭借这微弱的优势。而且你还得……
figure out how involved you want to be
弄清楚你想参与到什么程度。
&gt;&gt; on this point of being an active
在这一点上，积极主动
investor and picking stocks yourself
投资者和自己选股
versus being a passive one. The data
而不是被动的。数据
shows that passive investors who invest
这表明被动投资者投资
in the S&amp;P 500, like you said,
正如你所说，在标普500指数中，
consistently outperform most stock
持续跑赢大多数股票
pickers over a 20-year period, more than
在长达20年的时间里，采摘者人数超过
90% of actively managed investors, so
90%的主动管理型投资者
talking about funds there, underperform
谈到那里的基金，表现不佳。
the S&amp;P 500 after fees. So, should
扣除费用后的标准普尔500指数。所以，应该
people be actively investing or should
人们应该积极投资还是应该
they just put the money in an S&amp;P 500
他们只是把钱投到了标普500指数基金里。
and be patient?
要有耐心吗？
&gt;&gt; I say most people should not be active
我认为大多数人都不应该积极参与体育活动。
investors. In fact, I say 98% of America
投资者。事实上，我认为98%的美国人
should not be active investors. Just be
不应成为积极的投资者。就这么简单
a passive investor because if you don't
被动投资者，因为如果你不这样做的话
want to put in the work, if you're not
如果你不想付出努力，那就不要
willing to put in the time and the
愿意投入时间和
effort to research, you're probably
经过一番研究，你很可能
going to lose. And many people do.
将会输掉比赛。很多人都这么做。
&gt;&gt; So, why do people want to be active
那么，人们为什么想要积极参与体育活动呢？
investors if the if the probability is
如果概率是
stacked against them? Well, if you get a
他们处于不利地位吗？嗯，如果你得到一个
little bit better returns, if you're
如果你的回报稍微好一些，
willing to put in the work, you can get
只要你愿意付出努力，你就能得到
better returns and it is possible. We do
获得更高的回报是完全可能的。我们确实
see people that are doing it consist.
看看那些这样做的人。
&gt;&gt; Is there an element of fun in
是否存在趣味元素？
entertainment?
娱乐？
&gt;&gt; Absolutely.
绝对地。
&gt;&gt; People like sports betting and
人们喜欢体育博彩
&gt;&gt; that's the problem because the fun is I
这就是问题所在，因为乐趣在于……
like researching versus, oh, I want to
比如研究，而不是，哦，我想……
see my money go up tomorrow. If I buy a
明天就等着看我的钱涨价吧。如果我买一个
house tomorrow morning, am I going to go
明天早上要去房子那里吗？
on to Zillow in the afternoon, check,
下午去Zillow看看，确认一下。
what is my house price? I'm going to
我的房子值多少钱？我要
check in the evening, what's my house
晚上查看一下，我家在哪儿
price? No. because you know that this is
价格？不，因为你知道这是
something I want to own for the long
我想长期拥有它
term. Well, when I go into the stock
学期。嗯，当我进入股票市场时
market because it's so liquid, I buy a
因为市场流动性很好，所以我买入了一个
stock in the morning, I'm checking it 15
早上查看股票，我15号查看。
minutes later, I'm checking at lunch,
几分钟后，我在午餐时间查看情况。
I'm checking in the bathroom, I'm
我正在浴室里查看情况，我
checking in the evening, I know I'm
晚上查看时，我知道我是
getting anxiety cuz if it's going up or
感到焦虑，因为如果它上涨的话
down, I'm I'm a very emotional and
情绪低落，我是一个非常情绪化的人，
that's that emotional
那就是那种情绪
control as an investor, which is just as
作为投资者，控制权同样重要。
important as the research that you're
这项研究的重要性不亚于你正在进行的研究。
putting in. I see I fundamentally differ
投入。我发现我与此有着根本的不同。
on all of this stuff is people are so
所有这些事情，人们都如此
screwed. They are coming out of
搞砸了。他们正从……中走出来
university with massive debts. We looked
负债累累的大学。我们看了
at the stat earlier um off camera when
早些时候，在镜头外，
we were talking about the fact that
我们当时在讨论这样一个事实：
percentage of 30-year-olds who have a
30岁人群中拥有以下情况的比例
mortgage and a and and are married has
抵押贷款和，并且结婚了
gone from 52% in 1950 to 12%.
从 1950 年的 52% 下降到 12%。
Nobody can afford anything. So if you
谁都买不起东西。所以如果你
look at the average millennial in the US
看看美国千禧一代的平均情况。
and a Gen Z, they generally have a 401k
而Z世代，他们通常都有401k退休计划。
if they've got a job, right? They have
如果他们有工作的话，对吧？他们有
some sort of savings, but they're taking
他们节省了一些钱，但他们正在拿走
massive amounts of risk. A lot of us
巨大的风险。我们很多人
would look at them and say, "This is
会看着他们说：“这是
ridiculous."
荒谬的。”
&gt;&gt; Why are they taking risk for anyone that
他们为什么要为任何人冒风险？
doesn't?
不是吗？
&gt;&gt; Because there is no way of closing the
因为没有办法关闭
gap between buying, getting the deposit
购买和收到定金之间的差额
on the house, getting into a house,
在家，进入房子，
realizing that future vision of
实现未来愿景
themselves, however reasonable that is.
然而，即便这听起来合情合理。
Why
为什么
&gt;&gt; it's so far away? because the ass the
很远吗？因为那头驴
cost of assets has gone up so much
资产成本上涨幅度如此之大。
versus the incomes don't go up.
相反，收入却没有增长。
&gt;&gt; You mean the cost of buying like a house
你是说买房之类的费用吗？
for example?
例如？
&gt;&gt; Yes. Or even however much percentage
是的。或者哪怕是百分之多少
share of the stock market the average
股票市场平均份额
salary does, you know, stuff like that.
薪水确实会影响到很多方面，你知道的。
That you're you're getting less for your
你得到的比你付出的更少。
money. So your future self is
钱。所以，未来的你是
automatically going to be poorer because
必然会变得更穷，因为
of it because you could buy less of a
因为你可以少买一些
house, etc. Explain that to me like I'm
房子等等。请像我一样向我解释一下。
an idiot, like I'm like I'm 10 years old
我像个白痴，就像我只有10岁一样。
and maybe in the context of this mug
或许就这个马克杯而言
here
这里
in terms of the how why is that worth
从“如何”和“为什么”的角度来看，这有价值吗？
less now based on what you said?
根据你刚才说的，现在是不是感觉少了点？
&gt;&gt; The way of explaining it is money is the
解释起来就是，金钱就是……
medium of exchange, the thing that you
交换媒介，你
buy something with. If we all have a lot
用它买东西。如果我们都拥有很多
of money, we've all got a stack of cash
说到钱，我们每个人都有一大笔现金。
on this table and you want to sell that
在这张桌子上，你想卖掉它
mug. We can pay anything for that mug
马克杯。我们愿意为那个马克杯付出任何代价。
because we've got a stack of cash.
因为我们手头有一大笔现金。
&gt;&gt; Mhm.
嗯。
&gt;&gt; So that mug suddenly is worth not the
所以那个杯子突然变得不值钱了
$10 it's supposed to be worth. It's
它应该值10美元。它是
suddenly we're paying $150 for the mug.
突然间，我们得花150美元买这个马克杯了。
Why? Because that money has no value to
为什么？因为那笔钱对……毫无价值
us because we've got excess money. So
我们之所以这样做，是因为我们有多余的钱。所以
when you create excess money in the
当你积累了多余的资金时
system, it's this debasement of
系统，正是这种贬低
currency. It's an optical illusion that
货币。这是一种视觉错觉。
the value of assets are actually going
资产价值实际上正在下降
up. They're not. It's the value of your
向上。并非如此。这是你的价值
money is going down. And this is this
货币贬值了。这就是这个
pain point because your earnings
痛点在于你的收入
only grow with economic growth generally
通常只有经济增长才能带动增长。
plus your progression of your career or
以及你的职业发展或
whatever it may be. But those things,
不管是什么。但那些事，
the scarce assets are going up optically
稀缺资产价格上涨是显而易见的。
by the amounts they're lowering the
他们降低的幅度
thing. So what you find is salaries go
事物。所以你会发现，薪水……
up at about 2 or 3% a year.
每年上涨约2%至3%。
And the house of the cost of the S&amp;P is
而标普500指数的成本结构是……
about 12% 13% up every year and a house
每年上涨约 12% 至 13%，而且房子
price is about the same. Gold is about
价格差不多。黄金是关于
the same.
相同。
&gt;&gt; And that's because they're printing more
那是因为他们加印了更多。
and more money.
以及更多的钱。
&gt;&gt; Correct.
正确的。
&gt;&gt; Okay, that makes perfect sense to me. So
好的，我完全明白了。所以
I'm imagining you all have a big stack
我猜你们每个人都有一大笔钱吧。
of paper in front of you which you're
你面前有一张纸，你
using it to take some notes on. And if
用它来记笔记。如果
if I was saying I'm going to sell you
如果我说我要卖给你
guys this mug for some of the paper you
伙计们，这个杯子是为了你们的一些纸张。
have there, but then my team said you
那里确实有，但是我的团队说你
guys can have unlimited paper. this mug
男生可以无限量使用纸张。这个马克杯
loses value because you can all just
贬值是因为你们都可以这么做
offer a gazillion sheets of paper for
提供数不清的纸张
this mug.
这个马克杯。
&gt;&gt; Well, it doesn't lose value. It
它不会贬值。它
optically will give you a gazillion for
从光学角度来看，它会给你带来数不尽的收益。
it as opposed to, you know, three sheets
它和三张床单不一样，你知道，就是三张床单。
of paper because we've got so much
因为我们有很多纸张。
paper. It matters not.
纸。没关系。
&gt;&gt; So, I'll be I'll be thinking, "Wow, like
所以，我当时会想，“哇，就像……”
this mug is worth a gazillion sheets of
这个马克杯价值连城。
paper, but actually the each sheet of
纸张，但实际上是每一张
paper is now worth nothing."
纸张现在一文不值了。
&gt;&gt; Correct.
正确的。
&gt;&gt; Okay, got you.
好的，明白了。
&gt;&gt; And this is the problem that people are
这就是人们面临的问题。
finding is they put money in a 401k, you
发现他们把钱存入了401k账户，你
compound it at 10%. for my generation.
按10%的比例复利计算。对我这一代人来说。
Yeah, that was that was how the world
是的，世界就是这样。
worked and it was great and it worked
成功了，而且效果很好，真的有效。
and now it doesn't work. So, they need
现在它不起作用了。所以他们需要
assets that go up 50% a year, 100% a
每年增长 50% 的资产，100% 的资产
year, which is ridiculous, but luckily
今年，这很荒谬，但幸运的是……
we've been gifted a few. Um, and so
我们收到了一些礼物。嗯，所以
that's helped.
那很有帮助。
&gt;&gt; Go on and say it.
说出来吧。
&gt;&gt; Well, it's crypto. Simplistically, it
嗯，这是加密货币。简单来说，它
just outperforms all other assets even
即使如此，它的表现也优于所有其他资产。
with the excess volatility. So, Bitcoin,
伴随过度波动。所以，比特币
for example, produces about since 2012,
例如，自 2012 年以来，产量约为
it's produced about 145% a year returns.
它每年能产生约 145% 的回报。
So that's 10x the stock market
所以这是股市的10倍
and that's including three 70% draw
其中包括三次70%的抽奖
downs in the middle of it.
中间有低谷。
&gt;&gt; A draw down being a drop.
下降是指资金减少。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Well, you feel like you're an
是的。嗯，你觉得自己像个
idiot. You're losing money. It's all
笨蛋。你在赔钱。这一切都是
going to go, you know, you've made the
你要走了，你知道，你已经做到了
biggest mistake in your life and it
你一生中最大的错误，而且
recovers and it keeps going because it's
它会恢复并继续运行，因为它是
a it's a technological network adoption
这是一项技术网络采用
model that's happening. So, it's just
正在发生的模式。所以，就是这样
sucking in more and more people. So
吸引着越来越多的人。所以
there's now 650 million crypto brokerage
现在有6.5亿家加密货币经纪公司
accounts in the world, which is more
世界上的账户，这更多
than all the stock market brokerage
比所有股票市场经纪公司都多
accounts added together in the world.
全球账户总数。
And we're seeing it all around the world
我们在世界各地都看到了这种情况。
because everybody can buy a share of
因为每个人都可以购买股份
something. So as opposed to be able to
某物。所以，与能够……相反
buy, nobody can buy a Fifth Avenue
买，没人能买得起第五大道
apartment here. Everybody can buy a
公寓在这里。人人都能买得起
fractionalized share of Bitcoin, which
比特币的碎片化份额，
is in theory $100,000 asset. But we can
理论上是一笔价值 10 万美元的资产。但是我们可以
all put in 10 bucks, five bucks, a
每个人都出了10美元、5美元，一个
thousand bucks, 10 billion.
一千美元，100亿美元。
&gt;&gt; Let me challenge it then. So, Bitcoin
那我就来质疑一下。所以，比特币
isn't based on anything, though. Okay,
但这并没有任何依据。好的，
I'm being I'm being a futter here.
我真是个笨蛋。
That's my job.
那是我的工作。
&gt;&gt; Bitcoin isn't based on anything. It is a
比特币并非基于任何实体。这是一个
database in the sky that isn't backed by
空中数据库，却没有技术支持
gold or it doesn't produce any sort of
黄金，或者它不产生任何类型的黄金
valuable asset as its byproduct. So, why
其副产品是宝贵的资产。那么，为什么呢？
how can we have faith in Bitcoin? It's
我们如何才能对比特币抱有信心？它是
essentially in its essence before
本质上，在其之前
someone clips me, this is I'm playing
有人剪辑我，这是我在玩的游戏。
devil's advocate cuz I know they're
我是唱反调的，因为我知道他们是
going to clip this part out. It is
我要把这部分剪掉。这是
essentially many would say a Ponzi
很多人会说，这本质上就是庞氏骗局。
scheme.
方案。
&gt;&gt; Mhm.
嗯。
&gt;&gt; Which is it only goes up if other people
也就是说，只有当其他人……时，它才会上升。
take part in it and if everybody decides
参与其中，如果大家都决定……
that it's um not worth anything then
那它就一文不值了。
it's going to go to zero.
它会归零。
&gt;&gt; So all money is social consensus.
所以，所有的金钱都是社会共识。
Everything. Gold has no real value.
一切。黄金没有实际价值。
&gt;&gt; I can build a table with gold though. I
我可以用黄金造一张桌子。我
could rest some things on it and it's a
可以把一些东西放在上面，而且它是一个
good it doesn't rust.
好处是不会生锈。
&gt;&gt; If you're building a table of gold, then
如果你要打造一张黄金桌，那么
the value is going to be much less if
如果……，其价值将会大大降低。
everybody's building gold tables.
大家都在打造黄金桌。
&gt;&gt; Trump has
特朗普有
&gt;&gt; we do
我们这样做
um and so really it's just social
嗯，所以说到底这只是社交而已。
consensus. What do we as humans ascribe
共识。我们人类赋予了什么？
value to?
价值几何？
&gt;&gt; But the problem with the 145% like you
但像你这样的145%的人的问题在于……
mentioned, Bitcoin has fallen by 70
如前所述，比特币已下跌70%。
plus% on multiple occasions.
多次超过 %。
&gt;&gt; If we let's go back to the S&amp;P 500. A
让我们回到标普500指数。
lot of people invest in the SPY, the S&amp;P
很多人投资SPY，即标普500指数。
500, and still lose money. Why? Because
投了500块，结果还是赔钱。为什么？因为
when the we go through any downturn,
当我们经历任何经济衰退时，
people panic and they sell.
人们恐慌抛售。
&gt;&gt; And and if we look at I mean Bitcoin's I
而且，如果我们看一下比特币，我的意思是，
think Bitcoin's 2009 if when it started
想想比特币在 2009 年的起步时期。
if I'm not mistaken.
如果我没记错的话。
&gt;&gt; Um
嗯
&gt;&gt; if we look at the crashes from you know
如果我们看一下你知道的那些坠机事故。
recent history 2020 stocks fell by 30%,
近期历史数据显示，2020年股市下跌了30%。
Bitcoin fell by 50%. 2022 stocks fell by
比特币下跌了50%。 2022年股票下跌了
20. The S&amp;P fell by about 20%. Bitcoin
20. 标准普尔指数下跌约20%。比特币
fell by 60%. So in those times, people
下降了60%。所以在那个时代，人们
who are in the S&amp;P are freaking out
标普500指数成分股公司都吓坏了。
selling.
出售。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. But here's the thing. This is the
是的。但问题是……这是
riskreward that people don't understand.
人们不理解的风险回报。
If you've got a time horizon, let's say
如果你设定了一个时间范围，比如说
the average draw down in the S&amp;P during
标普500指数平均下跌幅度
a a bare market is 25%.
裸市价为 25%。
&gt;&gt; A draw down being a a drop.
资金回撤是指资金下降。
&gt;&gt; A lot. Yeah. A drop. A drop in prices.
很多。是的。一滴。价格下降。
you're getting compensated 15% a year
你每年能获得 15% 的补偿。
returns for that at best. In Bitcoin,
充其量也只能获得这样的回报。在比特币中，
the average draw down over the same
在同一时期内的平均回撤幅度
period will be about 70%. But you're
这段时间大约占70%。但你是
getting 150% return.
获得150%的回报。
&gt;&gt; If you're on the winning side, though
不过，如果你站在胜利的一方的话。
I buy it and I can sell it for a higher
我买下它，然后可以高价卖出。
price,
价格，
&gt;&gt; hold it. Just hold it.
等等。拿着就行。
&gt;&gt; That's the key.
这是关键所在。
&gt;&gt; So all of these are in a nice trend
所以所有这些都呈现出一种良好的趋势。
channel. They go up. So anybody can buy
渠道。它们上升。所以任何人都可以购买
something and hold it long enough it
把某样东西握在手里足够长的时间
will go up. Well, what about let's look
会上涨。那我们来看看吧
at housing. We could say the same thing
在住房方面。我们也可以说同样的话
about housing. 2008, housing crashed.
关于住房问题。 2008年，房地产市场崩盘。
Just hold it. I have too much debt. I'm
拿着就行。我负债太多了。我是
underwater. My bank's taking it from me.
水下。我的银行要把它从我这儿拿走。
People are buying Bitcoin with debt.
人们正在用债务购买比特币。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. I mean, that would not recommend
是的。我的意思是，那样做并不推荐。
that. But housing's different because
那。但住房情况有所不同，因为
you can endlessly create more housing.
你可以无限建造更多的住房。
&gt;&gt; And we have a demographic problem in
我们面临着人口结构问题。
housing that makes it more complicated.
住房问题使情况更加复杂。
Demographic problem is A, everyone's
人口问题是A，每个人的
leaving the cities now.
现在要离开这些城市了。
B, the generational gap. Nobody can
B，代沟。谁都不能
afford the boomer houses. We don't have
买得起婴儿潮一代的房子。我们没有
enough cheap housing for young people.
为年轻人提供充足的廉价住房。
People are relocating, moving around.
人们正在搬迁，四处迁徙。
So, we got a very interesting mismatch
所以，我们遇到了一个非常有趣的错配情况。
in real estate now that makes it more
在房地产领域，这使得它更加
complicated than it used to be.
比以前复杂多了。
&gt;&gt; Absolutely. And and I do want to say I
绝对地。而且，我确实想说，
think the part that we fundamentally
认为我们根本上
differ is not that there's value in
不同之处并不在于它们之间是否存在价值
crypto. I own crypto,
加密货币。我持有加密货币。
&gt;&gt; but the difference between you and I is
但你我之间的区别是
you are all in crypto. For me, it's a
你们都在玩加密货币。对我来说，这是一个
speculative piece of my portfolio. So, I
这是我投资组合中的一件投机性作品。所以，我
invest in my own business. I have real
投资我自己的事业。我有真正的
estate, stocks, my speculative assets,
房产、股票、我的投机性资产、
and then a little bit of gold.
然后还有一点黄金。
&gt;&gt; Imagine how difficult to replicate what
想象一下复制什么有多么困难
you've achieved in your amazing career
你在精彩的职业生涯中取得了卓越的成就
is for the average person listening to
是为普通听众准备的
this versus buying one thing in your
这与在你的商店里买一件东西相比
Coinbase account, your Robin Hood
Coinbase账户，你的Robinhood
account, and doing nothing. It's so
账户，却什么也不做。真是太
there's no cost. It's not like buying a
无需任何费用。这不像买东西
house. It's like servicing all the
房子。这就像为所有……提供服务
stuff. There's no debt involved. There's
东西。不涉及任何债务。有
nothing
没有什么
&gt;&gt; in theory, but theory isn't reality. How
理论上如此，但理论并非现实。如何
many people end up losing money when
很多人最终都会赔钱
things go down? How many people panic
事情会恶化吗？有多少人恐慌
especially with Bitcoin? Because if we
尤其是比特币？因为如果我们
look at especially the early adopters of
尤其要关注那些早期采用者
Bitcoin, who are those people? These are
比特币，这些人是谁？这些都是
the people that well a lot a lot of the
那些人，很多很多
average person is I want to get rich. I
普通人的想法是：我想致富。我
want to get rich quick. It's I want to
想快速致富。我想要
make money fast versus the average
与平均水平相比，快速赚钱
person who's buying the S&amp;P 500. This is
买入标普500指数的人。这是
somebody who is I want to invest and
我想投资的人
build wealth for the long term. It's a
为长远积累财富。这是一个
very different mindset. The average
思维方式截然不同。平均
investor of this is 32 years old. And we
这位投资者今年32岁。我们
said, "No, you need to invest for the
他说：“不，你需要投资……”
long run. They're never going to have a
从长远来看。他们永远不会有
house. So they their whole vision of
房子。所以他们整个愿景
their future selves is utterly
他们未来的自己完全是
destroyed."
被摧毁了。
&gt;&gt; So it becomes a logical thing to
因此，这便成了一件合乎逻辑的事情。
actually take more risk. It's logical
实际上要承担更大的风险。这是合乎逻辑的。
for them because they've got nothing to
对他们来说，因为他们一无所有。
lose.
失去。
&gt;&gt; So Bitcoin you're saying is 145% a year.
所以你的意思是比特币的年收益率是 145%？
&gt;&gt; Yeah. And in recent years as the trend
是的。近年来，这种趋势愈演愈烈。
rate of adoption grows, it's probably
采用率增长，很可能
down to about 100% a year. Let's call it
每年下降约 100%。我们姑且称之为
that for easy maths. But now let's think
那是为了简化数学运算。但现在让我们思考一下
about this just from a practical
仅从实际角度来说
long-term perspective. Warren Buffett is
从长远角度来看。沃伦·巴菲特是
arguably the best investor in the
可以说是最好的投资者
history of time.
时间的历史。
He has averaged about 19% a year over
他平均每年收益率约为19%。
the course of his decades making him a
他数十年的经历使他成为
multi multi multi-billionaire.
亿万富翁。
And so when we compare a 20% return from
因此，当我们比较 20% 的回报率时
one of the top investors in the world
世界顶级投资者之一
versus hey Bitcoin is going to give you
相比之下，比特币将给你带来什么呢？
100% a year there's there's some sense
每年100%都是如此，这有一定的道理。
of something wrong. So, even if I'm
感觉哪里不对劲。所以，即使我是
wrong by 50%. You still outperform
错误率高达50%。你依然表现出色。
Buffett. To put it in perspective,
巴菲特。换个角度来看，
Bitcoin since 20 2010 has done I think
我认为比特币自 2010 年以来已经做到了这一点。
it's about 90 million% returns. There's
回报率高达9000万%。有
no asset in all human history that's
人类历史上没有任何资产是这样的。
ever generated as much wealth in the
曾经创造出如此巨额的财富
shortest period of time. And because
最短时间。而且因为
it's not a random thing, it's actually a
这并非偶然，而是一个……
technology. It's a network model of
技术。这是一个网络模型
technology. as more people use the
技术。随着越来越多的人使用
network and we see with Bitcoin,
网络，例如比特币，就是一个很好的例子。
governments buying it and asset
政府购买该资产
management firms buying and everybody
管理公司收购和所有人
else you have this network adoption
否则，您将面临这种网络采用问题。
model and so what it creates is the same
模型，因此它所创造的也是相同的。
chart as Google or Amazon all of these
图表就像谷歌或亚马逊的所有这些
it just goes up in a log trend over time
随着时间的推移，它呈对数增长趋势。
with some volatility so you've got a
由于存在一些波动，所以你现在的情况是……
secular bull market which means that
长期牛市意味着
over time prices go up for measurable
随着时间的推移，价格会上涨，而且涨幅可衡量。
understandable reasons and it happens to
原因可以理解，这种情况确实会发生
be the highest performing asset of all
成为所有资产中表现最佳的资产
time. There's one problem
时间。有一个问题
&gt;&gt; and it's volatile. The psychological
而且它波动性很大。心理
thing you're dead right about. It's re
你说的完全正确。它是重新
very hard when it falls 70%. I've gone
当它下降 70% 时，情况会变得非常糟糕。我走了
through three of those. They're hard.
通过其中三个。它们很难。
&gt;&gt; The problem is
问题是
just like with real estate,
就像房地产市场一样，
everyone has said real estate only goes
大家都说房地产只会……
up. Well, how do you make money on the
向上。那么，你如何通过……赚钱呢？
real estate? You make money when you
房地产？当你……时，你就能赚钱。
sell or you lose money if you sell.
卖掉，否则你会赔钱。
Ultimately, it comes down to that. You
归根结底，就是这个原因。你
make or lose money only if you sell.
只有卖出才会赚钱或赔钱。
Well, what about everything along the
那么，沿途的一切又如何呢？
way? And what if I need to sell during
方式？如果我需要在销售期间出售怎么办？
that 70% crash? Because what happens
那70%的暴跌？因为会发生什么呢？
during those crashes? A lot of times
在那些坠机事故期间？很多时候
people lose jobs. A lot of times people
人们会失去工作。很多时候人们
lose their income. A lot of times people
失去收入。很多时候人们
need that money during that time. And so
那段时间我需要那笔钱。所以
now I'm desperate or I'm panicking.
我现在很绝望，或者说我很恐慌。
There's there's two things happening and
有两件事正在发生，
now maybe it's the end and I go in and
现在也许一切都结束了，我进去……
now I lose money thinking that I'm going
现在我因为想着要去而赔钱
to make all this money.
赚这么多钱。
&gt;&gt; I think I can appreciate your love for
我想我能理解你对……的爱
cryptocurrency and your 100%
加密货币和你的100%
concentration in cryptocurrency.
专注于加密货币。
&gt;&gt; You're saying it's suitable for
你的意思是它适合
everybody, right? I've got my the you
大家都一样，对吧？我拥有了你
know bottom of Maslo hierarch of needs
了解马斯洛需求层次的底部
taken care of. I've got houses. I don't
已处理。我有几处房产。我不
have debt. You know, it's easy for me.
负债。你知道，这对我来说很容易。
I've got multiple sources of income that
我有多份收入来源，
I can take that back. I'm not saying
我可以收回刚才的话。我不是说
that for everybody, but I can also
这对每个人来说都是如此，但我也可以
understand why a 25year-old can do that
理解为什么一个25岁的人能做到这一点。
too because they got nothing to lose.
也因为他们没有什么可失去的。
&gt;&gt; But do you think that if a 25year-old
但你认为如果一个25岁的
puts their entire salary and savings
把他们的全部工资和积蓄都投入进去
into Bitcoin and they lose it, let's say
假设他们把钱投到比特币里，然后又赔光了。
they run through a 70% draw down, aren't
他们经历了70%的跌幅，不是吗？
they just putting themselves in a bigger
他们只是把自己置于一个更大的境地。
hole for their future as well? like
这也是他们未来道路上的一个缺口吗？喜欢
maybe before there was a a glimmer of a
或许在那之前，还闪现过一丝曙光
chance that they could that they buy a
他们有可能买到
house and then now they can't.
房子，然后现在他们买不起了。
&gt;&gt; The most important um part of financial
财务中最重要的部分
markets is the least understood is time.
市场中最不为人所理解的就是时间。
&gt;&gt; Mhm.
嗯。
&gt;&gt; It's not just price, it's time. So if
不仅仅是价格问题，还有时间问题。所以如果
you're 25 years old and you get wiped
你25岁，然后就被干掉了
out,
出去，
&gt;&gt; we've all done it. We've all kind of
我们都做过这件事。我们都差不多
screwed up and you know had to move home
搞砸了，你知道的，我不得不搬家
to our parents or do whatever. We've all
对父母或其他任何事。我们都
done it. You can do that several times
完成了。你可以多次这样做。
when you're young and it's okay. You
年轻的时候这样做没关系。你
just don't want to do it.
就是不想做。
&gt;&gt; At age 50. Sure,
50岁？当然。
&gt;&gt; you really really don't. You become more
你真的真的不想。你变得更加
risk averse generally speaking.
总体而言，我比较厌恶风险。
&gt;&gt; It just depends where you are and how
这完全取决于你身处何地以及如何
much time you've got to take that risk.
你还有足够的时间去承担这种风险。
&gt;&gt; But now, if I'm investing my money in
但是现在，如果我把钱投资于
Bitcoin or really anything, a lot of the
比特币或者其他任何东西，很多
value is what some people refer to as
价值是有些人所说的
like equity. It's it's I bought it for
例如股权。就是它，我买它是为了
like I started buying Bitcoin when it
就像我开始购买比特币的时候一样
was $3,000.
原价为 3000 美元。
That other stuff is equity. It's
其他那些都是股权问题。它是
invisible money, which in my view is is
在我看来，无形货币就是
theory. It's not actual money in my bank
理论。那不是我银行账户里的实际现金。
account. It's sitting there waiting for
帐户。它就那样静静地待在那里，等待着……
me to sell, hoping that when I go to
让我卖掉，希望当我去的时候
sell, it's going to be a profit versus
卖出肯定有利可图
cash flow.
现金周转。
&gt;&gt; If I buy a dividend paying stock,
如果我购买一只派息股票，
&gt;&gt; what's a dividend paying stock?
什么是派息股票？
&gt;&gt; Some companies have big profits. For
有些公司利润丰厚。为了
example, McDonald's has billions of
例如，麦当劳拥有数十亿的……
dollars of profits. There's three things
美元的利润。有三件事
that they can do with their cash. They
他们可以用这笔钱做什么。他们
can save that money for an emergency.
可以把这笔钱存起来以备不时之需。
They can take some of that money and
他们可以拿走一部分钱，
reinvest it and open more stores and
将资金再投资，开设更多门店。
create better burgers. Or the third
做出更好的汉堡。或者第三个
thing that they can do, which some
他们可以做的事情，有些
companies do, not all, is they can just
公司确实可以这样做，但并非所有公司都能这样做。
give this money away to their investors,
把这笔钱分给投资者吧。
the shareholders. It's called a
股东们。它被称为
dividend. So, it's a cash payment for
股利。所以，这是一笔现金支付。
doing nothing except owning that
除了拥有它之外，什么也没做。
investment. So, if I buy something,
投资。所以，如果我买东西，
whether it's ETF, stock, or whatever,
无论是ETF、股票还是其他什么，
that's paying a dividend or a rental
那是指支付股息或租金
property that's putting money in my bank
能给我的银行带来收益的房产
account every single month or year,
每月或每年都要开户，
that's money I can use to buy food, go
那笔钱我可以用来买食物，走吧。
on a vacation, do something. Here's
度假的时候，做点什么。这里是
here's what Let me tell you.
让我来告诉你。
&gt;&gt; You're getting paid 4%.
你的薪水是4%。
&gt;&gt; Listen, who cares? I started buying
听着，谁在乎呢？我开始购买
Bitcoin at $3,000 a coin when it was at
比特币价格曾高达每枚 3000 美元。
I went through multiple crashes. I
我经历了多次崩溃。我
remember when $20,000 of Bitcoin was the
还记得比特币价值 2 万美元的时候吗？
oh my god, we did it.
我的天哪，我们成功了。
And once it hit around 70,000, I looked
当它达到7万左右的时候，我看了看。
at this and I said, "Wow, I have my real
我当时就说：“哇，我拥有了我的真实身份。”
estate, my stocks, my speculative, which
房地产、我的股票、我的投机资产，哪个
is crypto and startups, and then 2%
是加密货币和创业公司，然后是 2%
gold, which is now looking extremely
黄金，目前看起来非常值钱。
inflated. I need to lower this. That way
膨胀。我需要降低这个值。那样
I can have some more income." So what
我可以增加一些收入。”那又怎样？
did I do? I sold some Bitcoin about
我做了吗？我卖了一些比特币
rental properties. That now rental
出租房产。现在出租
property is putting money in my bank
房产正在为我的银行账户带来收入。
account every single month.
每个月都要开户。
The Bitcoin, it's a big number on paper,
比特币，从账面上看，它是个很大的数字。
but it doesn't actually mean anything
但这实际上没有任何意义。
unless I do something with it.
除非我拿它做点什么。
&gt;&gt; Could you have staked it, which means
你有可能把它押上赌注吗？这意味着
you can stake the cryptocurrency and
你可以质押加密货币，
make a monthly yield from it,
每月从中获得收益，
&gt;&gt; get a loan against it?
可以用它作抵押贷款吗？
&gt;&gt; Now, that's adding risk. Well, what
这无疑增加了风险。嗯，什么
happened into if I take a 80% loan, 70%
如果我贷款80%，结果就变成了70%。
loan? Let's let's uh 50% loan.
贷款？咱们就先借50%吧。
&gt;&gt; Yeah, it's it's very volatile. So
是的，它非常不稳定。所以
&gt;&gt; So let's take let's take a 50% loan
所以我们假设贷款额为50%。
&gt;&gt; and Bitcoin falls by 70%. Which it has.
比特币下跌70%。确实如此。
Now I'm underwater. Now what? Now the
我现在在水下。接下来怎么办？现在是
bank comes knocking on the door. Margin
银行来敲门了。利润
call. You're forced to sell and it's a
称呼。你被迫出售，而且
foreclosure.
止赎。
&gt;&gt; My point being on my Bitcoin.
我的意思是，关于我的比特币。
&gt;&gt; I mean, I don't disagree and really
我的意思是，我并不反对，而且真的
speaking, people should have the ability
说话，人应该具备这种能力。
to have cash flow or cash for if things
有现金流或现金以备不时之需
go wrong, right? That's really a super
出错了，对吧？那真是太棒了
important thing to be able to have a
能够拥有……是一件很重要的事
long-term view to be comfortable with
从长远角度来看，要感到自在
draw downs to be able to invest in
回撤以便能够投资
startups or to to invest in crypto or
创业公司或投资加密货币
technology and all of this stuff. Um,
科技以及所有这些东西。嗯，
that makes sense, but I just don't think
这听起来有道理，但我就是觉得……
a dividend of 4% makes any difference to
4%的股息会对……产生任何影响
anybody.
任何人。
&gt;&gt; Well, it does if you do it consistently
如果你坚持这样做，确实会有效。
month after month, year after year.
月复一月，年复一年。
&gt;&gt; You need huge capital to start with to
你需要大量的启动资金。
be worthwhile.
值得。
&gt;&gt; No. If if you if you start investing for
不。如果你开始投资的话
dividend income, I call it a decade of
我称之为十年的股息收入
sacrifice. And this is why it's so hard.
牺牲。这就是为什么它如此困难。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. But if you're 33 years old now,
是的。但如果你现在33岁，
you're sacrificing till you're 43.
你要牺牲到43岁。
&gt;&gt; You're going to become 43 at some point.
你总有一天会43岁的。
And imagine if you're 43 and now you
想象一下，如果你43岁，而现在你
have the income to pay for that car, to
有足够的收入来支付那辆车的费用
pay for the house, you don't have to
付房款，你不必
worry about it. Well, do you want to
别担心。那么，你想……
have hope that you have the Bitcoin or
希望你拥有比特币或
would you rather have more security? I'm
你更希望拥有更高的安全性吗？我是
again Bitcoin in my perspective high
再次强调，在我看来，比特币价格高企。
risk high potential return and I'm not
风险高但潜在回报也高，而我不是。
saying don't buy it. I'm saying allocate
建议不要买。我的意思是分配。
it in your portfolio in a way where you
以某种方式将其纳入你的投资组合中，这样你
understand you are arguably one of the
我知道你可以说是其中之一
top crypto experts in the world.
全球顶尖的加密货币专家。
&gt;&gt; I'm not I also am not the stock expert
我不是，我也不是股票专家。
in the world. I'm also not the real
在世界上。我也不是真正的
estate expert in the world. What I doing
世界顶级房地产专家。我在做什么
is I'm probably going to be wrong. If my
我可能要错了。如果我的
stocks crash, I have my real estate. If
股市崩盘，我还有房产。如果
real estate crashes, I got my stocks.
房地产市场崩盘，我买入了股票。
Crypto crashes, well, that's part of my
加密货币崩盘，嗯，那是我的一部分。
speculative portfolio. I really don't
投机性投资组合。我真的不
care. And if everything crashes, I got
关心。如果一切都崩溃了，我还有
some gold. So, for me, I have to
一些黄金。所以，对我来说，我必须
diversify against myself because I know
分散投资以对抗自己，因为我知道
stocks crash. I know crypto crashes. I
股市崩盘。我知道加密货币会崩盘。我
know real estate crashes.
了解房地产崩盘。
&gt;&gt; But if you're not starting with a lot of
但如果你一开始就没有很多
money, your your strategy is the
金钱，你的策略就是
strategy of a rich person. Oh, I've got
富人的策略。哦，我有
houses and I've got dividends and I've
我拥有房产，还有股息，而且我
got some gold and I've got a bit of
我弄到了一些黄金，还有一点
this. That's the strategy of being
这。这就是策略
&gt;&gt; But I didn't start with all of those. I
但我一开始并没有拥有所有这些。我
didn't start with all those at all. I
一开始根本不是这样的。我
started with one.
从一个开始。
&gt;&gt; Where did you make most of your money?
你大部分收入来自哪里？
Being an entrepreneur. What would you
成为一名企业家。你会怎么做？
taking obscene risk?
冒着极其危险的风险？
&gt;&gt; I did. That was me.
我做了。那是我。
&gt;&gt; An entrepreneur is taking obscene risk.
这位企业家正在承担极其危险的风险。
&gt;&gt; But if I'm making $50,000 a year, the
但如果我年收入是 5 万美元，
first step, let's assume now I'm putting
第一步，假设我现在正在放置
$5,000 aside, $7,000 aside a year. I can
每年存下 5000 美元，或者 7000 美元。我可以
take high risk, high potential return or
承担高风险，追求高回报或
I can be conservative or a hybrid
我可以是保守派，也可以是混合派。
and not everybody should be taking all
并非所有人都应该接受所有
the risk because there's Bitcoin has
因为比特币存在风险，所以存在这种风险。
risks and again I'm telling you somebody
风险，我再说一遍，有人
who owns it the government could come in
政府可能会介入，因为所有权归谁所有。
and change policies on Bitcoin.
并改变比特币相关政策。
Quantum could change Bitcoin.
量子技术可能会改变比特币。
people could stop caring about Bitcoin.
人们可能会不再关心比特币。
And if any of those things happen and
如果这些事情中的任何一件发生，
all my money is in this very speculative
我所有的钱都投在了这个投机性很强的项目上。
asset, I'm the one that's carrying all
资产，我才是真正承担这一切的人
the risk.
风险。
&gt;&gt; So, if you if someone was $1,000 in
所以，如果有人有1000美元……
disposable income to invest, what would
如果将可支配收入用于投资，会投资什么呢？
what would you suggest they did,
你觉得他们应该怎么做？
Humphrey?
汉弗莱？
&gt;&gt; My take on $1,000 is as has changed over
我对1000美元的看法已经改变了
the years. I used to say you could
岁月。我以前常说你可以
invest $1,000, but as as rule probably
投资1000美元，但通常情况下可能
mentioned, 10% on $1,000 is is not that
前面提到的，1000美元的10%并不是……
much, right? So, like, you know, if you
很多，对吧？所以，你知道，如果你
invest $1,000 bucks in the S&amp;P 500, you
如果你投资1000美元购买标普500指数，你
get 10%. Next year, you'll have $1,100.
获得10%。明年你将有1100美元。
That $100 is not going to change your
那100美元改变不了什么。
life dramatically. So, if I had $1,000,
人生跌宕起伏。所以，如果我有1000美元，
I'm investing in myself. So, trying to
我在投资自己。所以，尝试
improve my skills to make more money at
提高技能，以便赚更多钱
some point.
某个时候。
&gt;&gt; How exactly would you do that?
具体该怎么做呢？
&gt;&gt; When I was uh still coming up, I was
当我还在成长的时候，我
trying to take a lot of courses online.
我正在尝试在线学习很多课程。
So, I try to figure out different types
所以，我试着找出不同的类型
of skills that I could that I could use
我可以利用的技能
in the marketplace. So, I took a AdWords
在市场上。所以我投放了AdWords广告
course back in the day for like 150
以前这门课大概要150美元。
bucks that taught me how to do Google
教会我如何使用谷歌的钱
Adwords and I would try to consult for
我会尝试为AdWords提供咨询。
for businesses out there to try to make
供企业尝试创造
more of an hourly income on the side.
更像是赚取额外的时薪。
&gt;&gt; And Google Adwords, for anyone that
还有谷歌广告，供任何人参考。
doesn't know, is Google's advertising
不知道，这是谷歌的广告吗？
platform.
平台。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. And now there's Tik Tok ads and
是的。现在又出现了TikTok广告。
Facebook ads, but you know, anywhere
Facebook广告，但你知道，任何地方都可以。
where I could be more of value to
我可以在哪里发挥更大的价值
another business, I knew that
我知道，还有另一家公司。
economically speaking that I could
从经济角度来说，我可以
command more in the marketplace.
在市场竞争中占据更大优势。
&gt;&gt; So, something with that like that would
所以，类似这样的东西会
be great. So, so right now clearly that
很棒。所以，很明显，
is AI because what what you saw there is
是人工智能，因为你看到的就是人工智能。
like a knowledge arbitrage with a new
就像利用新知识进行套利一样
technology where most people didn't
大多数人都不了解的技术
didn't understand AdWords and you could
不懂 AdWords，所以你可以
be the young guy bridging the gap for
成为弥合差距的年轻人
people's ignorance. So most businesses
人们的无知。所以大多数企业
now would be dramatically more efficient
现在效率会大幅提高。
and effective if they understood even
即使他们理解了，效果也会很好。
the basics of AI.
人工智能基础知识。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; So a kid could take a a course in AI and
所以孩子可以去学习人工智能课程，
do you know what's crazy? If you read
你知道什么才是疯狂的吗？如果你读过
the top 10 books on AI, you'd be in the
如果你读过人工智能领域的十大书籍，你肯定榜上有名。
top 1% in the world in terms of
就以下方面而言，位列世界前 1%
knowledge.
知识。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. I mean if you just read the
是的。我的意思是，如果你读过……
instruction manual of how chat GBT or
GBT聊天使用说明手册
you know quad works you you could
你知道四轮摩托车能让你工作，你可以
probably be in the top you know 1% of
可能位列你所认识的那前1%
prompt engineers right and that could be
及时的工程师们，这或许是……
a that could be a value to a business or
这可能对企业有价值，或者
service right so
服务权如此
&gt;&gt; that's probably where my career came
我的职业生涯大概就是从那里开始的。
from was we were the kids 18 19 20 years
那时我们还是18、19、20岁的孩子
old that knew social media cuz we'd
年纪大了就懂社交媒体，因为我们……
messed around with it so we sold it to
我们把它弄坏了，所以就卖掉了。
companies right
公司权利
&gt;&gt; and that started my first business and
于是，我的第一家公司就此成立。
then there was soon hundreds of us
很快，我们就有数百人了。
&gt;&gt; and there's there's a lot of these apps
而且这类应用有很多。
right now coming out from 18 19 20 year
现在正处于18、19、20岁年龄段
olds have you seen that that one profile
老兄，你看到那个个人资料了吗？
of that guy who created Calai. Uh Calai
就是那个创造了卡莱的人。呃，卡莱
is this this app where you take a photo
这是那个拍照的应用程序吗？
of your food and then you know it sends
你的食物，然后你就知道它会发送
it to to AI and it tells you how many
它交给人工智能，人工智能会告诉你有多少
calories are in it. Well, the guy's
它含有卡路里。嗯，那家伙的
making 50 million bucks a year or
年收入5000万美元或
whatever it is. And
不管它是什么。和
&gt;&gt; yeah, I saw that this morning, funnily
是啊，我今天早上也看到了，真巧。
enough, for $4 million a month he's
够了，他每月能挣400万美元。
making from a
用
&gt;&gt; like Chad basically it's an AI rapper
就像查德一样，他基本上就是一个人工智能说唱歌手。
obviously. I think he has some, you
明显地。我觉得他有一些，你
know, secret sauce that he puts into it,
你知道他放进去的秘制酱料吗？
but a lot of a lot of kids these days
但现在很多孩子都是这样
are using AI to try to leverage that and
正在利用人工智能来尝试利用这一点，
and try to turn bit turn them into
并尝试将它们变成
businesses. I do want to say though, I
企业。不过，我确实想说，我
think with $1,000 and with with what
想想用1000美元能做什么
Jess Breit said, I think you can still
杰西·布雷特说：“我认为你仍然可以……”
make a decent if you can make a decent
如果你能做到，就去做一份体面的工作。
income, you can start to slowly save and
有了收入，你就可以开始慢慢存钱了。
invest your way to some sort of
通过投资获得某种东西
semblance of retirement. I think you can
表面上的退休生活。我认为你可以
still be able to retire and be
仍然能够退休并
financially independent without having
无需拥有即可实现经济独立
to, let's say, bet your life savings on
比如说，把毕生积蓄都押在……
on crypto. I know that I personally
关于加密货币。我知道我个人
bought Bitcoin at $100, but I've sold it
我以 100 美元的价格买入了比特币，但我已经卖掉了。
many time. You know, I bought and resold
很多次。你知道，我买过也转售过。
it so many times because, you know, when
很多次都是这样，因为你知道，当
it's up 10x, you're like, "Oh, like, you
它上涨了10倍，你会想，“哦，就像，你
know, if if you had given me a 10x
你知道，如果你当时给我10倍的奖励就好了。
return when I first bought it, I like,
就像我第一次买它时一样，我很喜欢。
yeah, I'm taking that any day of the
是的，我随时都愿意接受。
week, right?"
一周，对吧？
&gt;&gt; Mhm.
嗯。
&gt;&gt; And so, I think that's why it's so hard.
所以，我觉得这就是为什么这件事这么难的原因。
It's like Bitcoin does produce 145%
比特币似乎真的能产生 145% 的收益。
return since 2012, but in 2012, no one
自 2012 年以来一直有人回归，但在 2012 年，没有人回归。
knew how to buy it. I bought it on some
知道怎么买到它。我是在某个地方买的。
random sketchy website. I got this like,
一个来路不明的可疑网站。我收到这个，就像，
you know, this this string of characters
你知道，就是这一串字符
for my wallet and I I try to buy, you
为了我的钱包，我尽量买东西，你
know, I try to buy a coffee at a cafe in
我知道，我试着在一家咖啡馆买杯咖啡。
Palo Alto and I didn't know that bitcoin
帕洛阿尔托，我之前并不知道比特币
transactions took 30 minutes to go
交易耗时30分钟。
through. So, I sent Bitcoin twice for a
通过。所以，我两次发送了比特币。
$5 coffee. Now, keep in mind this is 0.1
5美元一杯的咖啡。请记住，这是 0.1。
bitcoins, right? This is 10k worth. It's
是比特币，对吧？这价值1万美元。它是
an expensive coffee.
一杯昂贵的咖啡。
&gt;&gt; I sent it twice and they didn't get it.
我发了两次，他们都没收到。
And guess what? I still had to pay for
你猜怎么着？我仍然需要支付费用
the coffee with my debit card.
我用借记卡买了咖啡。
&gt;&gt; So, where did my go?
我的钱都去哪儿了？
&gt;&gt; You spent what? 20k on
你花了多少钱？ 20k
&gt;&gt; I spent 20k on coffee. Yeah, that could
我花了2万块钱买咖啡。是的，有可能。
be the title of this video. just
成为这段视频的标题。只是
spent 20k on coffee. Yeah, I literally
花了2万块钱买咖啡。是的，我真的
was I I sent it to Koopa Cafe in Palto
我把它寄到了帕尔托的库巴咖啡馆。
if anyone wants to go there.
如果有人想去那里的话。
&gt;&gt; I think the average person
我认为普通人
psychologically speaking,
从心理学角度来说，
&gt;&gt; it's really hard when it goes down 80%.
当它下降 80% 的时候，真的很难受。
And if Jasp Breed says you need money
如果贾斯普·布里德说你需要钱
like at that moment, you're going to
就像在那一刻，你即将……
sell it.
卖掉它。
&gt;&gt; But your your point about I mean the
但你的观点是关于……我的意思是……
primarily important thing is income.
最重要的就是收入。
&gt;&gt; Yes. I mean, and that and we talked
是的。我的意思是，还有，我们聊了聊。
about last time I was on the podcast,
上次我上播客节目的时候，
he's like, "How do you just leverage the
他就像在说：“你如何利用……”
same skills in different ways that you
你以不同的方式运用相同的技能
can earn more money from it?" Like the
能从中赚更多钱吗？比如
story I was told when I left university
我离开大学时听到的故事
was speaking to a friend of my dad's, he
我当时正在和我爸爸的一个朋友聊天，他
was like, "Well, what are you going to
当时我就想，“那你打算怎么办？”
do?" And my father was in marketing and
“怎么做？”我父亲是做市场营销的，
I liked marketing and but it was like
我喜欢市场营销，但感觉就像……
late '8s Wall Street thing was going on.
80年代末的华尔街风云事件正在发生。
And I'm like, well, I'm thinking about
然后我就想，嗯，我在想……
either going uh to work for somebody
要么去给某人工作。
like Mars, do marketing, you know, great
就像玛氏公司那样，做好市场营销，你知道，很棒。
company, or or going work in the city in
公司，或者去城里工作
London. And the guy looked at me and
伦敦。那家伙看了我一眼，
said, it's really simple, Ral. It's the
他说，这其实很简单，拉尔。这是
same job. You're a salesman in both.
同样的工作。你在这两个领域都是推销员。
One, you get free miles, and the other,
一种方法可以获得免费里程，另一种方法是……
you get free money. And he realized, oh,
你可以获得免费的钱。他突然意识到，哦，
there's actually arbitrage in what you
实际上，你所做的一切都存在套利机会。
can do with the same skill set.
具备同样的技能即可。
&gt;&gt; Mhm. Well, I would say there is a point.
嗯。嗯，我觉得有道理。
So, I agree. If it was me with $1,000,
我同意。如果是我，手里有1000美元，
I'm going to go out and invest in my
我打算出去投资我的
income, read some books, get whatever I
收入，读些书，买些我想要的东西
got to do, go start something because
我得做点什么，去开始做点什么，因为
that's enough. But if we look at time,
够了。但如果我们从时间的角度来看，
$1,000 compounded is decent. If I if you
1000美元复利收益相当不错。如果我如果你
go back 1971,
回到1971年，
&gt;&gt; but how do I pay for my college loan and
但我该如何偿还我的大学贷款？
my house deposit and I want to get
我的购房首付，我想得到
married and have kids?
已婚并有孩子？
&gt;&gt; You're telling me I can't do that for
你是说我不能那样做吗？
another 20 years? If I took $1,000 in
再过20年？如果我拿走1000美元
1971, I invested that into the S&amp;P 500
1971年，我把那笔钱投资到了标准普尔500指数基金。
and I did nothing else. I keep doing
我什么也没做。我一直这样做
whatever I'm doing, my job, and I only
无论我在做什么，我的工作，而且我只……
invest $1,000. I never invested another
投资1000美元。我再也没有投资过。
penny again. Today, that would be worth
又是一便士。今天，那将值
if I reinvested my dividends about
如果我将股息再投资大约
$330,000.
33万美元。
And I never invested another penny after
此后我再也没有投资过一分钱。
the first $1,000 investment. Why?
首笔1000美元投资。为什么？
because the S&amp;P 500 has grown by a
因为标普500指数增长了
little bit over 10% a year from 1971 to
从1971年到现在，每年略高于10%。
now. It's something. Now, imagine if I
现在。总比没有强。现在，想象一下如果我
invested $1,000 a year, $1,000 a month.
每年投资 1000 美元，每月投资 1000 美元。
Now, I can't say that about Bitcoin
但是，我不能对比特币做出同样的评价。
because Bitcoin didn't exist 50 years
因为比特币在50年前还不存在。
ago. I can't say that about Bitcoin
前。我不能对比特币做出同样的评价。
because Bitcoin didn't exist 25 years
因为比特币在25年前还不存在。
ago. And so,
前。所以，
&gt;&gt; how about Amazon?
亚马逊怎么样？
&gt;&gt; That's that started trading in 2000 or
那是2000年开始交易的股票。
even better, Facebook 2012.
更棒的是，Facebook 2012。
How do I
我该怎么做？
&gt;&gt; do we not invest in it because it wasn't
难道我们不投资是因为它以前不是这样吗？
around? It hasn't been around as long as
大约？它存在的时间没有那么长
gold.
金子。
&gt;&gt; I mean, it's been has been around less
我的意思是，它存在的时间并不长。
than Bitcoin has shorter of time
比特币的时间比比特币短。
&gt;&gt; creates a profit. It has a tangible
创造利润。它具有切实可见性
value that you can see and feel because
看得见、感受得到的价值
I can go on to Amazon and order myself a
我可以去亚马逊订购一个
brand new guacamole set. They'll be
全新鳄梨酱套装。他们会是
there in 2 hours.
2小时后到达。
&gt;&gt; They didn't make a single profit until
他们直到……才开始盈利。
what, 2018?
什么？2018年？
&gt;&gt; Well, but that was that wasn't because
嗯，但那并不是因为
they weren't producing a value. It's
他们没有创造价值。它是
because they were growing so
因为它们长得太快了
aggressively. So, you think if you had
咄咄逼人。所以，你觉得如果你有
$1,000, you should you should invest it
你应该投资1000美元。
in the S&amp;P 500.
在标普500指数中。
&gt;&gt; Well, I'm not saying you should. I think
嗯，我不是说你应该这么做。我认为
personal finance is personal. I think if
个人理财是个人私事。我认为如果
it was me, I'm if I have $1,000 extra
是我，如果我有额外的1000美元的话。
and I'm just trying to figure things
我只是想弄明白一些事情。
out, I'm going to go buy some books. I'm
我出去了，我要去买几本书。我是
going to buy a class. I'm going to do
准备买一门课。我打算这样做
something about how do I increase my
关于如何增加我的
income? Going back to what you said,
收入？回到你刚才说的，
&gt;&gt; but if I'm saying I just want to work my
但如果我说我只想工作我的
job. I don't want to go out and do all
工作。我不想出去做所有事
that. I would do half into the S&amp;P 500.
那。我会把一半的资金投入标普500指数。
Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; And I would go half into uh individual
我会把一半时间投入到个人层面。
companies. So, more risk than the S&amp;P
公司。因此，风险高于标普500指数。
500. not as much risk as the Bitcoin.
500。风险不如比特币那么大。
And the reason why I would do this is
我之所以这样做，是因为
because this is something I enjoy. I
因为这是我喜欢做的事情。我
like that research side of things and I
我喜欢研究方面的工作，而且
understand this is something that I
我明白这是我需要了解的事情。
could see returns with. Like you talked
可能会有回报。就像你刚才说的
about Amazon, like you talked about
关于亚马逊，就像你刚才说的那样
Microsoft and whoever, there's
微软以及其他什么人，都有。
potential.
潜在的。
&gt;&gt; And what about you, Humphrey? If
那你呢，汉弗莱？如果
$10,000, does your strategy change?
如果给你1万美元，你的策略会改变吗？
&gt;&gt; My strategy is a little probably more
我的策略可能稍微更……
conservative or traditional. It's
保守的或传统的。它是
probably 90% index funds. Uh so tracking
可能90%都是指数基金。呃，所以追踪
the S&amp;P 500 and then 10% speculative.
标普500指数，然后是10%的投机性投资。
And my whole goal for that 25-year-old
而我为那个25岁的人设定的全部目标
would probably be to get to $100,000 as
大概目标是达到 10 万美元。
quickly as possible because at that
尽快，因为那时
point I think they have more options and
我认为他们有更多选择，
flexibility and they're able to kind of
他们很灵活，而且能够做到某种程度上……
use that capital to maybe take more risk
利用这笔资金或许可以承担更大的风险。
after
后
&gt;&gt; that's still 10 years with the S&amp;P.
那也相当于标普500指数的10年。
Well, eight years of the
嗯，八年了
&gt;&gt; S&amp;P about 7.84 years. Yeah. But that
标普500指数约7.84年。是的。但是……
also assumes that they're only doing the
还假设他们只做
10,000 bucks a year. Maybe they they can
每年1万美元。也许他们可以
save and invest a little bit more.
多存点钱，再投资一点。
That'd be nice. But I think for a lot of
那太好了。但我认为对很多人来说
people in America, if they can get a
在美国，如果人们能够获得一个
guaranteed $100,000 in 7.84 in 84 years.
保证在 84 年内获得 7.84 万美元。
I I think a lot of people might opt for
我认为很多人可能会选择
that.
那。
&gt;&gt; So, I agree, but I'd remove the S&amp;P.
所以，我同意，但我会剔除标普500指数。
&gt;&gt; You do all crypto?
你们都做加密货币吗？
&gt;&gt; No, I just do NASDAQ.
不，我只做纳斯达克。
&gt;&gt; Oh, yeah. You do NASDAQ.
哦，是的。你做纳斯达克。
&gt;&gt; So, NASDAQ compounds at 18% a year.
所以，纳斯达克指数的年复合增长率为 18%。
&gt;&gt; What is NASDAQ?
纳斯达克是什么？
&gt;&gt; The NASDAQ is um the NASDAQ 100, which
纳斯达克就是纳斯达克100指数，它
is the top technology stocks in the
是顶尖的科技股
United States, right? We live in a world
美国，对吧？我们生活在一个世界
that tomorrow will be more digital than
明天将比现在更加数字化。
today, guaranteed.
今天，保证有效。
Um and so therefore, these stocks tend
因此，这些股票往往
to generate the most performance. And
为了获得最佳性能。和
we've talked about many of these names
我们已经讨论过很多这样的名字。
that is all in the NASDAQ. So a little
以上内容均来自纳斯达克。所以一点点
arbitrage is if you want to shorten your
套利是指你想缩短你的
7.8 years
7.8年
&gt;&gt; to 5 and a half years, 6 years,
至5年半，6年，
&gt;&gt; buy the NASDAQ 100. It's an ETF, zero
买入纳斯达克100指数基金。它是一只ETF，零风险。
cost, easy. And then I would say and
成本低，容易。然后我会说，
then do 70% that 30% crypto and you
然后把那30%的加密货币拿出70%来投资，你
don't have to care about anything. True.
不必在意任何事。真的。
&gt;&gt; You're fine. Now, if you have a
你没事。现在，如果你有一个
different risk tolerance, you can tweak
不同的风险承受能力，您可以进行调整
those dials. Or if you are more
那些旋钮。或者如果你更
risk averse, then you up your cash dial
如果你厌恶风险，那就增加你的现金储备。
or or some other more stable flow,
或者其他更稳定的流动方式，
whether it's gold, although gold is
无论是黄金，尽管黄金是
still driven by the debasement of
仍然受到贬值的影响
currency. They're all the same thing.
货币。它们都是一回事。
They're all driven by the same macro
它们都受同一宏观经济因素驱动。
factors. But so, yeah, similar kind of
因素。但是，是的，类似的
idea.
主意。
&gt;&gt; And the NASDAQ is great. If I just say
纳斯达克很棒。如果我只是说
one thing, but just like with Bitcoin,
有一点，但就像比特币一样，
the difficult part with the 18% is you
18%的难点在于你
got to be willing to go through the
必须愿意经历
downturns. And I want to make sure that
经济衰退。我想确保
that's clear because I mean the big drop
那很明显，因为我指的是大幅下降
2000 the NASDAQ fell by 78%.
2000年，纳斯达克指数下跌了78%。
From its peak during that time the S&amp;P
标普500指数在那段时间的峰值
500 fell by 40%. So it's a bigger drop.
500下降了40%。所以跌幅更大。
Not to mention the NASDAQ didn't get to
更何况纳斯达克都没能……
its level until 2015.
其水平一直维持到 2015 年。
15 years later of no money.
15年后，身无分文。
&gt;&gt; It is still compounded more returns than
它的复利收益仍然高于其他收益。
the S&amp;P.
标准普尔500指数。
&gt;&gt; Absolutely. If you held on,
绝对地。如果你坚持下去，
&gt;&gt; you can't live your life of the drop.
你不能过那种跌宕起伏的生活。
&gt;&gt; 100%.
100%。
&gt;&gt; It's got to be in the riskadjusted
它必须包含在风险调整后的范围内。
returns versus the gains.
收益与回报的比值。
&gt;&gt; But how many people can hold on for 15
但有多少人能坚持15分钟呢？
years and say year one, h no big deal.
几年后，比如说第一年，没什么大不了的。
Year two, okay, year three, year five,
第二年，好的，第三年，第五年，
it's going to go up. Year 10, it's going
它会上涨的。十年级了，它要走了
to go up. And by the way, year 10 was
向上走。顺便说一下，十年级是
also another crash because
另一次崩溃也是因为
&gt;&gt; all you have to do is dollar cost
你只需要支付美元成本。
average.
平均的。
&gt;&gt; What's that? So dollar cost averaging is
那是什么？所以，美元成本平均法是
if you're young and you're you've got a
如果你年轻，而且你拥有一个
bit of excess cash now. You know, you've
现在手头有点闲钱。你知道，你已经
sold your income a little bit as opposed
相反，你稍微卖掉了一部分收入。
to just chucking everything in or you do
要么把所有东西都一股脑儿地扔进去，要么你就这么做
you put your large sum in. You've saved
你投入了一大笔钱。你已经存了一笔钱。
up your 10 grand, but now you've got
你投入了1万美元，但现在你只有
maybe $500 a month of of free capital
或许每月能有 500 美元的闲置资金。
you want to put into your savings. So
你想把钱存起来。所以
when you have these drawdowns, you're
当你遇到这些回撤时，你
actually keep buying. And what happens
实际上，应该继续购买。然后会发生什么？
is it lowers your average cost over time
它是否会随着时间的推移降低你的平均成本？
and you get to new all-time highs in
而且你还能创下历史新高
your portfolio much before the market
在市场开市之前，你的投资组合就已经被市场消化了。
did. So for example, in the last crypto
做过。例如，在上一个加密货币中
down cycle in 22,
22 年的下行周期，
in 22 all I did was add as much as I
22岁那年，我所做的只是尽可能多地增加我……
could to my crypto. So I was at new
可以转到我的加密货币账户。所以，我当时在一个新的地方。
all-time highs in my portfolio well
我的投资组合创历史新高
before the market was because I'd
在市场出现之前，是因为我……
lowered my average entry. That compounds
降低了我的平均参赛费用。这种情况加剧了
your profits over time incredibly. And
随着时间的推移，你的利润将大幅增长。和
is there something psychological there
这里面是否存在某种心理因素？
where if you commit to the habit of just
如果你能养成这样的习惯，那就太好了。
putting $500 in regardless of what
无论如何都要投入500美元
happens,
发生，
&gt;&gt; you remove emotion.
你去除了情感。
&gt;&gt; You remove a bit of emotion from it.
你从中剔除了一些情感因素。
&gt;&gt; And the emotion is the thing that people
而情感正是人们所关注的。
struggle with. If you're investing in
难以应对。如果你正在投资
things that are more volatile,
更不稳定的事物，
um you firstly understand that you will
首先你要明白，你会
see larger draw downs when markets go
当市场出现更大幅度的下跌时
down. Usually they're all correlated.
向下。通常它们之间都是相关的。
They all go down at the same time, all
它们同时倒下，全部
up at the same time.
同时起床。
&gt;&gt; So you're going to do that. But if you
所以你打算这么做。但是如果你
tell yourself that's an advantage for me
告诉自己这对我来说是个优势。
because I can buy more, that's a secret
因为我能买更多，这是个秘密。
hack that makes people fortunes
能让人一夜暴富的黑客技术
compounding. This is Warren Buffett's
复利。这是沃伦·巴菲特的
thing.
事物。
&gt;&gt; I% agree with that.
我完全同意。
&gt;&gt; More companies in a bare market than in
裸市中的公司数量比在裸市中更多
a bull market because
牛市
&gt;&gt; I agree.
我同意。
&gt;&gt; Yeah, I I 100% agree with that part. I
是的，我完全同意这一点。我
call it poop.
叫它粪便吧。
&gt;&gt; Uh panic leads to overselling leads to
恐慌导致超卖，进而导致……
opportunity leads to profit. So I am on
机会带来利润。所以我现在在
board with that.
带着它。
But that requires a specific level of
但这需要达到特定水平的
financial sophistication.
金融素养。
&gt;&gt; No, even your Coinbase app can just you
不，即使是你的 Coinbase 应用也可以让你……
can
能
&gt;&gt; dollar cost average.
美元成本平均法。
&gt;&gt; But how many people can dollar cost
但有多少人会因此付出代价呢？
average down 70% for 15 years waiting to
平均下跌70%，等待15年
see that?
看到了吗？
&gt;&gt; It wasn't 70% in 15 years. It was it was
15年内并没有达到70%。就是它
70% in one year and then rallied ever
一年内上涨70%，然后一路飙升
since. Every single year after year
自从。每年都是如此
after year it went up.
一年后价格上涨了。
&gt;&gt; Did you see that down? Well, no. After
你看到那东西掉下来了吗？不，不是。后
the 2008 crash, the Nasdaq also again
2008年股灾后，纳斯达克指数再次下跌。
crashed more than the S&amp;P 500.
跌幅超过标普500指数。
&gt;&gt; And then step back and look at the
然后退后一步，看看……
returns of the NASDAQ first.
首先是纳斯达克的回报。
&gt;&gt; I agree. Over the long term, it's a
我同意。从长远来看，这是一个
great investment, but volatility is hard
这是一笔不错的投资，但波动性较大。
for the average person who doesn't have
对于没有……的普通人来说
the emotional IQ and the financial
情商和财务
sophistication to understand.
需要一定的理解能力。
&gt;&gt; That's our job to educate them.
我们的职责就是教育他们。
&gt;&gt; Yes,
是的，
&gt;&gt; our job is to help people in this
我们的工作就是帮助人们做到这一点。
journey
旅行
&gt;&gt; and not get them to make decisions that
并且不让他们做出这样的决定
compromise their future. we have to help
损害他们的未来。我们必须帮忙
them. I agree. And riskadjusted returns
他们。我同意。以及风险调整后的收益
and time horizon are two of the single
时间范围是两个单一因素。
most important thing.
最重要的事。
&gt;&gt; And so what I hear I mean through
所以，我听到的意思是通过
history contrarians have made the most
历史的反面主义者们取得了最大的成就。
money. Um and also I think what the
钱。嗯，还有，我觉得是什么……
other thing that I've really pulled out
我还拿出了另一件东西
from what you both were just saying
从你们刚才说的话来看。
there is you need to set up a system
你需要建立一个系统
that removes emotion and requires you to
这消除了情感，并要求你
not make decisions because it's in
不要因为这件事就做决定
making decisions that your amydala the
做出决定时，你的杏仁核会……
emotional center of your brain is going
你大脑的情感中心正在……
to do make a bad one. And it's that I
做成一个糟糕的。而我
think that that self-awareness emerges
认为这种自我意识会逐渐显现。
from what you were both saying, which is
从你们俩刚才说的话来看，
okay, my brain is going to panic. It's
好吧，我的大脑要崩溃了。它是
going to poop or whatever you were
去拉屎或者不管你当时在干什么
talking about there. And I need a system
谈论那里。我需要一套系统
which is panic proof. So you know that
它能有效应对恐慌。所以你知道
the best performing brokerage accounts
表现最佳的经纪账户
in the United States are dead people.
在美国，这些人都是死人。
&gt;&gt; That's true. It's a known fact because
这是真的。这是众所周知的事实，因为
they don't do anything. So they have
他们什么也不做。所以他们有
these accounts that haven't been closed
这些尚未关闭的账户
and they're inactive. They outperform
它们处于不活跃状态。它们表现更佳。
all the active people. You are 100% in
所有积极向上的人。你百分之百投入
crypto in terms of your investment
就您的投资而言，加密货币有何意义？
portfolio.
文件夹。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; So, you must be sat here thinking that
所以，你坐在这里一定在想：
actually when I ask that $10,000
实际上，当我问到那1万美元时
question, what what would should someone
问题是，某人应该做什么？
do with $10,000? You must be thinking
1万美元该怎么花？你一定在想什么
that the right answer is to put it into
正确的答案是把它放进去
crypto.
加密货币。
&gt;&gt; The right answer for me is that to his
对我来说，正确的答案是对他
point,
观点，
&gt;&gt; but you you I actually would say but you
但是你，我其实想说，但是你
know this is it's an audience of people
要知道，这是一群人。
and people misinterpret things. Yes. The
人们常常误解事物。是的。这
answer is we've been given the gift of
答案是，我们被赋予了以下天赋：
the greatest performing asset the world
全球表现最佳的资产
has ever been given. That's not just
曾经给予过。那不仅仅是
Bitcoin. That's the the crypto complex.
比特币。这就是加密货币的复杂体系。
If you're very careful in investing in
如果你在投资方面非常谨慎
like top projects, you can even have a
就像顶级项目一样，你甚至可以拥有一个
more a broader diversified portfolio of
更广泛、更多元化的投资组合
that. Like you've had Ethereum, Bitcoin,
那。就像你已经拥有了以太坊、比特币一样，
Salana, Sui, all of these things great
萨拉纳，苏伊，这些都很棒
they will definitely outperform for a
它们肯定会表现得更好。
period of time and that's based on
一段时间，这是基于……
macroeconomic factors which is the
宏观经济因素，即
debasement of currency which we've
我们已经经历了货币贬值。
talked about. That means all of these
谈到过。这意味着所有这些
assets go up by a certain amount and
资产增加了一定数额，
some outperform it. The only two assets
有些表现优于它。仅有的两项资产
that outerform the debasement of
外在形式的堕落
currencies is the NASDAQ
货币是纳斯达克
and crypto.
以及加密货币。
This has been a persistent trend that is
这是一个持续存在的趋势。
observable and measurable. So this is
可观察和可测量的。所以这是
not a speculative asset. What it is is a
并非投机性资产。它是什么？
met law adoption model. Bitcoin is the
符合法律收养模式。比特币是
adoption of let's say a money or
比如说，采用某种货币或
collateral layer like gold, digital gold
类似黄金的抵押层，数字黄金
we'll call it. While the rest of crypto
我们姑且这么称呼它。而其他加密货币
is the new rails for the internet. So
是互联网的新轨道。所以
it's a tech technological investment. It
这是一项科技投资。它
is growing at twice the speed of the
增长速度是原来的两倍
internet in terms of adoption and has
互联网在普及方面已经取得了显著进展。
been since the first 5 million IP
自最初的500万个IP以来
addresses for the internet and the first
互联网地址和第一个
5 million wallets. Twice the speed of
500万个钱包。速度的两倍
the internet makes it the fastest
互联网使其成为最快的
adoption of any technology the world has
世界范围内任何技术的采用
ever seen aside from AI now which is now
除了人工智能之外，我们以前从未见过这种情况。
outpacing it.
超越了它。
&gt;&gt; If if we sit here in 20 years time
如果我们20年后还坐在这里……
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; and you were wrong.
你错了。
&gt;&gt; What happened do you think? Well,
你觉得发生了什么事？出色地，
firstly, in terms of investments, you
首先，就投资而言，你
have to always once you have a high
一旦达到高水平，就必须始终如此。
conviction bet, your entire job is to
信念赌注，你的全部工作就是
question yourself, not to keep
质疑自己，而不是保留
reaffirming yourself. Sure, you end up
肯定自己。当然，你最终会
reaffirming by questioning and then you
通过提问来重申，然后你
you figure it out. For it not to have
你自己想办法吧。因为它没有
been true, what would have happened?
如果这是真的，会发生什么？
The AI would have had a new system of
人工智能本应拥有一套新的系统
money that it created. This there has to
它创造的财富。这必须在那里
be a competitor to this because we're
成为它的竞争对手，因为我们是
now in the game of nation.
现在进入国家层面。
nations are acquiring this. The Middle
各国都在获取这种技术。中间
East nations, nations in Asia, the US
东方国家、亚洲国家、美国
wants to acquire it. So we've got and
想要收购它。所以我们已经有了……
we've got South American nations. So
我们有南美国家。所以
it's now the game of nations,
现在这是国家之间的博弈。
geopolitics. This is a real thing.
地缘政治。这是真的。
But what changes in 20 years time? Well,
但20年后会发生什么变化呢？出色地，
in 20 years time, we're in a very
20年后，我们将处于一个非常
different world. The economic engine is
另一个世界。经济引擎是
driven by robots and infinite
由机器人驱动，无限
intelligence.
智力。
We don't know how the economic machine
我们并不了解经济机器的运作方式。
works. We don't even know what the value
作品。我们甚至不知道它的价值是多少。
of money is when we go into that world.
当我们进入金钱的世界时，就进入了那个世界。
So I've talked about this before, the
我之前也谈到过这一点，
economic singularity. Past 2030, the
经济奇点。 2030 年之后，
economic model breaks down.
经济模式崩溃了。
So the the economy generally grows by a
因此，经济总体上以一定速度增长。
measure of population growth, how many
人口增长的衡量标准，即有多少
people are in the economy
人们身处经济之中
um or coming into the economy or being
嗯，或者进入经济领域，或者成为
born. Productivity, how much output they
出生。生产力，即他们的产出量。
create, and then debt growth is is the
创造，然后债务增长就是
other lever. What's happened here is the
另一个杠杆。这里发生的事情是……
population of the entire western world
整个西方世界的人口
plus Japan plus China has been aging.
加上日本和中国，人口老龄化问题日益严重。
So the rate of change of population
因此，人口变化率
growth is shrinking. They tried
增长正在放缓。他们尝试过
immigration but that became politically
移民问题，但这在政治上变得复杂起来。
unacceptable. So that's stopped. So
不可接受。所以这件事就此结束了。所以
you've got this slowing economy. GDP
现在经济增速放缓。国内生产总值
growth has been slowing over time.
随着时间的推移，增长速度一直在放缓。
Productivity. Old people make less
生产率。老年人收入减少
things. So it makes less economic
事物。所以它的经济效益较低。
output. So we've got this mess and then
输出。所以我们现在面临这种混乱局面，然后
we got this debt and we stopped that
我们背负了这笔债务，但我们已经还清了。
whole engine in 2008 and we need to
整个引擎在2008年，我们需要
service this debt. So okay, so that's
偿还这笔债务。好的，就是这样。
the system we're in and this is why
我们所处的体制，以及原因就在这里
we're printing money to service this
我们正在印钞来满足这项需求。
debt cuz we're not generating enough
负债累累是因为我们收入不足。
output in the economy.
经济产出。
But after 2030, this population part
但2030年以后，这部分人口将不再如此。
changes. We've got infinite
变化。我们拥有无限
artificial humans.
人造人。
&gt;&gt; You're talking about AI agents and
你指的是人工智能代理，
robotics.
机器人技术。
&gt;&gt; Yeah, infinite. So what does that do for
是的，无限。那么，这样做有什么作用呢？
that that the multiplier of that
也就是说，该乘数
formula, you know, population growth
公式，你知道，人口增长
plus productivity growth plus debt
加上生产力增长加上债务
growth? It breaks because you can have
生长？它之所以会崩溃，是因为你可以拥有
20% GDP growth because you've had an
20%的GDP增长，因为你拥有
huge rise in the number of AI agents
人工智能代理数量大幅增长
creating economic activity in robots.
利用机器人创造经济活动。
&gt;&gt; And so what does that mean for for me as
那么，这对我来说意味着什么呢？
a average person?
普通人？
&gt;&gt; For me is like the economic system
对我来说，这就像经济体系一样。
starts changing. We get to this world of
开始发生变化。我们进入了这个世界
abundance. We don't know what has value.
丰富。我们不知道什么才有价值。
what we as humans do, we we we change
我们人类的所作所为，会改变我们。
and retool to become more humans because
并进行改造，变得更像人类，因为
AI and robots can't be humans. So, we
人工智能和机器人不可能是人类。所以，我们
have to figure all of this stuff out.
得把所有这些都弄清楚。
Investing, we were talking about this
我们刚才在讨论投资这件事。
earlier, is like, well, does the the AGI
早些时候，就像，嗯，AGI 确实如此。
is that going to be a better investor
这样会成为更好的投资者吗？
than any of us? Yes.
比我们任何人都强？是的。
&gt;&gt; Artificial general intelligence.
通用人工智能。
&gt;&gt; So, that's the next stage where it's
所以，接下来就是……
smarter than any human that's ever
比任何人类都聪明
existed and we're very close to that.
它曾经存在过，而且我们离它非常接近了。
So, in which case, well, how do markets
那么，在这种情况下，市场又该如何运作呢？
work? And when businesses are agents
工作？当企业成为代理人时
selling stuff to other agents, where do
向其他代理商出售商品，在哪里？
we play a role? So all I'm saying is my
我们扮演什么角色？所以，我只想说我的
job my whole life has to been to look
我这辈子的工作就是观察
into the future sort of 10 years out and
展望未来，大概十年后，
try and probabilistically understand
尝试用概率论的方式理解
paths.
路径。
Here I get to like 2030 and it's like a
到了2030年，感觉就像……
dark curtain. Just to flip that for a
深色窗帘。只是为了把它反过来……
second, how could AI actually positively
其次，人工智能究竟如何才能真正发挥积极作用？
influence your hypothesis? I'm very
影响你的假设吗？我非常
positive about AI. I think humanity will
对人工智能持积极态度。我认为人类会
come out this just fine. I think
这样做完全没问题。我认为
economic growth that explodes is we can
经济增长爆发式增长是我们能够实现的。
work a way of accreing it to to humans
将其积累到人类身上的工作方式
or society or whatever we want to do
或者社会，或者任何我们想做的事情
with this. I'm not an AI doomer
就这样。我并非人工智能悲观主义者。
&gt;&gt; specifically on Bitcoin's value and
具体来说，是关于比特币的价值和
price. How could AI make it even more
价格。人工智能如何才能让它变得更好？
important in
重要
&gt;&gt; Well, in the end, an AI is a it requires
归根结底，人工智能需要
two inputs. It requires it's it's
两个输入。它需要它的
Maslov's hierarchy of needs is basically
马斯洛的需求层次理论基本上是
two things comput and energy and it
计算机和能源这两件事，以及它
needs to be paid. These agents can't you
需要支付费用。这些代理人不能……
can't build all this agents of billions
不可能建造所有这些数十亿个代理商
of agents running around doing things
特工们四处奔走做事
without paying for them. And agents will
无需付费。代理人将
use agents. So they will one agent will
使用代理。所以他们会派一个代理人
get another 10 agents to do all this
再找10个特工来做这些事
task. They're all going to have to be
任务。他们都必须是
paid. And the way of doing that is using
有薪酬的。而实现这一目标的方法是使用
crypto rails,
加密铁路，
&gt;&gt; stable coins,
稳定币
&gt;&gt; whether it's stable coins, whatever it
无论是稳定币，还是其他什么
is. But that whole crypto rail, you
是。但整个加密货币领域，你
know, all of this new infrastructure for
要知道，所有这些新的基础设施都是为了
the internet, the the blockchain, that's
互联网，区块链，就是这些。
where it works.
在某些地方它有效。
&gt;&gt; Often the difference between a company
通常，公司之间的区别就在于此。
succeeding or failing isn't down to its
成功或失败并非完全取决于它
product or strategy. It's down to the
产品或策略。这取决于……
people on the inside. After all, the
内部人员。毕竟，
definition of the word company is group
公司一词的定义是集团
of people. And some of the best
人。还有一些最好的
companies in the world have been largely
世界上的公司大多
built by a players. Because I'll let you
由玩家建造。因为我会让你这么做
in on a little secret. When you hire an
知道一个小秘密。当你雇佣一个
A player, they go on to hire more A
一名球员，他们继续雇佣更多球员。
players. And it perpetuates. The
玩家。而且这种情况还会持续下去。这
challenge is finding those first few A
挑战在于找到最初的几个A
players. I found the majority of mine on
玩家。我的大部分都是在……上找到的
LinkedIn who are a sponsor of this show.
LinkedIn是本次节目的赞助商之一。
LinkedIn provides talent I could not
LinkedIn 提供了我无法企及的人才。
find anywhere else. Talent with the
别的地方都找不到。天赋
necessary skills and culture fit that
必要的技能和文化契合度
I'm looking for. Whenever I've paid to
我在找。每当我付费
promote a role on LinkedIn, I've been
我一直在LinkedIn上推广一个职位。
able to hire faster and of course
能够更快地招聘到人才，当然
better. Their data supports this, too.
更好的。他们的数据也支持这一点。
You'll actually get three times more
实际上你会得到三倍的收益
qualified applicants than if you posted
比你发布的信息能吸引更多合格的申请人
the same role for free. So, if you're
免费担任同样的角色。所以，如果你是
trying to build something truly great,
努力打造真正伟大的事物，
you can get started by posting a job for
你可以通过发布职位来开始。
free by visiting linkedin.com/doac.
访问 linkedin.com/doac 即可免费获取。
That's linkedin.com/doac
那是 linkedin.com/doac
and you can post your role for free
您可以免费发布您的职位信息。
there. Terms and conditions, of course,
那里。当然，还有相关条款和条件。
apply. Do any of you remember a
申请。你们当中有人记得吗？
conversation I had on this podcast with
我在这期播客节目中与……进行了一次对话
anthropologist Daniel Lieberman. It was
人类学家丹尼尔·利伯曼。那是
one of our most viewed conversations of
我们观看次数最多的对话之一
all time. And the most replayed moment
一直以来。以及被反复播放的瞬间
in that conversation was when I talked
在那次谈话中，我谈到了
about this product. These are what I
关于本产品。这些是我
call barefoot shoes by Vivo Barefoot,
叫Vivo Barefoot赤足鞋
which have significantly reduced
这已显著减少
support, which gives my feet the
支撑，这给了我的双脚
opportunity that they desperately want
他们迫切想要的机会
to need to strengthen. If you've learned
需要加强。如果你已经学会了
anything from this podcast, it might be
这个播客里的任何内容，都可能是
that we're living in a comfort crisis.
我们正生活在一场舒适危机之中。
And that at all times in our lives,
而且在我们生活的任何时候，
we're making this trade of whether to
我们正在就此进行权衡：
have more comfort now and therefore more
现在更舒适，因此也更舒适
discomfort in the future or a little bit
未来可能会感到不适，或者只是轻微的不适
less comfort now, but to be stronger and
现在舒适度有所降低，但要变得更坚强。
healthier in the future. And for me,
未来会更健康。对我而言，
that is the choice to wear barefoot
这就是选择赤脚穿鞋的方式。
shoes. So, if you want to start
鞋。所以，如果你想开始
strengthening your feet and your body,
增强足部和身体力量，
visit vivobarfoot.com/stephven
访问 vivobarfoot.com/stephven
and you'll get 20% off when you use code
使用优惠码即可享受 20% 的折扣
Stevenb20
Stevenb20
at checkout. That also comes with a
结账时。这还附带一个
100day money back guarantee. What have
100天退款保证。有什么
you got to lose?
你有什么可输的？
&gt;&gt; I wanted to ask you a question. The
我想问你一个问题。这
reason I went and got my phone is
我去取手机的原因是
because um
因为……
&gt;&gt; I had someone contact me that I knew
我认识的一个人联系了我。
from my childhood. Used to be one of my
来自我的童年。曾经是我的其中之一
best friends. Frankly, not spoke to them
最好的朋友。坦白说，我没跟他们说过话。
in 10 years. sent me a text
他妈的10年。给我发了条短信
message and
信息和
the text message they sent me is
他们发给我的短信是
and I wanted to get your opinion on this
我想听听你对此的看法。
because I I said I ended up saying to
因为我说，我最后说了
him, listen, I'm not the guy to ask
听着，我不是问他的人。
about this. I think you've misunderstood
关于这件事。我想你误会了。
who I am.
我是谁。
&gt;&gt; Hi, mate. I hope you're well. I got
嗨，伙计。希望你一切都好。我得到了
myself in a bit of trouble with some
我自己也遇到了一些麻烦。
debt about £40,000.
负债约4万英镑。
some more than a bit of trouble after
之后出现了一些小麻烦。
I'm after some advice and direction in
我需要一些建议和指导。
terms of maybe passive income slash an
就被动收入而言，或许可以算作……
avenue to try and work my way out of it.
想办法摆脱困境。
Is there some material I should be
我应该准备哪些材料？
reading watching that you might know of?
你有什么想看的书籍或电视节目推荐吗？
And I asked him I said what kind of debt
我问他，我说，是什么类型的债务。
is it? And he said personal loans and
是吗？他说个人贷款和
credit cards, mate. Um and I said like
用信用卡吧，伙计。嗯，我说就像
how I need to ascertain how urgent those
我需要如何确定这些事情的紧迫性
debts are and if it's causing any any
债务是，以及它是否造成了任何后果
immediate issues. and he said, "Well,
当前问题。他说：“嗯，
they're not super urgent, but as a
它们并非特别紧急，但作为一种
result of the high monthly outgoings,
这是由于每月支出过高造成的。
I'm a month behind my mortgage payment
我的房贷已经逾期一个月了。
this month. So, it like is, but it's not
本月。所以，它看起来像，但又不是。
because I don't want to keep being in
因为我不想继续待在……
that position moving forward. It's
这一立场将继续下去。它是
costing me circa $1,000, £800 a month in
每月花费我大约1000美元，800英镑。
repayments at the moment, and I can't
目前我无力偿还贷款，
get a consolidation loan. It's a perfect
申请债务整合贷款。这是一个完美的
storm starting because I've just started
暴风雨开始了，因为我刚刚开始
a new job, and my partner is on
我找到了一份新工作，我的伴侣正在……
maternity leave, and I have this debt
休产假，而且我还背负着这笔债务
mountain. It's starting to affect my
山。它开始影响我的
family
家庭
&gt;&gt; if I can't pay the mortgage, you know?
如果我付不起房贷，你知道吗？
So, I've got to change moving forward
所以，我必须做出改变，继续前进。
and figure out
并找出答案
&gt;&gt; what to do. And you're the man to ask
该怎么办。而你正是应该问这个问题的人。
for advice. I was like, "Fuck, I'm not."
寻求建议。我当时想，“操，我不是。”
And then he messaged me again within an
然后他又在一个月内给我发了消息。
hour and said, "Hey, sorry, man. If
一个小时后，他说：“嘿，抱歉，伙计。如果
you're busy, just wanted to nudge this."
你很忙，我只是想提醒你一下。
Then messaged again an hour later cuz I
一小时后我又发了一条信息，因为我
was on a flight and said, "Hey, I really
当时我在飞机上，然后说：“嘿，我真的
need some help and direction, man. I'm
兄弟，我需要一些帮助和指导。我是
quickly running out of places to turn."
很快就无路可走了。
He's kind of in a hard spot because
他处境有点艰难，因为
£40,000 in debt with the interest
负债4万英镑，含利息
payments of let's say your interest rate
假设你的利率是……
is 15 to 20% that starts to spiral out
15%到20%的比例开始螺旋式下降
of control a little bit. Like if he was
稍微控制一下。就好像他是
under £10,000 in in debt, it's a little
负债不到1万英镑，这有点……
bit more manageable. But at 40,000, the
更容易一些。但40,000人时，
interest starts to compound quite
利息开始迅速复利增长。
quickly.
迅速地。
&gt;&gt; So, you know, you said he had a
所以，你知道，你说他有一个
mortgage, he might even have to consider
抵押贷款，他甚至可能不得不考虑这一点。
moving, selling, selling the home to at
搬家、出售、将房屋出售给
least get the interest payments under
至少要支付利息
control or like reduce that amount of
控制或减少该量
debt. It's kind of that one of those
债务。它有点像那种……
situations where you just need to reduce
有些情况下，你只需要减少
every single expense possible and start
每一项可能的开支都应考虑在内，并开始
really pouring all your money into the
真的把所有的钱都投入到
highest interest rate debt that he owns.
他所拥有的利率最高的债务。
So like, you know, you can rank your
所以，你知道，你可以给你的排名
interest rates of all your debts from
你所有债务的利率
highest to lowest and start start at the
从最高到最低，从这里开始
very top, right? If it has 22% interest
最上面，对吧？如果它有 22% 的利率
rate, you want to get rid of that first
利率，你首先想摆脱它。
because that's what's killing them. At
因为这就是导致他们死亡的原因。在
those levels of debt, it's really tough
背负如此巨额的债务，真的很难。
because I think a lot of people consider
因为我认为很多人都会考虑
bankruptcy at that point just to kind of
当时的破产只是为了某种程度上……
clear that amount of debt. uh depending
还清该笔债务。呃，视情况而定。
on what his income is. I know I've
根据他的收入情况来看。我知道我已经
known, let's say, a waitress or a server
比如说，一位女服务员或男服务员
that had $50,000 in credit card debt and
他背负着5万美元的信用卡债务，
just unable to get over it because the
就是无法释怀，因为
interest payments were as much as her
利息支出与她的支出一样多。
salary. So, in those cases, unless you
薪水。所以，在这些情况下，除非你
can get a personal loan from, let's say,
比如说，可以从……获得个人贷款
a family member and, you know, kind of
一位家庭成员，你知道，有点像
clear that debt, you're in a really
还清债务后，你就真的陷入困境了。
tough spot. Reduce your expenses as much
处境艰难。尽可能减少开支
as possible, put any extra money you
尽可能把多余的钱都投入到……
have towards that debt at the highest
已尽最大努力偿还该笔债务
interest rate possible, the first the
利率可能，首先是
highest interest rate thing, and then
最高利率的事情，然后
consider selling some assets if he has
如果他有资产，可以考虑出售一些资产。
assets. Bankruptcy.
资产。破产。
&gt;&gt; Bankruptcy.
破产。
&gt;&gt; When should someone consider bankruptcy
什么情况下应该考虑申请破产？
and what's the trade-off?
那么，这样做的代价是什么？
&gt;&gt; The trade-off is seven years. Uh I
这样做需要七年时间。呃，我
believe your credit is shot in America.
相信你在美国已经信用受损了。
So, um but I I believe that uh actually
所以，嗯，但我相信，实际上
I think if you pull up a chart, someone
我认为如果你调出一张图表，就会有人
sent me a tweet the other day of like
前几天给我发了一条推文，内容是这样的
bankruptcy lawyer searches in America on
在美国搜索破产律师
Google and it's like been kind of like
谷歌，感觉就像是这样
going up and to the right, which is not
向上向右，这不是
a great thing. Uh bankruptcy just you
一件好事。呃，破产就只有你一个人。
know there's different types of bankrupt
要知道破产有不同类型的情况
bankruptcy that you can file for but I
你可以申请破产，但我
do know that it usually clears some if
要知道，它通常会清除一些……
not all your debt and you basically have
并非你所有的债务，你基本上有
to start over but as a result you lose a
一切重新开始，但结果是你失去了一个
lot of your privileges like for example
你的很多特权，例如
no credit score.
没有信用评分。
&gt;&gt; I read some stat I'm not you might know
我读了一些统计数据，你可能不知道。
if this is true but I read a stat that
如果这是真的，但我读到过一项统计数据，
it said something to the effect that
它大致意思是说：
people avoid going into bankruptcy
人们避免破产。
because of the stigma associated with
因为与此相关的污名
it. But when they looked at the
它。但当他们审视……
financial performance over 10 years of
过去十年的财务业绩
people that did go into bankruptcy,
那些破产的人，
those that did typically were better off
那些这样做的人通常境况更好。
than those that tried to avoid it for
比那些试图避免它的人要多得多
the next 10 years.
接下来的十年。
&gt;&gt; Um, so yeah,
嗯，是的。
&gt;&gt; I don't know. That could be anecdotal. I
我不知道。这可能只是个例。我
don't know. That's tough because if you
不知道。那很棘手，因为如果你
have $50,000 in debt and you make
你负债 5 万美元，然后你赚了
$50,000 a year, it's Yeah, it's
年薪五万美元，是的，是的。
different.
不同的。
&gt;&gt; Bankruptcy in some ways is a good thing
从某种意义上说，破产是件好事。
because it forces you to do crisis
因为它迫使你应对危机
control. It's like your expenditure,
控制。这就像你的支出一样，
what you're doing, what everything
你在做什么，所有的一切
becomes hyperfocused. Like you you led
变得高度专注。就像你一样，你领导了
in the beginning with about you know how
一开始，你知道的
people should look at their expense
人们应该考虑自己的开支。
expenditure, right?
支出，对吧？
&gt;&gt; When you're $40,000 in debt, you've not
当你负债4万美元时，你还没有……
been doing that.
一直在这样做。
&gt;&gt; Correct.
正确的。
&gt;&gt; And bankruptcy actually forces you to to
破产实际上会迫使你……
actually discipline that for a extended
实际上，要长期坚持这种纪律。
period of time where it becomes a habit.
一段时间内，它就变成了一种习惯。
So Stephen, that's why they outperform
所以斯蒂芬，这就是他们表现优异的原因。
in the end because you've created the
最终，因为你创造了
habit that you talked about right in the
你刚才提到的那个习惯
beginning of this discussion.
本次讨论的开始。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. So I I just found the stat here.
是的。我刚刚在这里找到了统计数据。
It said, "Yeah, this is one of the
它说，“是的，这是其中之一
uncomfortable truths in finance." And
金融领域令人不安的真相。”
the answer is often yes. Those who file
答案通常是肯定的。那些提交文件的人
for bankruptcy end up in a better place
破产后反而能过上更好的生活。
long term than those who try for
从长远来看，比那些尝试的人要好
prolonged periods of time to avoid it.
长时间避免这种情况。
And the research shows uh that people
研究表明，人们
who file for bankruptcy typically get
申请破产的人通常会获得
their debt wiped out and cleaned. And
他们的债务被全部清偿。和
they um removing unpayable debt. Um and
他们正在消除无法偿还的债务。嗯，还有
it's bankruptcy can bring immediate
它的破产可能会立即带来后果。
mental relief removing the crushing
精神上的解脱，摆脱了压垮
stress of unpayable debts. People who
无法偿还的债务带来的压力。那些
avoid it often live in chronic financial
避免陷入长期财务困境
stress which spills into their health,
压力会影响他们的健康，
relationships and work. So in short,
人际关系和工作。简而言之，
those who fa face bankruptcy head-on
那些直面破产的人
often recover faster and end up in a
通常恢复得更快，最终达到……
long a stronger position than those who
长期以来，他们比那些拥有更强地位的人更强大
keep limping along trying to avoid it.
一瘸一拐地继续走，试图避开它。
And I think somebody who's listening who
我想，正在听的人是谁？
may be in a similar or the same
可能处于类似或相同的状态
situation ultimately wants to know how
最终，情况想知道如何
do I get relief? Bankruptcy is one
我能得到缓解吗？破产是其中之一
option, but at the end of the day, there
选择，但归根结底，
has to be change. And that change is
必须做出改变。而这种变化是
difficult. And that's the part that I
难的。而这正是我要说的那部分。
think a lot of people have hard time
我认为很多人都过得很艰难。
talking about or comprehending. There is
谈论或理解。有
relief, but it comes with severe,
解脱，但随之而来的是严重的……
extreme, and quick sacrifice. What do I
极端而迅速的牺牲。我该怎么办？
mean? Number one, you got to cut back
意思是？第一，你得减少开支
your expenses as fast as possible. In
尽快处理您的各项开支。在
that situation, you have to sell as much
在这种情况下，你必须尽可能多地卖出东西。
stuff as possible. I mean bankruptcy
尽可能多地装东西。我指的是破产。
obviously works but you also lose your
当然有效，但你也会失去……
house. You also lose other things along
房子。你还会失去其他东西。
with it. There's a lot of emotional toll
和它一起。这会造成很大的情感损失
with it. You have a family, you have a
和它一起。你有家庭，你有一个
kid. I mean it's also a big reason
孩子。我的意思是，这也是个重要原因。
people end up getting a divorce. So it
人们最终还是离婚了。所以它
can also impact your life in many
也可能在许多方面影响你的生活。
different ways. So you have to make
不同的方式。所以你必须做出
extreme sacrifices and I mean get rid of
做出极端牺牲，我的意思是摆脱……
the Netflix subscription not because
订阅 Netflix 并非因为
it's just costing you $15 a month but
你每月只需花费15美元，
because the average American is spending
因为普通美国人正在消费
more than two hours a day watching
每天观看超过两个小时
Netflix. And if you're in that type of
Netflix。如果你身处那种类型的
situation and you're spending two hours
这种情况，你花了两个小时
sitting there watching whatever the heck
坐在那儿看些乱七八糟的东西
is on Netflix, how do you sleep at
Netflix上有，你怎么睡觉？
night? You shouldn't be sleeping eight
夜晚？你不应该睡八个小时
hours a night. You better be getting up,
每晚数小时。你最好起床了。
going try to get some more money. I
打算再挣点钱。我
don't care if it's Uber. I don't care if
不管是不是优步。我不在乎
you're working at McDonald's.
你在麦当劳工作。
Find some extra money and learn how you
找点外快赚钱，并学习如何……
can earn some more money. And I mean, it
可以多赚点钱。我的意思是，
sounds harsh, but the reality is if you
听起来很残酷，但现实是，如果你
want extreme change, it's not going to
想要彻底改变，那是不可能的。
happen without extreme change.
无需剧烈变化即可发生。
&gt;&gt; So, could he sell his house? Do you
那么，他能卖掉房子吗？你
think that assuming he's making the 50k,
假设他年收入是5万美元，
which I think is probably accurate,
我认为这很可能是准确的。
having a vague understanding of his job
他对自己的工作只有模糊的了解
and where he lives, etc.,
以及他居住的地方等等。
&gt;&gt; sell his house and then move in, rent an
卖掉他的房子，然后搬进去，租一套
apartment, would that free up capital?
如果买公寓，能释放一些资金吗？
&gt;&gt; I mean, that would alleviate his current
我的意思是，那样就能缓解他目前的困境。
problem immediately. Sure.
立即解决问题。当然。
&gt;&gt; He says here after some advice,
他说，这是在听取了一些建议之后。
direction in terms of maybe passive
方向可能在于被动方面。
income, this word passive income, I know
收入，被动收入这个词，我知道
nuts.
坚果。
&gt;&gt; Why does it drive you nuts? It is a
为什么这件事让你如此抓狂？这是一个
there's like a passive income
就像被动收入一样
industrialization complex that is I mean
我的意思是，工业化综合体
it is literally every millennial's dream
这简直就是每个千禧一代的梦想
is I'm going to get passive income
我打算获得被动收入
&gt;&gt; and it doesn't exist. We talked about
它并不存在。我们谈到了
property. Property is the least passive
财产。房地产是最不被动的资产。
income you can imagine. It is awful.
你能想象到的收入。太糟糕了。
Every time I've tried to rent out
每次我尝试出租
property there are so many costs.
房产投资涉及的费用太多了。
Everything goes wrong. It's just
一切都不顺利。只是
endless. You're paying fees. And people
无尽的。你在支付费用。还有人
think there there's a magic passive
我觉得那里有个魔法被动技能。
income. Everything comes with effort.
收入。凡事都需要付出努力。
There is no such thing as returns
根本不存在退货这种事。
without effort. That's well even robbery
毫不费力。那甚至可以说是抢劫。
comes with effort. You know there
需要付出努力。你知道那里
there's no way of making money without
没有其他赚钱的方法
effort or risking something. And so when
付出努力或承担风险。所以当
you're 40 grand in debt, how on earth do
你负债4万，到底该怎么办？
you think passive income is going to
你认为被动收入会……
rescue you? But he's seen that on Tik
救你？但他已经在Tik上看到了。
Tok and uh on Instagram. Oh, we're we're
Tok 和 uh 在 Instagram 上。哦，我们是
are millennials in our in our 30s and
千禧一代正处于我们30多岁的时候，
we're now living in in the in in Lisbon
我们现在住在里斯本。
and we've got passive income from our
我们从我们的……获得了被动收入
house. It's like it's It's
房子。简直就是胡扯。它是
social social media dream that doesn't
社交媒体的梦想，却并非如此
really exist and that's never going to
真实存在，而且永远不会存在
save him from £40,000 debt.
帮他摆脱 4 万英镑的债务。
&gt;&gt; Passive income can exist.
被动收入是存在的。
The perception of what it is is the
对它的认知是
problem. I am struggling with money. I
问题。我经济拮据。我
have no money. I got bills to pay. I
我没钱。我还有账单要付。我
need passive income. Well, that's not
需要被动收入。嗯，那不是。
how it works.
工作原理。
&gt;&gt; So, how it works?
那么，它是如何运作的呢？
&gt;&gt; The way it works is you you take an
它的运作方式是，你拿一个
extra money, right? I have I'm going to
额外的收入，对吧？我有，我要去
work and I'm I'm I'm saving and
工作，我在存钱，
investing some money. I take the extra
投资一些钱。我拿走额外的
money that I'm want to put my to my
我想把钱投入到我的
investments and I can put it into an
我可以把它投入投资领域。
asset, an investment that can pay me for
资产，一项可以给我带来收益的投资
owning it without actually working,
拥有它却不实际工作，
without going to work to own it. Now,
无需工作就能拥有它。现在，
let me ask you about your real estate
我想问问您关于您的房地产方面的情况。
because I got to I got to keep coming
因为我必须继续来
back to you, man. Did did you did you
把机会还给你，伙计。你做了吗？你做了吗？
manage your real estate yourself or did
你自己管理房地产吗？
you have a manager? I've
你有经理吗？我已经
&gt;&gt; done both. I've had management agent and
两个都做了。我曾有过经纪人，
a management myself.
我自己也是一名管理人员。
&gt;&gt; Managing yourself is probably a a
自我管理可能是一种
absolute nightmare.
简直是一场噩梦。
&gt;&gt; It's horrific.
太可怕了。
&gt;&gt; And managing it with a manager is also
而通过经理来管理它也是
probably a nightmare just in a different
或许只是换了一种形式的噩梦。
scene.
场景。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. And because your yield is
是的。因为你的产量是
massively reduced as well.
也大幅减少了。
&gt;&gt; It is reduced.
减少了。
&gt;&gt; And then you take the trade-off between
然后你就要在两者之间做出权衡了。
whether you're going to do short-term
无论你是打算短期
less or longerterm rentals. And there's
短期或长期租赁。还有……
the volatility in the short-term less
短期波动性较小
that you don't know what your yield's
你不知道你的产量是多少
going to be. long-term different as
将会是。从长远来看，情况有所不同
well. Then you've got the tenants and
出色地。然后你就有了租户，
how bad the tenants have been and the
租户的素质有多差，以及
damage that they've done. Y
他们造成的损害。是
&gt;&gt; by the end of it, you walk away and
最后，你转身离开。
think really it was just wasn't worth
我觉得真的不值得。
the effort.
努力。
&gt;&gt; Well, I would disagree with part.
嗯，我不同意其中一部分观点。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. I mean, obviously people can do
是的。我的意思是，显然人们可以这样做
really well out of property.
房产收益非常好。
&gt;&gt; The work in real estate investment
房地产投资方面的工作
is learning the process. When I first
正在学习这个过程。当我第一次
started investing in real estate, it was
开始投资房地产，当时
a complete nightmare. And it was not
简直是一场噩梦。但事实并非如此。
passive, anything close to passive. It
被动的，任何接近被动的。它
was a nightmare. What you don't know
简直是一场噩梦。你不知道的事
when you start is that there's a good
当你开始时，你会发现一切都很好。
property manager. There's also a bad
物业经理。还有一个坏的
property manager. How do I find good
物业经理。我如何找到好的
property managers? By going through a
物业经理？通过经历
lot of bad property managers and
很多糟糕的物业经理
learning that process. And that is a
学习这个过程。那是一个
painful process, a very timeconuming
过程很痛苦，非常耗时
process. But when you do have the right
过程。但当你拥有权利时
team, it can be extremely passive. So I
团队，它可能非常被动。所以，我
I invest in real estate.
我投资房地产。
&gt;&gt; What kind of properties are we talking
我们指的是哪种类型的房产
about?
关于？
&gt;&gt; Single family houses and multif family
单户住宅和多户住宅
apartments.
公寓。
&gt;&gt; And do you have lots of them?
你有很多吗？
&gt;&gt; Not lots, but I have a decent amount.
虽然不多，但我有不少。
And how much of your portfolio is in
你的投资组合中有多少是……
buying properties and then renting them
购买房产，然后出租
out to families?
出门见家人吗？
&gt;&gt; 50%.
50%。
&gt;&gt; And what are your returns been like over
你们的收益情况如何？
year-over-year for the last decade?
过去十年逐年变化的情况如何？
&gt;&gt; So the way I look at returns when I look
所以我看待回报的方式是，当我……
to acquire a property is I want 7% cash
我想要7%的现金来购买房产。
on cash on the money that I put in. So
我投入的钱，用现金偿还。
when I look at return, I don't care
当我看回报时，我并不在意
about equity. We talked about this kind
关于公平。我们讨论过这种
of a lot that if I buy a house for,
如果我买房，那有很多东西需要花掉，
let's just call it $100,000 and it goes
我们姑且称之为 10 万美元，然后它就……
up to $200,000. I don't care. My goal
最高可达 20 万美元。我不在乎。我的目标
when I acquire real estate is not to
我购置房产并非为了……
sell it and flip it for a profit. My
卖掉它，然后转手卖掉赚取利润。我的
goal is to grow the cash flow that I'm
我的目标是增加我的现金流。
generating month after month after month
每月持续产生
rental payments.
租金支付。
&gt;&gt; From rental payments.
来自租金收入。
&gt;&gt; It's really difficult though cuz if I
但这真的很难，因为如果我
someone that hasn't done a lot of
一个没做过很多事的人
property rentals and stuff like that,
房产租赁之类的事情，
the chance that I'm going to up
我搞砸的概率
&gt;&gt; is so high.
太高了。
&gt;&gt; And I'm one of those people and I
我就是其中之一，而且
probably screwed up
可能搞砸了
more than more than I could count. It
多到我都数不过来。它
has cost me a lot of sleep, cost me a
这让我失眠了很多，让我……
lot of stress.
压力很大。
&gt;&gt; So, you have to kind of be an expert.
所以，你必须得算是这方面的专家。
&gt;&gt; Uh you don't have to be an expert, but
呃，你不需要是专家，但是……
you got to be willing to passive.
你必须愿意保持被动。
&gt;&gt; In the beginning, right, for the first
一开始，对吧，第一个
number of years, it was extremely
多年来，情况极其糟糕
painful. But today, when I go and I
痛苦。但今天，当我去的时候，
acquire a property, I will look for the
如果要购置房产，我会寻找合适的房产。
property just like I do research on a
就像我研究房产一样
stock or whatever I want to do. I do the
股票交易或者任何我想做的事情。我做
work to research a property. In today's
负责房产调查工作。在今天的
economy, it's much harder, not
经济方面，情况要困难得多，不是吗？
impossible, to find those returns.
不可能找到这些回报。
acquire the property, hand over the keys
取得房产，交出钥匙
to the property manager, give them the
交给物业经理，把
goals, and now I oversee the manager
目标，现在我负责管理经理。
because I have a team now that is
因为我现在有一个团队，那就是
&gt;&gt; it's a business.
这是一门生意。
&gt;&gt; It's like starting a starting a startup,
这就像创办一家初创公司一样。
&gt;&gt; but it's not like starting a startup.
但这和创办一家初创公司不一样。
&gt;&gt; Why?
为什么？
&gt;&gt; Because starting a startup,
因为创办一家初创公司，
&gt;&gt; when I work in my company, I am working
当我在公司工作时，我正在工作
at my company and I work a lot of hours.
我在公司工作，工作时间很长。
So, I'm meeting with my employees. I'm
所以，我正在和我的员工开会。我是
leading the meetings. I'm coming up with
主持会议。我正在想办法
ideas. I'm leading the vision. With
想法。我负责引领愿景。和
this, I acquire, I hand over the keys.
我得到这个，就交出钥匙。
I've already set the framework and now
我已经搭建好了框架，现在
you are doing the execution.
你正在执行操作。
&gt;&gt; That's a mature business. With my
那是一项成熟的业务。我的
company, there's hundreds of people in
公司里有数百人。
the UK right now.
英国现在的状况。
&gt;&gt; But you're not the one that's the
但你并不是那个人
starting that startup.
开始创办这家初创公司。
&gt;&gt; I was the founder.
我是创始人。
&gt;&gt; And now what have you done? You've
现在你又做了什么？你已经
acquired more employees to get there,
为了实现这一目标，他们雇佣了更多员工。
&gt;&gt; which is what you did with your property
这就是你对你的财产所做的事。
management.
管理。
&gt;&gt; It's much harder to do with a startup
对于初创公司来说，这要困难得多。
though. How big does a startup have to
尽管。一家初创公司需要多大规模？
be in order to be able to displace you
以便能够取代你
as a CEO to pay for the staff to make
作为首席执行官，要支付员工工资以创造价值。
the money and then to hire a new CEO and
用这笔钱聘请一位新的首席执行官
to lead it the way?
引领它前进？
&gt;&gt; Depends. My friends, my friend Ash, who
视情况而定。我的朋友，我的朋友阿什，他
was just with me last week in LA, has
上周刚和我一起在洛杉矶，
four people in his startup. He's out in
他的创业公司有四个人。他出去了
LA right now in my house in LA with my
我现在在洛杉矶的家里，和我……
girlfriend and my other best friend
女朋友和我另一个最好的朋友
who's still there. And I watched, he's
还有谁在那里？我看着他……
in the hot tub right now. I know that
我现在正在泡热水澡。我知道
because every day at the same time he
因为每天同一时间他
goes in the hot tub and then they go for
他们先去泡热水浴缸，然后就去了
this hike and my girlfriend sends me
这次徒步旅行，我女朋友发给我
photos. What he's done is he set up his
照片。他所做的就是他设下了他的
team of four people. They do personal
由四人组成的团队。他们做个人事务
branding on LinkedIn for people and
在LinkedIn上为个人打造品牌形象
they're running it back for him in the
他们正在为他重新跑一遍。
UK. He's up in bloody the mountain with
英国。他爬上了那座该死的山。
my girlfriend right now.
我现在的女朋友。
&gt;&gt; That's beautiful. But how many startups
那好美丽。但是有多少初创公司呢？
don't do it there? to start a business.
不要在那里做？创办企业。
&gt;&gt; You described it to me. I was like, "Oh,
你给我描述过。我当时想，“哦，
that's just it's just a business."
那只是一门生意而已。
&gt;&gt; A steep learning curve to develop
学习曲线陡峭，难以发展
expertise and then you put systems in
拥有专业知识，然后你就可以建立系统了。
place to make it sustainable.
使其成为可持续发展的地方。
&gt;&gt; But it the systems are kind of
但是这些系统有点……
pre-established
预先设定的
where you need to rent it out. You need
你需要把它租出去。你需要
a good manager. It's going to find a
一位优秀的管理者。它会找到一个
good tenant. They got to pay the bills.
好租客。他们得支付账单。
And it's it's not like a startup where I
而且它不像是一家初创公司，我
have to innovate and create an idea. I
必须创新并提出想法。我
don't have to go out and build the
不必出去建造
blueprint. I am going out. I'm acquiring
蓝图。我要出门了。我正在收购
an asset that people already need that's
这是人们已经需要的一种资产。
already existing.
已存在。
&gt;&gt; Mhm. and then I'm going to put use to it
嗯。然后我就要好好利用它了。
by having somebody live there or use it
让某人居住或使用它
&gt;&gt; and then there's a team just maintaining
然后还有一个团队专门负责维护。
it.
它。
&gt;&gt; So what do you think then in terms of
那么，你对此有何看法？
passive income and is it real? But
被动收入真的存在吗？但
specifically let's do this point of
具体来说，我们来谈谈这一点。
housing. Do you advise people to buy
住房。你建议人们购买吗？
rental properties and then generate
出租房产，然后生成
rental fees from them as a source of
租金收入是其来源之一
income?
收入？
&gt;&gt; Well, you just heard Jasp breed at how
嗯，你刚才听到Jasp是如何繁殖的。
much work it would take. So I I
这需要花费大量精力。所以，我
generally don't advise people to to get
通常不建议人们这样做
into that business just because of the
进入那个行业仅仅是因为……
steep learning curve and not everyone is
学习曲线陡峭，并非人人都能适应
built for that and not everyone has
专为此而建，但并非人人都有
capital for that. So if you're just
为此需要资金。所以如果你只是
trying to get started and actually make
尝试开始并真正制作
some money, I just think the stock
一些钱，我只是觉得股票
market is the most liquid and easiest
市场流动性最强，最容易交易。
place to get started. I personally rent
开始的地方。我个人租房
and I I plan on renting and just instead
我打算租房住，而不是
investing the difference of what my
投资我的差额
mortgage payment might be in my my rent.
房贷可能包含在我的房租里了。
I think in on the coasts like San
我认为在像圣安东尼奥这样的沿海地区。
Francisco, New York, I think Miami, that
旧金山、纽约，还有迈阿密，我想是吧。
might actually be the more reasonable
或许这才是更合理的选择。
thing to do.
要做的事。
&gt;&gt; I was reading a New York Times article
我正在读一篇《纽约时报》的文章
that just came out yesterday and it said
那份文件昨天刚发布，上面写着：
more millionaires than ever are renting
越来越多的百万富翁选择租房。
in the United States and that it's
在美国，而且是
tripled between 2019 and 2023. So, in
2019年至2023年间增长了两倍。因此，在
just a couple of years, millionaires are
短短几年内，百万富翁就出现了
choosing to rent more than ever before.
选择租房的频率比以往任何时候都高。
What's going on? My guess would be a lot
这是怎么回事？我猜会很多。
of the millionaires are probably living
这些百万富翁可能都住在
on the coast because they invest a lot
因为他们在沿海地区投入了很多资金。
or they have higher paying jobs and
或者他们有收入更高的工作，
maybe it's slightly unaffordable for
或许对某些人来说有点贵。
them to buy a house in say San
让他们在圣安地列斯买房
Francisco, Seattle, New York, Los
旧金山、西雅图、纽约、洛杉矶
Angeles.
天使们。
&gt;&gt; In the New York Times article, it says
《纽约时报》的文章中写道：
they're choosing flexibility and
他们选择灵活变通。
liquidity over ownership. Um, and they
流动性优先于所有权。嗯，还有他们
don't want to be bothered with the
不想被打扰
inconveniences of home ownership, which
拥有房屋带来的不便之处，
includes paying a real estate tax and
包括缴纳房产税和
insurance, especially in markets like
保险业，尤其是在保险等市场。
Florida and California where we're
我们在佛罗里达州和加利福尼亚州
seeing a lot of natural catastrophes.
目睹了很多自然灾害。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. So the US is a peculiar market
是的。所以美国是一个特殊的市场。
because there's this high real estate
因为这里有高价房地产
tax in owning real estate.
拥有房地产需缴纳税款。
&gt;&gt; Mhm.
嗯。
&gt;&gt; So all the time your returns are being
所以你的收益一直都在
reduced by that you pay. So whether it's
扣除你支付的金额。所以，无论是
like 1 and a half% or 2% whatever the
比如1.5%或者2%之类的
number is, there's that and then there's
数字是，有这个，然后还有另一个
the other real estate taxes that come on
其他房地产税
top of it.
最上面。
Interest rates have been high. They've
利率一直很高。他们有
been high for a while now. So a lot of
已经嗨了一段时间了。所以很多
people have just been priced out of the
人们只是因为价格太高而买不起房了。
market just in interest payments. But
市场仅涉及利息支付。但
now because of mortgage payments are
现在因为抵押贷款还款
here. The difference is actually with
这里。区别实际上在于
the rental is a lot of rental people
出租房有很多租客
aren't trying to cover a mortgage cost
并非试图支付抵押贷款费用
because they own the property outright.
因为他们拥有该房产的完全所有权。
So you get cheaper rates. So it's to do
这样你就能享受更便宜的价格。所以，这是要做的。
with price. The US economy's not been
价格另议。美国经济尚未……
super strong yet at Main Street level.
实力超群，但价格却很亲民。
Wall Street's had a great period of
华尔街经历了一段辉煌时期
time, but Main Street hasn't. So people
时间已经过去，但主街却没有。所以人们
don't have excess earnings yet. So I
目前还没有多余的收入。所以，我
think it's a function of that, but it's
我认为这与此有关，但事实并非如此。
probably a larger trend as well.
这可能也是一种更大的趋势。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. I think also it's understanding
是的。我认为这也是一种理解。
what the opportunities are. I mean,
有哪些机会？我是说，
there's a lot of flexibility with
有很多灵活性
renting. I mean, I finally bought a
出租。我的意思是，我终于买了一个
house in 2025. I've been renting before
2025年买房。我以前一直租房住。
this.
这。
&gt;&gt; So, you bought your first property to
所以，你买了你的第一套房产
live in with your family this year
今年和家人一起生活
&gt;&gt; for Yes. me to live in was 2025.
是的。我理想的居住年份是2025年。
&gt;&gt; Why didn't you do it sooner?
你为什么不早点这么做？
&gt;&gt; Well, because when I was renting, I
嗯，因为我租房住的时候，
could take the capital and buy other
可以利用这笔资金购买其他商品。
rental properties, buy other
出租房产，购买其他
investments. So, it was uh it made more
投资。所以，呃，它制造了更多
sense for me to put that money to work
对我来说，让这笔钱发挥作用是明智之举。
somewhere else. So, is buying a property
别的地方。所以，买房是……
as a means to generate wealth a terrible
作为一种创造财富的手段，这简直太可怕了。
idea?
主意？
&gt;&gt; As a means to generate to buy for
作为产生购买力的一种手段
yourself to live in or to
自己居住或
&gt;&gt; Well, but you know, when you when I grew
嗯，但是你知道，当我长大的时候
up, everyone said to me that you get
起来，每个人都跟我说你会得到
money, get a job, then you get a
有了钱，找了份工作，然后你就能……
mortgage. And so, like that's what you
抵押。所以，就像你那样
did.
做过。
&gt;&gt; That's one of the worst pieces of advice
这是最糟糕的建议之一。
you can give somebody,
你可以给别人，
&gt;&gt; but that's what everyone's doing. That's
但大家都在这么做。那是
still what the vast majority of people
仍然是绝大多数人的看法
doing. And I know that because I look at
正在做。我知道这一点，因为我观察过……
I look at my friends that um don't have
我看着我的朋友们，他们……没有
the same financial advice that I have
我给出的理财建议和之前一样。
from like my brother and my financial
就像我哥哥和我的财务状况一样
adviserss, my accountants, and the first
顾问、我的会计师，以及第一家
thing they do when they get a bit of
他们有点兴奋的时候会做的事
money is they go and get a mortgage and
他们用钱去申请抵押贷款
that's because that's what their parents
那是因为他们的父母就是这么做的。
did and that's what everyone's always
确实如此，而且这也是大家一直以来的做法。
done. Is that a good idea?
完毕。这是个好主意吗？
&gt;&gt; Yes and no. No. I think these days with
是，也不是。不。我觉得现在和
how the economy has been set up, don't
经济体系的构建方式，不要
forget when I was 24, 25, I was working
忘了我24、25岁的时候，我在工作。
in an investment bank. I wasn't the
在投资银行工作。我不是……
highest paid guy there. I was a 25 year
那里薪水最高的人。我当时25岁
old and to buy my first flat in London
老了，想在伦敦买我的第一套公寓
was three and a half times my income.
是我收入的三倍半。
That equivalent flat and the equivalent
那等价的公寓和等价物
income is 12 times.
收入是原来的12倍。
So rent makes much more sense now. And
所以现在租房更划算了。和
you might as well invest, buy all the
你还不如投资，把所​​有东西都买下来。
stuff that you think will drive returns.
你认为能够带来回报的事情。
But a house, a primary house is not an
但是，一栋房子，一栋主要住宅，并不是
investment. Never will be because once
投资。永远不会，因为曾经
you buy it, you don't sell it. You don't
你买它，你不卖它。你没有
realize the equity. Maybe your kids do
实现股权。也许你的孩子会这么做。
if you've got kids. So it's not an
如果你有孩子的话。所以这不是一个
investment, but it can be an investment
投资，但它也可以是一种投资
in your future.
在你的未来。
&gt;&gt; But there's like some optical illusion
但这就像某种视觉错觉。
going on here because when I think about
这里发生的一切是因为当我想到
renting, I go, "Well, that money, I
租房的话，我会想，“嗯，那笔钱，我
never see it again."
再也没见过它了。
&gt;&gt; But with buying a house, I'm paying into
但是买房的话，我就得向……付款
it. So it's like me depositing the money
它。这就好比我把钱存进去一样。
in a piggy bank. So logically, of
放在存钱罐里。所以，从逻辑上讲，
course, renting is wasting money. It
当然，租房是浪费钱。它
goes to someone else. I never see it
转给了其他人。我从没见过它
again.
再次。
&gt;&gt; But that's not exactly true. If you go
但事实并非如此。如果你去
out today, I buy a half a million dollar
今天出炉的，我买了五十万美元
house. I put 20% down. So I put $100,000
房子。我付了20%的首付。所以我投入了10万美元。
down. I finance $400,000.
向下。我出资40万美元。
I get a $6.5% mortgage. 30 years, my
我的抵押贷款利率是6.5%。 30年，我的
mortgage payment is $2,500 a month. Now,
每月房贷还款额为2500美元。现在，
what am I doing? I'm not renting. I'm
我在做什么？我不是在租房。我是
not giving money to my landlord. I'm
我不给房东钱。我是
building equity in my property.
增加我的房产净值。
But banks also understand the same game.
但银行也深谙此道。
They frontload your mortgage. What does
他们会提前收取房贷。什么
that mean? When I pay $2,500,
那是什么意思？当我支付2500美元时，
it's not 12250 going to principal to
不是12250要上交校长
build equity in my house and 1250 for
在我的房子里积累资产，并获得 1250 美元
interest. It's
兴趣。它是
&gt;&gt; principal being
主要
&gt;&gt; buying your house back for yourself.
买回自己的房子。
It's not half and half. It's almost all
不是五五开。几乎全部
interest. In fact, if you go on and buy
兴趣。事实上，如果你继续购买
the half a million dollar house today at
今天这栋价值五十万美元的房子
a 6.5% mortgage, 20% down
6.5%的抵押贷款利率，首付20%。
for the first 20 years of that mortgage,
在该抵押贷款的前20年里，
more than half of that payment is going
超过一半的款项将用于
to go directly to your banker's pocket
直接进入你银行家的口袋
with interest. It's not until you're 21
有利息。直到你21岁为止
that half of your $2,500 payment is
你2500美元付款的一半是
going to go towards equity in your
这将有助于提升你的股权。
house. So it's all interest zero equity
房子。所以，所有股权都是零利率。
and then slowly it moves like this. It
然后它慢慢地像这样移动。它
takes 20 years to get there. And then
需要20年才能到达那里。进而
what happens along the way for a lot of
在这个过程中，很多人会经历什么？
people for not everybody for a lot of
很多人，不是所有人，对很多人来说
people is along the way interest rates
人们一路走来，利率也在变化
go down. I need some extra money. So
下去。我需要一些额外的钱。所以
what do I do? I refinance.
我该怎么办？我进行再融资。
As soon as I refinance that amortization
我一完成那笔摊销的再融资
starts all over again. And so now I'm
一切重新开始。所以现在我是
paying all this interest again. and my
再次支付所有这些利息。以及我的
real equity that I'm building is not
我正在积累的真正资产并非
there. This is why I say it's not bad to
那里。这就是为什么我说这样做并不坏
buy a house. I think it's great if you
买房。我觉得如果你这样做就太好了
buy a house, but don't treat your house
买了房子，却不好好对待你的房子
like like you said, don't treat your
就像你说的，不要那样对待你
house like an investment. Treat it like
把房子当成投资。把它当成
an expense. Buy it buy it because you
一项支出。买它，买它，因为你
can afford it, because you want it,
因为你想要，所以你买得起。
because you're ready, but not because
因为你准备好了，但并非因为
you're going to build wealth.
你会积累财富。
&gt;&gt; I agree with both their takes. I think
我同意他们两种观点。我认为
that um
那个嗯
you know, a home is an asset that you
你知道，房子是一项资产。
can't sell very easily, so that's also a
不容易卖出去，所以这也是……
good thing. Like if you have $100,000 to
好事。比如，如果你有10万美元
put into stocks or $100,000 to put on a
投资股票或10万美元用于一项……
down payment and you know you were just
首付，你知道你只是
such an emotional person that the moment
她是一个如此感性的人，那一刻
that the stock market goes down 2%
股市下跌2%。
you're selling probably better to buy a
你卖的东西可能更适合买一个
house, right? You can't really sell your
房子，对吧？你其实卖不出去你的
house in the tap of two swipes. But in
轻点两下即可拥有房子。但在
terms of an investment, it's like
从投资的角度来看，它就像
usually it's much more than an
通常情况下，它远不止是一个
investment to people. They they buy them
投资于人。他们买下它们
for psychological reason or emotional
出于心理或情绪原因
reasons or this the sense of security.
原因或安全感。
So, I would just say like if you're
所以，我只想说，如果你是
interested in buying a house and you you
有兴趣买房，而你
can afford it, then that that's great.
如果买得起，那就太好了。
Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; And let's let's actually go with the
我们还是选择这个方案吧。
best case scenario. So, like I think you
最佳情况。所以，我觉得你
were mentioning this. I buy a house for
我们正在讨论这件事。我买了一套房子
let's call it half a million dollars. It
我们姑且算它五十万美元吧。它
goes up in value to a million dollars.
价值上涨至一百万美元。
Oh my god, I'm rich, right? Well, it's
我的天哪，我发财了吧？嗯，是的
invisible, but but yeah, I could take a
隐形的，但是，是的，我可以接受
cash out refinance, but now I had to pay
套现再融资，但现在我必须付款
all that. But here's the problem. You
所有这些。但问题就在这里。你
now own a million dollar house. What
现在拥有一栋价值百万美元的房子。什么
does that mean? You have to pay property
那是什么意思？你必须支付房产税
taxes on a million- dollar house. So,
价值百万美元的房屋的税款。所以，
you got to pay a lot more property
你需要支付更高的房产价格。
taxes. you have to pay insurance on a
税。你必须为……支付保险费
million dollar house. And so now if you
价值百万美元的房子。所以现在如果你
pass this house down to your kids,
把这房子传给你的孩子。
great. They got a million dollar house.
伟大的。他们买了一栋价值百万美元的房子。
But if they can't afford the property
但如果他们买不起这处房产呢？
taxes or the insurance on a million-
一百万美元的税款或保险费
dollar house, now they have to sell.
一美元的房子，现在他们不得不卖掉了。
&gt;&gt; Insurance is one of these really hidden
保险是其中一种真正隐蔽的领域。
costs that you don't realize. Um
你没有意识到的成本。嗯
particularly if like if you're in a
尤其是如果你身处……
hurricane area like Texas or Oklahoma or
像德克萨斯州或俄克拉荷马州这样的飓风地区
something, suddenly your house insurance
突然，你的房屋保险
costs are prohibitive on top of the
除了这些之外，成本也高得令人望而却步。
taxes you pay. People don't think about
你缴纳的税款。人们不会想到
So Jasper, you're saying by Bitcoin,
所以Jasper，你的意思是说，通过比特币，
right?
正确的？
&gt;&gt; Go all in. You're one coin away from
全力以赴。你离胜利只差一枚硬币了。
everything.
一切。
&gt;&gt; Zero cost.
零成本。
&gt;&gt; They've just clicked that. Clipped that.
他们刚刚点击了那个链接。已剪辑。
Gone viral.
爆红网络。
&gt;&gt; But none. No one at this table would
但一个也没有。在座各位都不会
adopt buying a house as a wealth
将购房视为一种财富
creation strategy.
创作策略。
&gt;&gt; No. You would all do many things before
不。你们之前都会做很多事情。
then.
然后。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; Correct.
正确的。
&gt;&gt; Would that be almost at the bottom of
那岂不是几乎到了谷底？
the list of things?
物品清单？
&gt;&gt; It's part of its age cohort. Who are we
它属于同龄群体。我们是谁？
talking about? If you're kind of like 38
在说什么？如果你大概38岁左右
years old, you've got a kid, you kind of
几岁了，你有了孩子，你有点
cleared up some of your student debt
帮你还清了一些学生债务
payments, you
付款，您
okay, that security thing is fine, but
好的，安全措施没问题，但是……
it's not an investment. Um, anybody
这不是投资。嗯，任何人
younger, just no.
年轻点？不行。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. If you're just talking pure dollar
是的。如果你只谈美元的话。
investment returns, I probably would
投资回报方面，我大概会
rank it lower on the list for sure.
肯定要把它排在更靠后的位置。
Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; Is there any such thing as good debt?
是否存在良性债务？
Because I remember at the start you said
因为我记得一开始你就说过
clear up your debt. Is there is there a
还清债务。是否存在
good debt? People make a lot of money on
良性债务？人们靠此赚了很多钱。
debt, but people lose a lot of money on
负债，但人们却因此损失了很多钱
debt.
债务。
&gt;&gt; I just try to stay away from debt
我尽量避免负债。
altogether. Yeah. I mean, I think, yeah,
共。是的。我的意思是，我觉得，是的。
there is such a thing as like good debt
确实存在良性债务这种东西。
if it's working for you and you're able
如果它对你有效，而且你能够
to to leverage that money to make more
利用这笔钱赚取更多利润
money. But a lot of people, you know,
钱。但你知道，很多人
with leverage get comes a lot of risk.
杠杆作用越大，风险也越大。
And I know a lot of people got wiped out
我知道很多人都被消灭了。
because they took on quote unquote good
因为他们承担了所谓的“善”
debt, right?
债务，对吧？
&gt;&gt; What's leverage? leverages. So, for
什么是杠杆？杠杆作用。所以，对于
example, in Jasper's example, you put
例如，在 Jasper 的例子中，你放入
20% down on a house and you take an 80%
首付20%，贷款80%。
the rest of it as a mortgage. That's
剩余部分以抵押贷款的形式偿还。那是
technically leveraging your money
技术上来说，就是利用你的资金进行杠杆操作。
because you're taking the 100k that you
因为你拿走了那10万块钱
have and now you are affording an asset
你已经拥有，现在你有能力负担一项资产。
that's 500 worth $500,000. If your home
那可是价值 50 万美元的 500 个呢。如果你的家
goes from $500,000 to a million, you
从50万美元涨到100万美元，你
have a $500,000 gain, but you only put
获得 50 万美元收益，但你只投入了
in $100,000. So, technically, your
10万美元。所以，严格来说，你的
profit or your return percentage is much
利润或回报率非常高
higher. It was leveraged by that debt
更高。它利用了那笔债务进行杠杆操作。
that you carried.
你携带的。
&gt;&gt; Well, I don't think most people know
嗯，我觉得大多数人都不知道。
that they can leverage their crypto.
他们可以利用自己的加密货币。
&gt;&gt; That's right. You can borrow against it.
这是正确的。你可以用它作抵押进行贷款。
&gt;&gt; So, anyone can. You don't need to go to
所以，任何人都可以。你不需要去
a bank.
一家银行。
&gt;&gt; No, you can do it instantaneously in
不，你可以立即完成。
what's known decentralized finance or
所谓去中心化金融，或者
there's there's a whole bunch of
有很多
companies that do this. Well, you can
从事这项工作的公司。嗯，你可以
borrow against your assets. You can even
用您的资产作抵押进行贷款。你甚至可以
do it against digital arts. I I'm a huge
反对数字艺术。我是个大
digital art collector, much like the art
数字艺术收藏家，就像艺术一样
market. You can actually go and borrow
市场。你其实可以去借
against the value of the art. Maybe 40
与艺术品的价值相比。或许40
50% against the value.
价值的50%。
&gt;&gt; Explain this to me super simply if I as
请用最简单的方式向我解释一下，如果我……
if for someone that's like never even
如果对某些人来说，那就像从未发生过一样
bought a Bitcoin before and is thinking
之前买过比特币，现在正在考虑
about potentially buying one, but they
关于可能购买一辆，但他们
would also like some way to have a
也希望有办法实现
little bit of cash.
一点现金。
&gt;&gt; Look, I I don't like it.
你看，我不喜欢这样。
&gt;&gt; Okay,
好的，
&gt;&gt; I understand why. But the issue is
我明白为什么。但问题是
you've got an asset that does this.
你拥有可以做到这一点的资产。
&gt;&gt; It's volatile.
它波动性很大。
&gt;&gt; It's very volatile. and you're borrowing
它非常不稳定。你正在借钱
a certain amount against it and you
对此，你提出了一定的反对意见。
don't know whether it falls below that
不知道它是否低于那个水平。
that value and you get liquidated then
如果达到那个价值，你就会被清算。
you've lost all of your Bitcoin. The
你所有的比特币都丢失了。这
whole game is if you're in a secular
整个游戏的关键在于，如果你身处世俗世界的话。
bull market it's don't lose control of
牛市中，不要失去控制。
your tokens own your Bitcoin all the way
你的代币始终拥有你的比特币
through and you have a risk of screwing
穿过去，你就有搞砸的风险
that up for the extra 5% income or 10%
那相当于额外5%或10%的收入
income
收入
&gt;&gt; in in Ethereum very different world
在以太坊的世界里，情况截然不同。
because you're staking so you're getting
因为你在进行质押，所以你会得到
naturally rewarded in the network.
在网络中自然获得奖励。
&gt;&gt; What does that mean staking? What it
质押是什么意思？它
means is in in Bitcoin you actually get
意思是，在比特币中，你实际上会得到
miners basically get rewarded for
矿工基本上会因为……而获得奖励
solving the the algorithm the
解决该算法
computation in Ethereum and Salana and
以太坊和Salana中的计算
Suie and the other big blockchains you
Suie 和其他大型区块链
basically get rewarded for securing the
基本上，确保安全就能获得奖励
network. So you stake your tokens to
网络。所以你要质押你的代币
secure the network as the more people
随着参与人数的增加，确保网络安全至关重要。
then have this network connectivity
然后具备这种网络连接能力
between them and you get paid for that.
他们之间有利益往来，而你会因此获得报酬。
So in Ethereum right now it's probably
所以现在在以太坊上，它可能
4% yield.
产率为4%。
&gt;&gt; Okay. Okay. So, just uh I'll try and
好的。好的。所以，嗯，我会尽量……
summarize this like a 10-year-old.
用十岁小孩能听懂的方式概括一下。
&gt;&gt; There's no risk in that. You're not
这样做没有任何风险。你不
getting leverage in that.
获取这方面的筹码。
&gt;&gt; I So, if I choose to buy Ethereum, which
所以，如果我选择购买以太坊，那么
is a form of cryptocurrency, I can take
是一种加密货币，我可以接受
my $100,000 of Ethereum and on my phone
我的10万美元以太坊在我的手机上
in a couple of clicks, I can move it. I
只需点击几下鼠标，我就可以移动它。我
can press a button and move it so that
可以按下按钮并移动它，以便
it is staked. And when it's staked, I am
它已被押注。当赌注押上时，我
basically using my Ethereum to secure
基本上是用我的以太坊来保护自己
the network to make the whole thing more
建立网络，使整个过程更加……
secure so it can run properly. And in
确保安全，以便正常运行。并且
return, they'll give me 4%
退货的话，他们会给我4%
of it as a payment every month.
每月支付一部分作为款项。
&gt;&gt; Well, not 4% a month, but monthly
不是每月 4%，而是每月
payments. Monthly payments
付款。每月付款
&gt;&gt; of 4% annualized.
年化收益率为 4%。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; So, you can you can get interest on your
所以，你可以获得利息。
crypto.
加密货币。
&gt;&gt; Yes.
是的。
&gt;&gt; And then if you're a little more
然后，如果你再多一点的话……
sophisticated, a little bit racier,
精致，略带挑逗性
there are then yield enhancements. And
然后，产量会得到提高。和
we talked about high yield bank
我们讨论了高收益银行
accounts. There's high yield versions in
账户。有高产量版本
crypto and you can get up to 20 30%. But
使用加密货币，最高可获得 20% 至 30% 的收益。但
now you're taking risks
现在你这是在冒险
&gt;&gt; and I can also loan against my Ethereum.
我还可以用我的以太坊进行贷款。
So I actually did this at one point. I
所以，我确实曾经这样做过。我
don't do it anymore, but I I had a,000
不再这么做了，但我曾经有1000
Ethereum and I and I put it um I took
以太坊和我，我把它放进去了，嗯，我拿走了
&gt;&gt; $1,000 or a,000
1,000 美元或 1,000 美元
&gt;&gt; Ethereum. Yeah, Yeah, I know.
以太坊。是啊，真他妈的。是的，我知道。
&gt;&gt; I actually I switched it into Bitcoin a
实际上，我把它换成了比特币。
little while ago. So a couple of months
不久前。所以几个月
back, but probably bad timing. This is
回来了，但可能时机不对。这是
why Melon
为什么是甜瓜
&gt;&gt; Terrible timing.
时机太糟糕了。
&gt;&gt; You should have called me first.
你应该先给我打电话。
&gt;&gt; I know. Um but yeah, this people
我知道。他妈的。嗯，是的，这些人
are emotional. Um, I had a loan against
情绪化。嗯，我之前有一笔抵押贷款
it. So, I borrowed a couple of million
它。所以我借了几百万。
dollars a at one point to buy some more
一度用美元买更多
other crypto assets against my Ethereum.
其他加密资产与我的以太坊进行交易。
And it was surprising to me that I
令我惊讶的是，我
didn't have to call anybody. I didn't
不需要打电话给任何人。我没有
have to ring a bank. I could just click
得给银行打个电话。我只需点击一下即可
a couple of simple buttons on my phone.
我手机上的几个简单按钮。
And this thousand Ethereum I had, I
我拥有的这1000个以太坊，我
managed to get a couple of million
设法弄到了几百万美元
dollars paid straight away in cash
美元立即以现金支付
straight to me.
直接给我。
&gt;&gt; Um, but I chose not to do that cuz the
嗯，但我选择不那样做，因为……
markets are super volatile. But but it
市场波动极大。但是，但是它
is incredibly efficient effective way of
是一种极其高效且有效的方式
people if you were to let's say you had
如果你要说你拥有……人们
$100,000 of Bitcoin, one Bitcoin to
价值 10 万美元的比特币，一个比特币
borrow $20,000 against it.
以它作抵押借款 2 万美元。
&gt;&gt; Yeah,
是的，
&gt;&gt; that's not very risky.
那风险并不大。
&gt;&gt; Or $5,000 against it
或者抵押5000美元。
&gt;&gt; or$5,000, whatever it is, it's not very
或者5000美元，不管是多少，都不算多。
risky. Or if you're in a different
有风险。或者如果你身处另一个境地
currency where you can stake it, very
你可以用这种货币进行质押，非常
little risk, very very little risk. It's
风险很小，风险非常非常小。它是
like lending to the US government, i.e.
例如向美国政府提供贷款，即
lending to the to the government of
向政府提供贷款
Ethereum, the Ethereum network. That's a
以太坊，即以太坊网络。那是一个
pretty decent way of of of enhancing.
相当不错的增强方法。
&gt;&gt; It's hard to do that with stocks. It's
但股票很难做到这一点。它是
hard to get a loan against your stocks
很难用股票作抵押获得贷款
if you have
如果你有
&gt;&gt; $5,000 of stocks,
价值5000美元的股票
&gt;&gt; isn't it?
难道不是吗？
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; It's typic I mean, when I was when I was
我的意思是，这很典型，当我还是……的时候
younger and I had I bought $10,000 of
年轻的时候，我买了价值 10,000 美元的
Facebook stock when I finally got some
当我终于买到一些Facebook股票时，我终于买到了一些。
money, I couldn't think I couldn't see a
钱，我脑子里一片空白，什么也看不见。
simple way of taking a loan against my
用我的钱作抵押获得贷款的简单方法
Facebook stock. It wasn't until later
Facebook股票。直到后来
when I had a private investment bank in
当我拥有一家私人投资银行时
Europe that my private investment bank
欧洲，我的私人投资银行
were like, "Do you want 50% of your blue
他们会问：“你想要50%的蓝色吗？”
chip stocks as a loan.
芯片股票贷款。
&gt;&gt; Yeah, it's probably usually reserved for
是的，它通常可能是为……预留的。
people with more assets. But I do want
拥有更多资产的人。但我确实想要
to push back a little bit on the staking
稍微收回一些赌注
yield. I do understand it's 4% virtually
屈服。我知道这实际上是4%。
risk-f free, but there are are always
虽然没有风险，但总是存在风险。
going to be risks with, you know, the
你知道，这其中会有风险。
price of Ethereum, right? So like you're
以太坊的价格，对吧？所以就像你
getting paid in Ethereum. And so
以以太坊支付报酬。所以
&gt;&gt; this is a key thing, right, is
这是关键所在，对吧？
&gt;&gt; your your risk is the is the currency
你的风险在于货币本身。
you're staking. So if Ethereum goes down
你在下注。所以如果以太坊宕机
50% then your fiat value of Ethereum
50% 即你的以太坊法币价值
sorry of your stake could go down versus
很遗憾，您的赌注可能会下降。
you know if you're getting a 4% high
你知道，如果你的兴奋度达到 4% 就好了
yield savings account it's backed by the
收益储蓄账户，它由……担保
FDIC it's virtually this
FDIC实际上就是这样
&gt;&gt; and there is another risk as well is
此外，还有另一种风险。
Ethereum is actually annual staking.
以太坊实际上是按年质押。
&gt;&gt; Oh I see. And most of it is being done
我懂了。而且大部分工作正在进行中。
via a few businesses like LADA which are
通过像LADA这样的少数几家企业
turning into short-term staking.
转为短期质押。
&gt;&gt; And so there's a duration mismatch that
因此，存在持续时间不匹配的问题。
has some elements of risk in. Sorry, go
其中包含一些风险因素。抱歉，请离开。
ahead.
前方。
&gt;&gt; I was going to say when do you get paid
我本来想问你什么时候领工资
the with the Ethereum staking you get
通过以太坊质押，您可以获得
paid every month or do you get paid on
是每月支付还是按周支付
the year?
年份？
&gt;&gt; I was getting paid monthly.
我按月领工资。
&gt;&gt; Monthly. Okay.
每月一次。好的。
&gt;&gt; What about pensions?
养老金情况如何？
&gt;&gt; Retirement.
退休。
&gt;&gt; Retirement. So in the UK we call it a
退休。所以在英国我们称之为
pension. And I think you guys call it a
养老金。我想你们管它叫……
401k.
401k。
&gt;&gt; Okay.
好的。
&gt;&gt; But over across the world, it's pretty
但放眼全球，情况相当不错。
much the same across the western world
西方世界的情况大致相同。
anyway.
反正。
&gt;&gt; If I'm 25 or 30 or whatever, should I
如果我25岁、30岁或者其他任何年龄，我应该……
should I be paying into my pension as a
我应该继续缴纳养老金吗？
way to generate to make myself wealthy
让自己致富的方法
someday?
总有一天？
&gt;&gt; Is that a smart idea?
这是个好主意吗？
&gt;&gt; I don't have a 401k. I don't have an
我没有401k退休账户。我没有
IRA. But the reason why people like
个人退休账户（IRA）。但人们喜欢的原因在于……
these accounts and why they can work for
这些账户以及它们为何能发挥作用
some people is because they are tax
有些人是因为要缴税才被扣税的。
deferred accounts. meaning I can put my
延期账户。这意味着我可以把我的
money in whether I pay taxes now or
无论我现在是否缴税，钱都会流入我的口袋。
later.
之后。
The money will then sit there, grow, and
这笔钱就会放在那里，不断增值，
I don't pay taxes until I pull my money
我提取资金之前不用缴税。
out.
出去。
But there's a couple problems. Problem
但这里存在一些问题。问题
number one is
第一名是
I have very little control where my
我对我的去向几乎没有任何控制权
money can be invested. Maybe this will
资金可以用于投资。也许这会
change. Uh the Trump administration has
改变。呃，特朗普政府有
passed a new executive order on 401ks to
通过了一项关于401(k)计划的新行政命令
change what you could potentially invest
改变你可能的投资方向
in 401ks, but that hasn't happened yet.
在 401k 计划中，但这种情况尚未发生。
you have very limited options. They're
你的选择非常有限。他们是
primarily just mutual funds and many of
主要就是共同基金和许多
them have a fee. I think Nerd Wallet
他们需要支付费用。我觉得 Nerd Wallet
said 92% of Americans don't know what
92%的美国人表示不知道什么
the 401k fees are. So, if you don't have
401k 的费用是。所以，如果你没有
know what your 401k fee is, this is your
了解你的401k费用是多少，这是你的
uh notice to go check what the expense
呃，请注意去查看费用是多少。
ratio is, and you should know that. So,
比例是这样的，你应该知道这一点。所以，
you have very limited options. You're
你的选择非常有限。你是
going to have to pay a fee, which means
需要支付一笔费用，这意味着
somebody on Wall Street is going to be
华尔街有人会……
paid forever until you retire. Number
直到退休为止，一直都在领薪。数字
two, I can't touch this money until I'm
第二，在我……之前，我不能动用这笔钱。
60 years old, 59 and a half. if I do, I
60岁，59岁半。如果我这样做，我
have to pay a 10% penalty.
需缴纳10%的罚款。
And number three, the whole discussion
第三，整个讨论
is you're doing this for tax benefits,
如果你这样做是为了获得税收优惠，
but kind of like we talked about
但就像我们之前讨论的那样
earlier, there's a lot of tax benefits
早些时候，有很多税收优惠。
that you can get outside of a 401k,
除了401k计划之外，你还可以获得这些。
which is why for me, I don't like it.
这就是为什么我不喜欢它的原因。
But I'm not everybody. For some people,
但我并不代表所有人。对某些人来说，
it can be a great place because your
这可能是一个很棒的地方，因为你
employer might say, "We're going to give
雇主可能会说：“我们将给予
you a 3% match." So, if you invest,
您将获得3%的匹配资金。”所以，如果您投资，
let's just say, $3,000 into your 401k
假设你往401k账户里存了3000美元。
and and they match it 100%. they might
而且他们100%都符合。他们或许
also just throw $3,000 into your 401k,
另外，还可以往你的401k账户里存入3000美元。
but you have the same risks and concerns
但你们也面临着同样的风险和担忧。
um along the way.
嗯，一路走来。
&gt;&gt; I don't think most people even know what
我认为大多数人甚至都不知道什么
a pension is to be honest. I think we
养老金就是诚实。我认为我们
pay into it, but we don't really know
投入其中，但我们并不真正了解
what's working. And I saw this really
哪些方法行之有效？我真的看到了这一点
interesting debate take place on X the
关于X的讨论很有趣
other day where someone was a guy was
前几天，有个男的在场。
saying in the UK, I've paid into my
在英国，我说过，我已经缴纳了我的税款。
pension my whole life. Um so I deserve
我这辈子都靠养老金过活。嗯，所以我值得
it and it'll be there when I'm ready.
它就在那里，等我准备好了就会在那里。
And then everyone underneath it was
然后，它下面的所有人都是
telling him that by the way it's not
顺便告诉他，那不是
like some piggy bank that you get to
就像你可以拥有的那种存钱罐
break open. The money you paid into a
打开。你投入的钱
pension was used to pay for the people
养老金被用来支付人民的开支。
that needed a pension when you were
当你需要养老金的时候
working.
在职的。
&gt;&gt; So you're talking about social security
所以你是在谈论社会保障
in the United States because as an
在美国，因为作为一个
employee in the United States,
美国雇员
&gt;&gt; you have to pay into social security. So
你必须缴纳社会保障金。所以
6.2% of your income. So you you have a
你收入的 6.2%。所以你有一个
lot of taxes. you're going to have to
税费很多。你必须……
pay income taxes on what you make. And
对你的收入缴纳所得税。和
then you have social security tax. So on
然后还有社会保障税。很快
your income, you're going to pay 6.2% of
你的收入中，你需要支付6.2%的税款。
that separately from your income tax,
这部分税款是单独计算的，与你的所得税无关。
but 6.2% into this social security fund.
但其中 6.2% 投入了社会保障基金。
And then your employer is also going to
然后你的雇主也会……
pay 6.2% into this fund.
将 6.2% 的资金投入该基金。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; This money in theory is supposed to grow
理论上，这笔钱应该会增长。
and compound. That way when you retire,
和化合物。这样，当你退休的时候，
you have this retirement fund that's
你有一笔退休基金，
going to pay you every single year. You
每年都会付你工资。你
don't get to choose. I mean, you can
没有选择权。我的意思是，你可以
choose when you pull it out, but you
你可以选择何时取出，但是你
don't get to do anything with it. The
你根本没机会用它做任何事。这
government's going to be in charge.
政府将负责此事。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; This is what is running out of money in
这就是资金即将耗尽的原因。
the United States today. Why? Because
今天的美国。为什么？因为
people that are in their 20s, 30s, and
20多岁、30多岁以及
40s that are paying into it today, it's
今天参与其中的40多岁人士，是
not paying for their retirement. It's
没有支付他们的退休金。它是
paying for the people who are retiring
为退休人员支付费用
today to pay for their social security
今天他们要缴纳社会保障金
benefits.
好处。
&gt;&gt; And that's what people don't understand.
这就是人们不理解的地方。
They think they're paying into a piggy
他们以为自己是在给猪圈交钱。
bank that they get to crack open and
他们可以打开的那家银行
that will pay for them as long as they
只要他们这样做，就能为他们支付费用。
live for the rest of their life. I was
余生都将如此度过。我当时
looking at the biggest misconceptions
探究最大的误解
around pensions. And the first one was
围绕养老金问题。第一个是
that my pension is guaranteed money for
我的养老金是有保障的。
the entirety of my life once I retire.
我退休后的全部生活。
&gt;&gt; Well, there there is some truth to that.
嗯，这话有一定的道理。
The part in the United States at least
至少在美国是这样。
that you are guaranteed what what the
你得到保证的是什么
what the wording is that you're going to
你要用的措辞是什么？
get the social security until you pass
领取社会保障金直到去世
away. But the part that they never tell
离开。但他们从未透露的那部分内容
you and there's no asterisk about this
你，这一点没有任何附加条件。
either is how much that value of the
要么是这个价值是多少
check will be. So here's what's going
检查将会进行。事情是这样的……
on. People are paying into the social
在。人们正在为社会福利付费
security fund thinking that they're
安全基金认为他们是
going to be able to fund their
将能够为他们提供资金
retirement. Every financial adviser
退休。每位财务顾问
historically has said that retirement is
从历史上看，退休是……
a three-legged stool. You have your
三脚凳。你有你的
401k, your your personal retirement. You
401k，你的个人退休账户。你
have your own personal savings and then
先拥有自己的个人储蓄，然后
you have social security. Well, you pay
你有社会保障金。嗯，你付钱
into social security by force because
因为被强制纳入社会保障体系
you don't get to opt out of it unless
除非你选择退出，否则你无权选择退出。
you are an investor. You don't have to
您是一位投资者。你不必
pay your social security income or
缴纳你的社会保障收入或
social security taxes on your investment
你的投资需要缴纳社会保障税
income. But you pay into this until you
收入。但你要为此付出代价，直到你
hit retirement age and then you get to
到了退休年龄，你就可以……
pull this money out. Well, the
把这笔钱取出来。嗯，
government is running out of social
政府的社会保障资源正在枯竭。
security money. But people misconrue
保证金。但人们误解了
that because they say, "Oh, that means
因为他们会说，“哦，那意味着
the government's no longer going to pay
政府将不再支付
social security." That's not true.
社会保障。” 这不属实。
They'll still pay it, but they'll just
他们还是会付钱，但他们只会……
print their way to pay it, which is what
他们通过印钞来支付，这就是……
you've been talking about. So great,
你一直在谈论的。太好了！
they they're giving you a bigger check.
他们会给你开出更大的支票。
The problem with that bigger check is
那张数额更大的支票的问题在于：
that bigger check can't buy you as much
更大的支票买不到那么多东西
stuff. So yeah, you're based off what
东西。所以，是的，你是根据什么来判断的
the United States government says,
美国政府表示：
assuming that they don't default, you're
假设他们不违约，你
going to get the social security check,
去领取社会保障金支票，
is just not going to be able to buy you
根本买不到你
as much as you thought before.
和你之前想的一样多。
&gt;&gt; The other big misconceptions are that
其他一些常见的误解是：
people think their employer is putting
人们认为他们的雇主正在投入
enough in to cover their full
足以覆盖他们的全部
retirement. They think it's the same as
退休。他们认为这和……是一样的
a savings account. They think they can
储蓄账户。他们认为他们可以
access it whenever they like. Um the
他们可以随时访问。嗯
government will cover them when it runs
政府会在运行期间承担他们的费用
out and I don't need to think about it
出去了，我不需要考虑这件事。
until I'm older. And lastly, my pension
直到我长大。最后，还有我的养老金
pot is taxfree. So the big shift that
大麻免税。所以，最大的转变是
happened around 20 years ago was a shift
大约20年前发生的一次转变
from what's known as defined
从所谓的定义来看
benefit to divine contribution.
受益于神圣的贡献。
So defined benefit used to work for Ford
所以，固定收益计划过去对福特公司来说是行之有效的。
or an American Airlines or whatever
或者美国航空公司之类的
company. You retired, you got 60% of
公司。你退休了，你得到了60%的
your final year salary forever.
你最后一年的薪水将永远有效。
Oh
哦
&gt;&gt; that was bankrupting all of these
那导致所有这些公司破产。
pension plans because people were living
因为人们都住在养老金计划里，所以才有了这些计划。
longer all the other stuff. And so they
比其他所有事情都长。于是他们
kind of changed it to define
某种程度上改变了它的定义
contribution. Basically, you get out
贡献。基本上，你逃出去了
what you put in plus the investment
你投入的加上投资
returns, but there's fees. Maybe you
有回报，但需支付手续费。或许你
didn't give it to a good manager. Maybe
没交给一个好经理。或许
you didn't know when they said, "Well,
你不知道他们什么时候说的，“好吧，
do you want to put it in bonds or
你想把它投资到债券上吗？
equities?" You like bonds and it didn't
股票？你喜欢债券，但它并没有。
grow as much or whatever it was. And in
长到原来的高度或者其他什么高度。并且
the end, you're just not sure that your
最后，你只是不确定你的
the average 401k in the United States
美国平均401k计划
for a baby boomer, I believe, is about
我认为，对于婴儿潮一代来说，大约是
$100,000.
10万美元。
&gt;&gt; What age? a baby boomer like 65.
多大了？像65岁左右的婴儿潮一代。
&gt;&gt; Yeah,
是的，
&gt;&gt; I think it's right now around 200,000.
我认为现在应该在 20 万左右。
&gt;&gt; Oh, 200. Okay, but it's not enough to
哦，200。好吧，但这还不够。
retire.
退休。
&gt;&gt; 200 is not enough to retire. There's 10
200美元不足以退休。有10个
years of 20 grand a year,
每年两万英镑，
&gt;&gt; right?
正确的？
&gt;&gt; So, there's so little money in the US
所以，美国现在钱很少。
pension system particularly um that
养老金制度，尤其是……
there is no hope for these people. And
这些人没有希望了。和
this whole video on this called the
这段关于此事的视频叫做
retirement crisis became a huge kind of
退休危机演变成一场巨大的危机
viral success years ago just explaining
几年前的病毒式成功只是解释一下
there is no way out of this for the
对于他们来说，这是没有出路的。
pensioners, the boomers or the
退休人员、婴儿潮一代或
millennials and everyone's going to have
千禧一代和所有人都会拥有
to change within this to figure this
在此基础上进行改变以解决这个问题
stuff out.
把东西拿出来。
&gt;&gt; I think you said it earlier today. You
我想你今天早些时候已经说过这话了。你
were talking about a Ponzi scheme here.
我们说的是庞氏骗局。
You have one but nobody wants to say
你有一个，但没人愿意说。
that. But everyone is paying in to keep
那。但每个人都在缴费以维持现状。
funding this thing but the only way it's
为这个项目筹集资金，但唯一的方法是……
running is because people are paying it
之所以会运营，是因为有人为此付费。
in. problem is there's not enough money
问题是钱不够。
coming in
进来
&gt;&gt; because
因为
&gt;&gt; because the remember the remember we
因为我们记得，我们记得
talked about at the beginning the
开头谈到的
demographics there's less and less young
人口结构方面，年轻人越来越少。
people there's less and less young
那里的人越来越少，年轻人也越来越少。
people because we're having less babies
因为生育率下降了，所以人们的生育率也降低了。
&gt;&gt; but there's tons of these retired people
但这类退休人员有很多。
so and this keeps going in perpetuity
所以，这种情况会永远持续下去。
because we're having babies so that's
因为我们要生孩子了，所以就是这样。
workers in 20 years time the babies now
20年后的工人，现在的婴儿
workers in 20 years time we can forward
20年后，我们可以向前迈进的工人
project this it doesn't stop so how the
这个项目不会停止，所以如何……
hell are we going to pay for this
我们到底要为此付出代价？
massive amount of baby boomers which is
数量庞大的婴儿潮一代，即
in the United States is 78 8 million of
美国有7880万
them, a largest cohort in history at the
他们，是历史上规模最大的一批学生。
time. We can't pay for them.
时间。我们付不起钱。
&gt;&gt; And this is where the proposals are to
这就是提案的由来……
tax your Bitcoin, the value of your
对你比特币征税，即你的比特币价值。
Bitcoin or tax the value of your assets
比特币或对您的资产价值征税
or tax your investment income.
或者对您的投资收益征税。
&gt;&gt; But the UK's got the same this whole
但英国也面临着同样的问题。
wealth that everybody's got the same
人人平等的财富
problem. Everybody
问题。大家
&gt;&gt; What do you think, Humphrey? In terms of
你觉得呢，汉弗莱？按照
retirement crisis,
退休危机
&gt;&gt; I think that so I have a different take
我也这么认为，所以我有不同的看法。
on Well, I think first of all, I think
嗯，首先，我认为
Jess Breed row you guys were talk and
杰西·布里德，你们当时在聊天。
you were talking about social security,
你刚才在谈论社会保障，
right? Yeah. But I I I have a different
正确的？是的。但我有不同的看法。
take on retirement altogether. I think
彻底退休。我认为
uh I think 401ks are good for the
嗯，我觉得401k计划对……有好处。
average person because it's a forced
对普通人来说，这是被迫的。
savings mechanism. A lot of people
储蓄机制。很多人
wouldn't contribute to a retirement
不会对退休生活做出贡献
account unless they the employer offered
除非雇主提供账户，否则他们不得向其提供账户。
it, right? And so the the whole match
对吧？所以整场比赛就是这样。
thing is a great thing for behavioral
这件事对行为学来说是一件好事
behavioral finance. It's like, okay, if
行为金融学。就好像，好吧，如果
I if I do this, I get some free money
如果我这样做，就能得到一些免费的钱。
from my employer and at least I'm saving
从雇主那里，至少我还能存点钱。
some money instead of nothing. You are
总比没有强。你是
working for that money. It's not really
靠自己的努力挣钱。其实并非如此
free. A 401k for anyone that doesn't
自由的。 401k计划适用于任何没有401k计划的人
understand is you agree to invest in a
理解就是你同意投资于
investment pot alongside your employer.
与雇主共同投资。
&gt;&gt; It is more like an individual retirement
它更像是个人退休计划
account that is awarded to you because
因以下原因授予您的帐户
you work for an employer. You have the
你为雇主工作。你有
option to invest within a 401k and that
可以选择在401k账户内进行投资，而且
401k is typically tax deferred
401k计划通常是延税的。
&gt;&gt; uh which means that you pay taxes on it
这意味着你要为此缴税。
later in life.
晚年时期。
&gt;&gt; And what's the difference between that
那两者之间有什么区别呢？
and a social security? A social security
还有社会保障金？社会保障
is a government program where you are
这是一个政府项目，你在这里
required to pay into it every paycheck
每次发工资都必须缴纳这笔款项。
that goes into this big pot and then
这些东西都放进这个大锅里，然后
when you do retire the government will
当你退休时，政府会
send you a social security check every
每月给你寄一张社保支票
month.
月。
&gt;&gt; Okay.
好的。
&gt;&gt; But I I still think that there are
但我仍然认为存在
plenty of ways to retire and retire with
退休和退休的方式有很多种。
some sort of freedom. Retire early. Have
某种形式的自由。提前退休。有
you heard of Coastfire before?
你之前听说过Coastfire吗？
&gt;&gt; No. Coastfire is another newer thing
不，Coastfire是另一个比较新的事物。
that's uh that's kind of on Reddit, but
那好像是在Reddit上看到的，不过
it's a variation of financial
它是金融的一种变体。
independence retire early and it's
独立自主，提前退休，而且是
essentially you get your nest egg to a
基本上，你可以把你的养老金存到……
point where you don't have to invest any
无需投资的点
dollar into it after that, but because
之后投入了一美元，但是因为
you get it to let's say a certain number
你把它弄到比如说某个特定的数字。
and that number is usually pretty
而且这个数字通常相当
reasonable. The investment returns if
合理的。投资回报
you're invested into the S&amp;P 500 will
你投资了标普500指数。
get you to a full retirement by the time
到那时，你就能完全退休了。
you're able to retire at 65. So, it
你可以65岁退休。所以，
doesn't mean you retire early
这并不意味着你要提前退休。
completely, but it means that if you get
完全如此，但这意味着如果你得到
to your Coastfire number, which is what
发送到您的 Coastfire 号码，也就是
it's called, maybe you have more freedom
它叫做，或许你拥有更多自由
of choice in what you're working on. So,
对你正在从事的工作拥有选择权。所以，
like maybe you don't have to work for
比如，你可能不必为……工作
the employer that you absolutely hate.
你最讨厌的老板。
You can maybe go do something that's a
你或许可以去做一些……
little bit more suited to your
更适合你
lifestyle. You're still working, but
生活方式。你还在工作，但是
you're not working to save for
你工作不是为了攒钱
retirement anymore because you hit that
不再退休了，因为你达到了那个目标。
coastfire number. So, for example, at
海岸火灾编号。例如，在
the age of 35, I think the coastfire
35岁，我想是海岸火灾
number is like $150,000.
数字大概是15万美元。
If you can hit 150k by 35, if you have
如果你能在35岁之前达到15万，如果你有
30 years of investment returns at 8%,
30 年投资回报率为 8%，
you'll have $1.5 million by the time you
到那时，你将拥有150万美元。
retire, which is a little bit more
退休，这稍微多一点。
palatable for people that are having a
适合正在经历……的人
hard time wrapping their heads around,
他们很难理解，
am I ever going to retire. They're not
我到底什么时候才能退休？他们不是
going to retire in that they're not
他们即将退休，但他们并非如此。
going to be kicking up their feet on the
他们会翘起二郎腿
sand beaches of Aruba, but you're still
阿鲁巴的沙滩，但你仍然
going to be doing something. And I I
准备做点什么。而我
personally think if I was retired, I'd
我个人认为，如果我退休了，我会……
be so bored out of my mind doing
无聊到发疯
nothing, right? So, I'd like to work on
什么也没有，对吧？所以，我想从事以下工作：
something. The idea is you just don't
某物。我的意思是，你根本不需要
have to work for maybe the job you hate
你可能不得不为了自己讨厌的工作而努力。
or something like that.
或者类似的事情。
&gt;&gt; So if I hit the $150,000 in savings and
所以如果我能存下15万美元，
I put it into the S&amp;P 500 and get the
我把它投入标普500指数，然后……
&gt;&gt; 8% return.
8%的回报率。
&gt;&gt; 8% return by the age of 65 I'll have 1
到65岁时，如果收益率为8%，我将拥有1个。
something million.
几百万。
&gt;&gt; 1.59. Yeah.
1.59。是的。
&gt;&gt; What's that worth then?
那它值多少钱？
&gt;&gt; That's true. There that is another part
这是真的。那还有另一部分
of the equation is with inflation what
等式中包含通货膨胀的是什么？
is it going to be worth?
值得吗？
&gt;&gt; And is this what you're trying to do?
这就是你想要做的吗？
Cuz I remember an hour ago you said I'm
因为我记得一个小时前你说我是
just trying to retire early words to
只是想早点退休，说几句。
that effect.
这种效果。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Yeah, I mean I'd like to be
是的。是的，我的意思是，我希望如此。
Coastfire and uh Coastfire is, you know,
Coastfire，呃，Coastfire就是，你知道的，
however you would like to define it.
无论你怎么定义它。
But, you know, I already think I'm I'm
但是，你知道，我已经觉得我……
pretty close or if not, I've already
差不多了，或者如果不是，我已经……
reached it, which is like I get to work
达到了，就像我终于可以工作了。
on the things that I love and I I think
关于我喜欢的事物，我认为
that my retirement nest egg will
我的退休储蓄将会
eventually grow to a point where by the
最终发展到一定程度，到那时
time I hit 60, 65, I'll be able to
等我到了60岁、65岁，我就能……
coast. Jill,
海岸。吉尔，
&gt;&gt; did you create a number? Do the math on
你创建了一个号码吗？计算一下
what you'd need to get to?
你需要到达哪里？
&gt;&gt; Yes.
是的。
&gt;&gt; Okay.
好的。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. So you can project out your
是的。所以你可以把你的
expenses of what you think your expenses
你认为你的开支是多少
are going to be on an annual basis and
将会按年度进行，
then kind of work backwards to that
然后反过来推导。
number.
数字。
&gt;&gt; Okay.
好的。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; A lot of math involved, but you kind of
涉及到很多数学知识，但你大概……
have to do
必须这样做
&gt;&gt; tragedy or something.
悲剧之类的。
&gt;&gt; Retirement crisis. Hm. That's
退休危机。嗯。那是
concerning.
有关。
&gt;&gt; That's concerning. So your approach is
这令人担忧。所以你的方法
to do the Coastfire thing. My approach
去做Coastfire那件事。我的方法
is let's stay disciplined, consistent
让我们保持自律和坚持。
with our savings and investing and
我们的储蓄和投资
actually get to a place where retirement
真正达到退休的境界
might be possible. I
有可能。我
&gt;&gt; I love that idea and that's the same as
我喜欢这个想法，这和……是一样的。
when I started with the manifesting your
当我开始显化你的
your destiny. You say, "Well, I need
你的命运。你说：“嗯，我需要
this goal. How do I do it? We do this
这个目标。我该怎么做？我们这样做
and grow it via investments, right? It's
然后通过投资实现增长，对吧？它是
it's brilliant to do that
这样做真是太棒了。
&gt;&gt; and then you can take more risk." If you
然后你就可以承担更大的风险了。”如果你
isolate that and say, "Well, any capital
把这一点单独拿出来说：“嗯，任何资本
I build now, I can do whatever I want."
现在我可以自由发挥，想做什么都可以。
&gt;&gt; Um, that was the same idea that I had
嗯，我的想法跟你一样。
with the home. It's exact. It's like
和家。完全正确。就像
I've derisked my life now. I can take
我现在已经拿自己的生命冒险了。我可以接受
risk. And that's a really nice thing to
风险。那真是一件好事。
do.
做。
&gt;&gt; And I love the way that you do it by
我喜欢你这样做的方式。
saying, well, my future self wants this.
他说，嗯，未来的我想要这个。
&gt;&gt; For me to do that, I need to do this now
为了做到这一点，我现在需要这样做。
and then it should take care of that.
然后它应该就能解决这个问题了。
Now,
现在，
&gt;&gt; it's all there's always imagine, but
这就是我们一直想象的一切，但是……
yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; And then you have extra dollars to do
然后你还有多余的钱可以做其他事。
whatever you want with, right? So,
你想用什么都行，对吧？所以，
&gt;&gt; I also love that you've been disciplined
我也很欣赏你的自律精神。
on like what you like and what you know.
喜欢你所喜欢的和你所了解的。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. And uh I appreciate that. Thank
是的。我很感激。感谢
you.
你。
&gt;&gt; Because you said I think 90% are in
因为你说我认为90%的人都在
index funds and ETFs.
指数基金和ETF。
&gt;&gt; That's what I would recommend for
这就是我推荐的做法。
people. Sorry. For me personally, I'm
人们。对不起。就我个人而言，我是
like 50 60% index funds,
例如50%到60%的指数基金，
&gt;&gt; but still that's that's pretty high and
但即便如此，这个数字仍然相当高。
and not having that, you know, shiny
而且没有那种闪亮的感觉，你知道，就是那种闪亮的感觉。
object syndrome or whatever you want to
客体综合症，或者你想叫它什么都行。
call it. I mean that that may
就这么叫它。我的意思是，那可能
everybody here, but but whatever it
这里每个人都在，但是不管怎样
might be um to to to be disciplined. I
或许需要接受纪律约束。我
think that's such a valuable trait. And
我认为这是一个非常宝贵的品质。和
you know, you talked about the scarcity
你知道，你谈到了稀缺性
mindset. I think that's also a
心态。我认为这也是一个
discipline mindset that you have that.
你具备那种自律的心态。
So, I I would I would reframe that and I
所以，我会重新表述一下，而且
think you've done an excellent job.
我认为你做得非常出色。
&gt;&gt; I think personal finance is personal.
我认为个人理财是个人的事情。
&gt;&gt; All right, guys. Gonna go get Steve. The
好了，各位。我去叫史蒂夫。这
guest is here. Ready?
客人已到。准备好？
&gt;&gt; Come in.
进来。
&gt;&gt; Oh my god. Steve,
我的天啊。史蒂夫，
&gt;&gt; what are you doing?
你在干什么？
&gt;&gt; This is uh Bontage face mask. It's good
这是 Bontage 面膜。很好
for blemishes, wrinkles, uh clears up
针对瑕疵、皱纹，呃，清除
the skin. It's red light. Have you not
皮肤。是红灯。难道你没有
used it before?
以前用过吗？
&gt;&gt; No.
不。
&gt;&gt; I tried this before. It's um it's really
我之前试过。嗯，真的
really good.
非常好。
shines red light on your face which
它会用红光照射你的脸部，
helps increase and boost collagen
有助于增加和促进胶原蛋白生成。
production. Actually found it out
生产。实际上已经找到了
because of the misses seen her wearing
因为小姐们看到她穿着
it. She terrified me a couple of nights
它。她吓了我好几个晚上。
in a row. Um I thought it was to scare
连续。嗯，我以为是为了吓唬人。
people with but actually it's really
人们有这种想法，但实际上这真的
really good for your skin. So they are a
对皮肤真的很好。所以他们是
sponsor of the podcast and uh I've been
我是播客的赞助商，嗯，我一直……
using it every day for about a year and
每天使用，大约用了一年。
a half now.
现在是半个月了。
&gt;&gt; Wow.
哇。
&gt;&gt; Well, I'm glowing. Great.
我容光焕发。伟大的。
&gt;&gt; Yes. And Boncharge ships worldwide with
是的。 Boncharge 提供全球配送服务。
easy returns and a year-long warranty on
轻松退货和一年保修
all of their products. So, visit
他们的所有产品。所以，请访问
bondcharge.com/diary
bondcharge.com/diary
for 25% off on any product sitewide, but
全场任意商品享25%折扣，但是
you have to order through that link.
你必须通过那个链接下单。
That's boncharge.com/diary
那是 boncharge.com/diary
with code diary. Make sure you keep what
附代码日志。请务必保留好
I'm about to say to yourself. I'm
我正要对你说。我是
inviting 10,000 of you to come even
邀请你们中的10000人前来参加
deeper into the diary of a CEO. Welcome
深入了解一位CEO的日记。欢迎
to my inner circle. This is a brand new
致我的核心圈子。这是全新的
private community that I'm launching to
我即将推出的私人社区
the world. We have so many incredible
世界。我们有很多令人惊叹的
things that happen that you are never
那些你永远不会经历的事情
shown. We have the briefs that are on my
已显示。我们有我身上穿的那几件内裤。
iPad when I'm recording the
我用iPad录音的时候
conversation. We have clips we've never
对话。我们有一些从未播放过的片段
released. We have behind the-scenes
已发布。我们有幕后花絮
conversations with the guests and also
与客人的交谈以及
the episodes that we've never ever
我们从未见过的那些剧集
released and so much more. In the
已发布，还有更多精彩内容。在
circle, you'll have direct access to me.
圈内人可以直接联系到我。
You can tell us what you want this show
你可以告诉我们你希望这个节目呈现什么内容
to be, who you want us to interview, and
你想让我们采访谁？
the types of conversations you would
你会进行的对话类型
love us to have. But remember, for now,
爱我们拥有。但请记住，就目前而言，
we're only inviting the first 10,000
我们只邀请前10000名。
people that join before it closes. So if
在截止日期前加入的人。所以如果
you want to join our private close
你想加入我们的私人封闭式社区吗？
community, head to the link in the
社区中，请点击链接。
description below or go to
下方有详细说明，或前往
daccircle.com.
daccircle.com。
I will speak to you there. On that point
我会在那里和你谈谈。关于这一点
of discipline, Humphrey, I have seen a
汉弗莱，我见过纪律方面的……
couple of videos from you where you talk
你发的几个视频，你在里面谈到……
about the things that you stopped
关于你停止的那些事
spending money on. And there is a
花钱的地方。而且还有
narrative that says, you know, in order
叙述方式是，你知道，为了
to get rich or to save uh to get to
致富或储蓄，呃，达到
where you want to go with your financial
你希望你的财务状况达到什么目标？
goals, you should not have the Starbucks
目标，你不应该去星巴克
coffee.
咖啡。
&gt;&gt; Sure.
当然。
&gt;&gt; You should not do these things. What
你不应该做这些事。什么
what did you stop spending money on and
你停止在哪些方面花钱了？
what's your framework there? So, I
你们的框架是什么？所以，我
looked at I took a look at my expenses
我查看了一下我的开支。
from 2014 and onward and just kind of
从2014年起，就一直这样
like saw the differences in how my
就像看到了我的方式的不同之处
spending habits have changed. The first
消费习惯发生了改变。第一个
thing I stopped spending money on are
我不再花钱买的东西是
Airbnbs. So, Airbnbs used to be a great
爱彼迎房源。所以，Airbnb曾经是一个很棒的
value. They used to be a unique
价值。他们曾经是独一无二的
experience, but these days they're all
经验，但如今他们都是
kind of commercialized. And I feel like
有点商业化了。我觉得
with the cleaning fees and all these
包括清洁费和所有这些费用
fees, you end up paying more for less
各种费用，最终你花更多的钱却买到更少的东西。
convenience as a hotel. So, that's
便利程度堪比酒店。就是这样。
number one. I stopped buying food in
第一。我停止在超市购买食物。
bulk. I know that sounds kind of random,
大部分。我知道这听起来有点莫名其妙，
but uh I'm a single guy. Sometimes I I
但是，呃，我是个单身汉。有时我
get two gallons of milk and I can't
我要买两加仑牛奶，但我买不起。
finish it, right? So, I'm pouring milk
完成了，对吧？所以，我正在倒牛奶
down the drain or I'm buying 48 eggs at
要么扔进下水道，要么我就去买48个鸡蛋。
a time from Costco and I'm just like,
我从Costco买了一些东西，当时我就想，
dude, like I I I mean, I like the gym,
兄弟，我是说，我喜欢健身房。
but I can't eat 48 eggs in like 2 weeks
但我不可能在两周内吃掉48个鸡蛋。
or what whatever that that time is,
或者说，不管那段时间是什么情况。
right? So, that's that's another. And
正确的？所以，这是另一个问题。和
then, um, another thing I did was I
然后，嗯，我做的另一件事是……
started to switch my car insurance
开始更换我的汽车保险
because I moved into San Francisco, the
因为我搬到了旧金山，
city, I'm driving less. So, I used to
在城里，我开车少了。所以，我过去常常
drive 15,000 mi a year. I drive 3,000 mi
每年行驶 15,000 英里。我开车行驶了3000英里
a year now. And just by calling my car
已经一年了。只需给我的车打个电话就行了
insurance, I was able to save like 40
保险方面，我大概省了40美元。
bucks a month just because my driving
因为我开车，一个月就能赚几块钱
requirements are much lower. So those
要求低得多。所以那些
are like
就像
&gt;&gt; Explain that.
请解释一下。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. So, you know, a car a car
是的。所以，你知道，一辆车，一辆车
insurance rates are dependent on how
保险费率取决于……
much you drive. And if you drive less
你开车很多。如果你开车少一些
and you you move to a city, then your
然后你搬到一个城市，然后你的
rates should come down. But I think some
利率应该下降。但我认为有些
people are a little bit too loyal to
人们对……有点过于忠诚了。
their providers. They're not willing to
他们的供应商。他们不愿意
compare rates because it it's painful.
比较价格很麻烦。
You don't really want to do it. It takes
你其实并不想做这件事。它需要
time. Uh, but I think doing that,
时间。呃，但我认为那样做，
spending an hour calling your insurance
花一个小时打电话给你的保险公司
provider, looking at different insurance
保险公司，正在考虑不同的保险方案
providers, not just for cars, but for
供应商，不仅限于汽车供应商，还包括
homes, too, you can save a lot of money
同样，买房也能省很多钱。
because insurance is kind of
因为保险有点像……
commoditized. So, it's like you're going
商品化。所以，就好像你要去
to get coverage from many different
获得来自多个不同来源的报道
providers. You might as well put them
供应商。你最好还是把它们放进去。
kind of in a bidding war for your
有点像是在竞价争夺你
business.
商业。
&gt;&gt; I used to work selling car insurance,
我以前从事汽车保险销售工作。
you know, I used to it was one of my
你知道，我以前经常这样做，那是我……
telly sales jobs that
电视销售工作
&gt;&gt; Yeah. And there was interestingly, I
是的。而且有趣的是，我
don't think people know this, but as I
我觉得大家可能不知道这一点，但是……
sat there in the the car insurance call
坐在那里接听汽车保险电话
center, there's this bar on the screen
屏幕中央有一条横条
that I can move in either direction to
我可以朝任一方向移动
basically give you a discount
基本上就是给你打折
&gt;&gt; based on how the sale is going. So, if I
根据销售情况而定。所以，如果我
really think I'm going to lose your
我真的觉得我会失去你
sale, all I do is slide the bar to the
出售时，我所做的就是将滑块滑到……
left and it brings your your upfront
向左，它会带你到你的前面
payment down and your monthly payment
首付金额和月供金额
down. But if I thought this sale was
向下。但如果我认为这次促销是
easy, I could bring the bar up in terms
很简单，我可以提高标准。
of the price I quote you and give you
我给你报的价格就是我给你的价格。
breakdown insurance and all these other
故障保险以及所有其他保险
upsells. And so I don't think people
追加销售。所以我觉得人们不会这么做。
realize how negotiable all of their
意识到他们所有的事情都是可以商量的。
insuranceances are, even their their
保险，甚至他们的
phone insurance and all these other
手机保险以及所有这些其他保险
things. And sometimes you don't figure
事物。有时候你根本想不到
out until you you say you're going to
直到你说你要……为止
quit and then suddenly they give you
辞职，然后突然他们就给你
some great offer where they're going to
他们即将推出一些很棒的优惠活动
give you 50% off.
给你五折优惠。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. And the other way of approaching
是的。另一种方法是
it is I never really sold for cost. I
我从来没真正按成本价卖过东西。我
sold for income.
出售以获取收入。
&gt;&gt; Okay.
好的。
&gt;&gt; And that is saying that is saying okay
也就是说，也就是说，好的
your lifestyle as long as you're not
只要你不是，你的生活方式就保持不变。
being ridiculous, right? It's like
是不是很荒谬？就像
&gt;&gt; do I really want to not go to a go to a
我真的不想不去吗？
restaurant or get that Uber Eats or
去餐厅吃饭，或者叫 Uber Eats 外卖。
whatever.
任何。
&gt;&gt; I understand. Yeah.
我明白。是的。
&gt;&gt; Because that's penalizing yourself and
因为那样就等于惩罚自己。
that's not a nice thing to do always,
这样做并不总是好事。
right? It takes a lot of discipline and
正确的？这需要很强的自律性，而且
discipline is hard. But if you've got an
自律很难。但如果你有一个
equal and opposite amount of discipline
同等程度的相反纪律
in solving for income,
在求解收入问题时，
you actually move your lifestyle further
你实际上进一步提升了你的生活方式。
ahead. So, you know, the rise of I mean,
前方。所以，你知道，我的意思是，
I do three, four jobs. You do three,
我同时做三四份工作。你做三个，
four, we all do lots of different things
第四，我们都做很多不同的事情
now. You do as well. We all got
现在。你也一样。我们都得到了
different income streams. You're almost
不同的收入来源。你快要……
better off to spend your energy thinking
最好把精力花在思考上
about how do I increase my income stream
关于如何增加我的收入来源
than your cost basis. At a certain
比你的成本基础还要高。在某个时候
point, we agree like Steven's friend who
这一点，我们同意史蒂文的朋友的观点，他
sent him the message, he needs to
给他发了信息，他需要
desperately rescue his cost base.
拼命挽救他的成本基础。
&gt;&gt; Um, but generally, if you're looking at
嗯，但一般来说，如果你正在查看
a life plan,
人生规划
&gt;&gt; you'll get to your coast fire or
你会到达海岸火灾现场或
whatever it's called
不管它叫什么
&gt;&gt; quicker by solving for income than you
通过求解收入来更快地解决问题
will for cost.
费用自理。
&gt;&gt; I just think lowering fruit is solving
我认为降低水果价格就能解决问题。
for expenses, which is like everyone can
用于开支，就像每个人都可以做的那样
cut back a little bit, but everyone
稍微减少一点，但每个人
can't just like say, "I'm going to make
不能就这么简单地说，“我要去做……”
2x more tomorrow." That's kind of a
明天翻倍。”这有点像……
harder problem. And I think if you want
更难的问题。而且我觉得如果你想
&gt;&gt; well you just trade off your time
你只需要交换时间就行了。
because you I mean you can if you're in
因为你，我的意思是，如果你在的话，你就可以。
a lower earning job you can drive an
一份收入较低的工作，你可以开车
Uber and earn extra money or you can do
你可以通过优步赚取额外收入，或者你可以……
a bar.
酒吧。
&gt;&gt; I see what you're saying. Yeah.
我明白你的意思了。是的。
&gt;&gt; It's like multiple revenue streams is
这就像拥有多种收入来源一样。
now the way the world works because the
现在世界就是这样运转的，因为
cost of living has become so expensive
生活成本变得如此之高。
&gt;&gt; that everyone's having to do multiple
每个人都必须做多件事
jobs but with technology we can actually
工作，但借助科技，我们实际上可以
do it much easier. I Trey's point as
这样做更容易些。我同意 Trey 的观点
well though, you can get a 30% pay rise
不过，你可以获得 30% 的加薪。
today just by maybe bringing a pack
今天或许只需要带上一个背包
lunch or
午餐或
&gt;&gt; sure
当然
&gt;&gt; walking somewhere or whatever else and
步行前往某个地方或其他什么地方
it's probably harder to get a 30% pay
拿到 30% 的加薪可能更难。
rise. Not sure about that.
上升。我不太确定。
&gt;&gt; It depends. I think it depends on which
这取决于。我认为这取决于哪个
stage of life you're in because now if
你现在所处的生命阶段，因为如果
you just stick with a lunch,
你只要吃顿午饭就行了。
&gt;&gt; if you're on the lunch example, packing
以午餐为例，打包午餐。
lunch costs time and depending on how
午餐需要花费时间，而且取决于……
much your time is worth,
你的时间价值几何？
&gt;&gt; that one hour of time could be $20, it
那一个小时的时间可能价值20美元，
could be $2,000. And I think that's that
可能是2000美元。我想就是这样。
key difference. And and I think there's
主要区别。而且我认为还有
&gt;&gt; definitely times and places you got to
当然，你肯定在某些时间和地点……
cut. I fully agree with you on that. But
切。我完全同意你的看法。但
I think at a certain stage, look, I'm I
我认为在某个阶段，你看，我
have still cheap with my money in
我仍然很节俭，我的钱花得值。
multiple places. Uh but I have on when
多个地点。呃，但我有……
it comes to time. So our office is in
时机到了。所以我们的办公室位于
downtown Detroit and my commute there
底特律市中心以及我到那里的通勤路线
45 minutes and but I don't drive. What I
45分钟，但我不会开车。我
do is I get driven there. U and the
我只需要被开车送过去就行了。 U 和
reason why I do that is because I can
我这样做的原因是因为我可以
sit in the back seat and work. And one
坐在后座工作。还有一个
of the things that you know we publish
你知道我们发布的内容
daily financial news. So sometimes
每日财经新闻。所以有时候
something will be happening in the with
在……中将会发生一些事情。
our market briefs where oh this is
我们的市场简报，哦，这是
important and if I'm driving I don't
很重要，如果我开车的话，我就不开车了。
want to be texting and driving. So
想边开车边发短信。所以
instead I pay for an Uber or whatever
相反，我会花钱叫优步或其他交通工具。
and I go that 45 minutes there 45
我在那里待了45分钟。
minutes back and it's money out of my
几分钟前，我的钱就没了。
account every single day but I get back
每天都会收到账户，但我又回来了
an hour and a half of my time which is
占用我一个半小时的时间
worth way more than whatever I'm paying
绝对物超所值，远超我支付的价格。
in my driver fees. So I I think it
包含在我收取的司机费用里。所以我觉得
depends on where you are in the stage of
取决于你所处的阶段
life because I wouldn't do that if this
因为如果这样，我就不会那样做了。
was way before.
很久以前就发生了。
&gt;&gt; What is the biggest This is an open
这是最大的一个开放
question to everybody. What do you think
问大家这个问题。你怎么认为
the biggest money mistake the average
最大的理财错误是平均水平
person makes is?
这个人做的是什么？
&gt;&gt; They spend all your money. The the two
他们会花光你的钱。这两个
S's you you're spending all your money
你把所有的钱都花光了
&gt;&gt; and if you get past that then you're
如果你能克服这一点，那么你就是
saving all of your money.
把所有的钱都存起来。
&gt;&gt; Both of them are mistakes.
这两个都是错误。
&gt;&gt; So just having your money sat in a bank
所以，就让钱放在银行里吧。
account doing nothing,
账户没有任何活动，
&gt;&gt; you're becoming poorer every single day.
你每天都在变得更穷。
&gt;&gt; I don't think most people know this.
我认为大多数人都不知道这一点。
I've got a friend who's
我有个朋友是
steadily compounded his his bank balance
他的银行存款稳步增长。
over time. And I remember asking him, I
随着时间的推移。我记得我问过他，我
like, "How much money do you now have in
例如，“你现在有多少钱？”
your bank account?" He's taken a really
你的银行账户？”他真的
slow approach over time. He runs a
循序渐进的方法。他经营一家
business as a freelancer. And he goes,
以自由职业者的身份开展业务。然后他就走了，
"I think probably about a million
我想大概有一百万左右吧
dollars." And I was like, "It's just sat
美元。” 我当时想，“它就这么放着呢。”
in your bank account." He was like,
在你的银行账户里。”他当时说，
"Yeah." And because he's scared, like
“是的。”因为他害怕，就像
he's scared. He doesn't know what to do
他很害怕。他不知道该怎么办
with it. So he thinks just putting it in
和它一起。所以他认为只要把它放进去就行了。
the bank account is the safest possible
银行账户是最安全的选择。
thing to do.
要做的事。
&gt;&gt; Well, it's a guaranteed loss. uh if your
嗯，这肯定会亏。呃，如果你的
if your bank account the average bank
如果你的银行账户是平均水平的银行
account in the United States today not
今天在美国没有账户
the high yield accounts but the average
高收益账户，但平均水平
account is paying
账户正在付款
&gt;&gt; 0.1%
0.1%
0.5% I don't know something something
0.5% 我不知道一些事情
super low if we just say inflation is
如果我们简单地说通货膨胀率是极低的，那就是
3%. Meaning the the the cost you have to
3%。这意味着你必须付出的代价
spend out of the bank account to buy
从银行账户里花钱购买
something is going up by 3% and that's
某物上涨了3%，就是这样。
the reported number. It's not the the
报告的数字。不是那个
real inflation that many people feel.
许多人都能感受到真正的通货膨胀。
Well that means there's a net loss of 2
这意味着净亏损为 2
and a.5% on that. So, if I have a
再加上0.5%。所以，如果我有一个
million dollars there, that's $25,000 of
那里有100万美元，那就是25000美元。
lost buying power.
购买力下降。
&gt;&gt; Ro, do you think companies, because a
Ro，你认为公司会因为……
lot of my audience are companies,
我的听众中有很多是公司，
whether they're, you know, one person
不管他们是，你知道，一个人
companies or big companies, do you think
你认为公司还是大公司？
they should be putting their money that
他们应该把钱投在那里。
they have sat in their account into
他们已经登录了自己的账户
Bitcoin?
比特币？
&gt;&gt; In essence, if you're Microsoft, they
本质上，如果你是微软，他们
have huge cash piles. What does
拥有巨额现金储备。什么
Microsoft buy with their cash?
微软是用自有资金收购的吗？
really they buy
他们真的买了
some investment stuff but it's generally
一些投资方面的内容，但总体来说
cashbased
现金
and then they may buy another company or
然后他们可能会收购另一家公司，或者
they may buy real estate data centers
他们可能会购买房地产数据中心
let's say or they may buy their own
比如说，或者他们可能会自己购买。
shares back all of those three things
股票支持这三件事
that they buy are driven by the
他们的购买行为受以下因素驱动：
debasement of currency and they get more
货币贬值，他们反而获得更多
expensive every year and they're holding
每年都很贵，而且他们还在坚持
a cash return of three and a half%. So
现金回报率为3.5%。所以
it's stupid what they're doing because
他们这样做很愚蠢，因为
actually all your shareholder cash is
实际上，你所有的股东资金都是
not buying the equivalent of the actual
不购买等同于实际的
things that drive the value of the
驱动价值的因素
company.
公司。
&gt;&gt; What about small companies? What if
那么小公司呢？如果什么
there's people listening now that have
现在有人在听，他们有
companies where they've got a million 2
那些拥有百万家公司的2
million in the in the bank? They
银行里有100万美元存款？他们
probably don't need it all for cash flow
可能不需要全部用于现金流
reasons.
原因。
&gt;&gt; And so I do think that investing versus
所以我认为投资与……
saving is misunderstood to go back to
储蓄被误解为回到过去
your original question. I think
你最初的问题。我认为
investing
投资
is much more important. I made the
重要得多。我做了
mistake of being a saver when I was
我犯了个错误，当时我是个储蓄者
young because you know that the fear
年轻是因为你知道那种恐惧
that you know all of that stuff meant I
你知道所有这些事情的意思是……
was super riskaverse and I was an
我当时非常厌恶风险，而且我是一个
investment banker. I was investing but I
投资银行家。我当时在投资，但是
didn't so I made money from being in
没成功，所以我靠待在……赚了钱。
that industry. So I'm I'm just going to
那个行业。所以，我这就去
hoard cash. I did worse for doing that
囤积现金。我那样做后果更严重。
and then once we saw the banking system
然后，当我们了解了银行系统之后，就……
fail I'm like I'm not doing this
失败了，我感觉自己做不到。
anymore. I'm going to take control of my
不再是了。我要掌控我的
own finances. So the same is true of a
自有财务。所以，对于a来说，情况也是如此。
business. that they're generating cash.
商业。它们正在创造现金流。
They shouldn't be sitting on a massively
他们不应该坐在一个巨大的……
large amount of cash, but some liquid
大量现金，但部分流动资金
investments, I think, massively help
我认为投资有很大的帮助
because you're going to make your cash
因为你要赚钱。
grow for you and your shareholders. Um,
为您和您的股东创造增长。嗯，
and that's important, but but don't let
这很重要，但是，不要让
go of your liquidity because when you
动用你的流动资金，因为当你
really need it and you don't have cash,
你真的很需要它，但你没有现金。
that's the worst thing in the world,
那是世界上最糟糕的事。
particularly when you've saved the
尤其是当你已经保存了
money.
钱。
&gt;&gt; So, in your business bank account for
所以，在您的企业银行账户中
Real Vision, do you put some of the
Real Vision，你们放了一些吗？
&gt;&gt; the money into crypto?
把钱换成加密货币？
&gt;&gt; It depends. A lot of it gets reinvested
这取决于。其中很多都会被再投资。
for growth within the company. So you're
为公司内部发展做准备。所以你是
making a decision is does how's your
做出决定就是你的感受。
capital going to grow? Is it going to
资本会增长吗？它会……
grow grow your share price via
通过以下方式提高您的股价
reinvesting in the business or is it
是将资金再投资于企业，还是另有其他用途？
better to use the savings pool and buy
最好利用储蓄池购买
other investments and diversify away?
转向其他投资，分散投资风险？
That really depends on your business
这真的取决于你的业务。
where it is in the growth cycle. But if
它所处的生长周期阶段。但是如果
you're like a a cashg generating regular
你就像一个定期产生现金的常客
non-growth style business
非增长型企业
then you're going to be generating cash.
这样你就能赚钱了。
You might have taken some de dividends
你可能已经领取了一些股息。
out and bought a house and done all that
出去买了房子，做了所有那些事。
thing. Yeah, there's no reason not to do
事物。是的，没有理由不这样做。
some relatively conservative investment
一些相对保守的投资
strategy.
战略。
&gt;&gt; Humphrey, you worked with lots of rich
汉弗莱，你曾与许多富有的人共事。
people advising them.
给他们提供建议的人。
&gt;&gt; What is it that rich people know that
富人究竟懂得什么？
the average person doesn't know as it
普通人并不了解这一点。
relates to money? Because there are
和钱有关吗？因为有
money games that you discover when you
当你发现那些金钱游戏时
get to see behind the curtain. What is
有机会一窥幕后真相。什么是
it that they're doing with their money
那就是他们如何支配自己的钱。
that the average person isn't aware of
普通人并不了解
or isn't able to do with their money?
或者他们无法妥善管理自己的钱？
&gt;&gt; Rich people are typically more
富人通常更
disciplined. They're they're typically
有纪律的。它们通常是
checking their bank account every day,
他们每天都查看银行账户，
right? They they're doing the little
正确的？他们正在做一些小事
things that compound into huge results
累积起来会产生巨大结果的因素
at the end of 10 or 20 years and they're
10年或20年后，他们……
they're thinking in decades, not just
他们考虑的是几十年，而不仅仅是
what am I going to do this week, right?
我这周要做什么呢？对吧？
They're they're choosing investment
他们正在选择投资
choices for themselves in 10 years, 20
10年后，20年后，他们为自己做出的选择
years from now instead of choosing
多年以后，而不是选择
sports betting on on the football match
足球比赛的体育博彩
for 1,000, you know, uh that night
你知道，那天晚上，1000美元。
because they know that their,000 working
因为他们知道他们有 1000 名员工
for them today will be worth, you know,
对他们来说，今天的一切都将是值得的，你知道的。
10,000, 20,000 in 10 or 20 years. So,
10年或20年内达到1万、2万。所以，
it's more just like a long-term mindset
这更像是一种长远的心态。
versus a short-term mindset.
与短视的思维方式相反。
&gt;&gt; Like delaying gratification.
就像延迟满足一样。
&gt;&gt; Delaying gratification. Yes.
延迟满足。是的。
&gt;&gt; What were you writing down there?
你当时在下面写什么？
&gt;&gt; Okay. I was writing down how the system
好的。我正在记录这个系统是如何运作的。
is rigged in the favor of rich people is
选举制度被操纵，有利于富人。
it's extraordinary because it's the it's
它非同寻常，因为它是……
the Charlie Munger quote of show me the
查理·芒格的名言：“给我看看……”
incentive and I'll show you the outcome.
给我激励，我会让你看到结果。
What people get once you get it's not
人们一旦得到它，所得到的就不是你得到的了。
the 100,000 but it's like the people
10万人，但就像人们一样
who've got 10 million in their bank
谁的银行账户里有1000万
account they get loans that are called
他们通过账户获得贷款，这些贷款被称为
non-reourse loans.
无追索权贷款。
It's an extraordinary thing because
这是一件非同寻常的事，因为
unlike your friend, they don't have to
与你的朋友不同，他们不必
pay it back.
还钱。
So, a non-reourse loan means you're not
所以，无追索权贷款意味着你不是
legally liable for the loan in the end.
最终要对贷款承担法律责任。
Now, there'll be some provisions and how
现在，会有一些规定以及如何规定。
to do it, but why are they doing this?
这样做，但他们为什么要这样做？
Why are they getting these favorable
他们为什么能获得这些优惠待遇？
terms? Why are they getting the private
条款？为什么他们会获得私人贷款
placements in stocks before they go
在股票上市前进行配售
public? Why are they getting all of the
民众？为什么他们能得到所有的
best offers? Because they pay fees.
最佳优惠？因为他们要缴纳费用。
They pay fees to the investment banks.
他们向投资银行支付费用。
And the investment banks desperately
投资银行迫切需要
want these people because they have a
想要这些人是因为他们有
lot of financial activity. And so they
金融活动频繁。于是他们
incentivize them. None of us get a look
激励他们。我们谁都没机会看。
at all of that. It's the same thing that
所有这些都是。这是同一件事，
I talked about with the hedge fund
我和对冲基金谈过。
industry in the beginning. It's like
工业的开端。就像
they were incentivized by a phase to get
他们受到某个阶段的激励去获得
information that was better than
比……更好的信息
everybody else. And I think part of that
其他人。我认为部分原因在于此
is is the ability that all we're trying
这就是我们一直在努力的方向。
to say to people is you don't have to
对人们说的是，你不必……
play the same game.
玩同样的游戏。
You don't have to pay anybody's fees.
你无需支付任何人的费用。
You buy a Bitcoin, stick it in your
你买一个比特币，把它存入你的账户
Coinbase thing or wherever. It cost you
Coinbase之类的网站。这让你付出了代价。
nothing to run and you're outperforming
无需运行任何程序，你的表现却超出了预期。
a venture capital investor. There's, you
风险投资人。有，你
know, simple things like buying an index
我知道，像购买指数这样的简单事情。
fund. You're not paying the Wall Street
基金。你不用向华尔街缴税。
complex thousands of dollars for active
复杂的活动需要花费数千美元。
management. There's ways of hacking this
管理。有办法破解这个。
and it's not that expensive to do. Just
而且这样做成本也不高。只是
before we move to Jasper, one of the
在我们搬到贾斯珀之前，其中之一
things that I think you kind of both
我觉得你们俩都有点儿……
alluded to a little bit and you said
你稍微提了一下，然后你说
earlier on was about how relationships
前面讲的是人际关系
make money and because what I was
赚钱，因为我当时
watching when I was sat in that
我当时坐在那里看着
apartment with this billionaire is his
这位亿万富翁的公寓是他的
friends and his contacts who had done
朋友和他认识的人都做过这件事
business with him in the past were
过去与他有过生意往来
getting
获得
&gt;&gt; the allocation the prime allocation of
主要分配
being able to invest just before this
能够在此时之前进行投资
company went public which means that the
公司上市了，这意味着
next day it would multiply but those
第二天它就会成倍增长，但那些
were relationships. So if if there is a
是人际关系。所以如果存在
strategy to to build wealth, it goes
积累财富的策略是这样的。
back to what Ral said at the start.
回到拉尔一开始说的话。
Being around people and having good
与人相处并拥有美好的时光
relationships is actually I think really
人际关系其实真的……
really unappreciated.
真的不被赏识。
I've got a friend I can name my friend
我有个朋友，我可以称他为我的朋友。
um called Harry Stubbings. He runs a
嗯，名叫哈里·斯塔宾斯。他经营一家
podcast called 20BC and on that podcast
一个名为“20BC”的播客，以及那个播客
he sits with extremely rich people. the
他与极其富有的人坐在一起。这
podcast. Harry's podcast isn't as big as
播客。哈里的播客节目没有那么火爆。
Joe Rogan's, but because Harry has had
乔·罗根的，但因为哈里已经有了
two-hour conversations with the richest
与最富有的人进行两小时的对话
people on planet Earth and continues to
地球上的人们，并且继续……
do so, he's built one of the biggest
这样做，他已经建立了一个最大的建筑群。
investment funds in Europe, especially
欧洲的投资基金，尤其是
as like a guy in his 20s. I mean, I
就像一个二十多岁的小伙子。我的意思是，我
think he's raised, if I'm not mistaken,
如果我没记错的话，他应该是被抚养长大的。
750 million
7.5亿
just from the relationships. And he said
仅仅是人际关系。他说
to me, he said, you know, the biggest
他说，你知道，最大的
value leverage I've built in the last 5
我在过去5年中建立的价值杠杆
10 years isn't like the views. People
十年光阴可不是白来的。人们
have more views than him. It's he had he
浏览量比他多。是他拥有的
knows everyone rich
认识所有有钱人
&gt;&gt; and and I think we underestimate that
而且我认为我们低估了这一点。
when we think about wealth creation
当我们思考财富创造时
because if you can do what Ral said and
因为如果你能做到拉尔说的那样，
get around rich people
与有钱人打交道
&gt;&gt; help them in some way build those
以某种方式帮助他们建立那些
relationships it pays dividends what
建立关系会带来丰厚的回报。
forever.
永远。
&gt;&gt; There's a there's a great guy called
有一个很棒的人，名叫
Desh Mackan who runs a firm an
德什·麦坎经营着一家公司
investment firm in in San Francisco
旧金山的投资公司
called Iconic. He was a young investment
被称为标志性的。他是一位年轻的投资者。
banker at Goldman around the same time
大约在同一时期，高盛的一位银行家
when I started there as well. But he was
我也是在那里开始工作的。但他
he was hired into the internet banking
他被聘用从事网上银行业务。
team
团队
at in 2000. He turned up the office but
2000年，他出现在办公室，但
a month later the entire thing was gone.
一个月后，所有东西都消失了。
Everybody was fired and he was too
所有人都被解雇了，他也一样。
young. He was kind of too junior to
年轻的。他资历尚浅，不太适合……
bother fire. They fired all the senior
麻烦的火。他们解雇了所有高级管理人员。
bankers and um he thought what he do. I
银行家们，嗯，他想他该怎么做。我
think he had no bosses left. So he just
我觉得他已经没有老板了。所以他就
basically went to Silicon Valley and
基本上去了硅谷，
hung out in coffee shops and made
在咖啡馆里闲逛并制作
friends. The people he happened to make
朋友们。他碰巧结识的那些人
friends with with Mark Zuckerberg, Reed
与马克·扎克伯格是朋友的里德
Hastings, Reed Hoffman, all of these
黑斯廷斯、里德·霍夫曼，所有这些人
people. But he then became their wealth
人们。但他后来成了他们的财富。
adviser at Goldman to Morgan Stanley and
高盛的顾问，为摩根士丹利提供咨询服务
then built his own firm. Iconic and
然后他创立了自己的公司。标志性的
Iconic is massive. runs all the wealth
标志性意义重大。掌控所有财富
for these Silicon Valley people from
对于这些来自硅谷的人来说
this network of meeting these random
这个网络促成了与这些随机人士的会面。
dudes building businesses when nobody
当没人的时候，这帮家伙在创建公司
else wanted to speak to them because you
其他人想和他们谈谈，因为你
know they gone through the big bust and
他们知道他们经历过那场大萧条，而且
he made his entire life on that network.
他的一生都建立在那家电视台之上。
Genius.
天才。
&gt;&gt; Probably at that cafe where I spent all
大概是在我待了那么久的那家咖啡馆吧
my bitcoin.
我的比特币。
&gt;&gt; The one with the gold door. You were
就是那扇金色大门的。你曾是
there at the same time sending zero
同时发送零
bitcoin.
比特币。
It's interesting because when we talk
这很有趣，因为当我们谈论
about systems and all these things for
关于系统以及所有这些事情
money, nobody ever talks about a system
金钱，没人谈论制度。
for managing your relationships. And the
用于管理你的人际关系。以及
way that most of us manage our
我们大多数人管理自身的方式
relationships is we get someone's
人际关系就是我们获得某人的东西
number.
数字。
&gt;&gt; Mhm.
嗯。
&gt;&gt; And we hope that we'll cross paths
我们希望能够相遇。
again. But I think I even I'm thinking
再次。但我认为我甚至在思考
about obviously I do this podcast where
很显然，我做这个播客节目
I meet so many great people. I should
我遇到了很多很棒的人。我应该
have a much better system for
拥有更好的系统
understanding those relationships, how I
理解这些关系，我如何
can be of service to those people,
可以为这些人提供帮助，
understanding their birthdays and all
了解他们的生日等等
these other kinds of things. And uh not
其他这类事情。呃，不是
only would that be good for my mental
只有那样才对我的精神健康有益
health in more friends, less all these
多交朋友，少一些这些，更健康。
kinds of sort of social psychological
某种社会心理学
things, but in business terms, there's
事情就是这样，但从商业角度来看，有……
going to be opportunities whether it's
无论是什么，都会有机会。
six years from now where I need your
六年后的今天，我需要你
advice.
建议。
&gt;&gt; The the key to networks
网络的关键
is it's what you put into the network,
这取决于你输入到网络中的内容。
not what you take out.
不是你拿出来的东西。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. So the people who have the best
是的。所以那些拥有最好的人
networks I've ever seen are always the
我见过的所有网络总是
people say, "How can I help you?"
人们会问：“我能帮您什么忙？”
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; Hey, I've got something for you. You
嘿，我这儿有东西要给你。你
should meet so and so.
应该与某某见面。
&gt;&gt; Oh, yeah.
哦，是的。
&gt;&gt; It's never,
从来都不是，
&gt;&gt; hey, listen, what can you do for me?
嘿，听着，你能帮我什么忙？
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; That comes back. Karma flows back
那件事还会再发生。因果报应终会到来。
always. Give as much into the network as
总是。尽可能多地向网络贡献力量
possible and the network gives back.
有可能，而且网络也会给予回报。
&gt;&gt; I think that's what in the case of
我认为这就是这种情况。
Harry, he's also done because funnily
哈利，他也完蛋了，因为有趣的是
enough about a month ago, I said, "Oh,
大约一个月前，我说：“哦，
I've got this idea to do this thing."
我有个想法要做这件事。
And Harry turned around to me 30 seconds
哈利转过身来看着我，30秒后。
within WhatsApp and said, "Oh, I know
在WhatsApp中，他说：“哦，我知道。”
insert name of this person who's the
插入此人的姓名
very top in investing in Europe. I'll
欧洲顶级投资机构。患病的
put you in a WhatsApp group with him.
把你和他拉进一个WhatsApp群里。
Put me in a WhatsApp group with this
请把我加入这个WhatsApp群组。
guy." Sent a voice note said, "Steve's
那个人。” 发了一条语音留言说：“史蒂夫的
the best ever." Then he said, he said,
“史上最佳。”然后他说，他说，
"Steve's way better than I am.
“史蒂夫比我强多了。”
Everything." This is literally what he
一切。” 这就是他所说的。
said. And then he said about the guy who
说。然后他说起那个人，
put me in the WhatsApp group. He goes,
请把我加入WhatsApp群组。他走了，
"And this guy's also the best at what he
“而且这家伙在他所擅长的领域也是最棒的。”
does ever putting you two together. Good
曾经有人把你们两个撮合在一起。好的
luck." And immediately I thought,
运气。”我立刻想到，
"Fucking hell, Harry's what a great
“我的天哪，哈利真是个了不起的人。”
guy." And then the guy he' introduced me
“那个人。”然后他介绍给我的那个人。”
to goes, "Isn't Harry such a great guy?
有人说：“哈利真是个好人啊！”
And so I measured her like listen if
于是我像听着一样衡量她。
there's anything I can do for you. But
我能为你做任何事。但
that's the karma that
这就是因果报应。
&gt;&gt; honestly I you know I really believe in
说实话，你知道我真的相信
networks. I think it's the most
网络。我认为这是最
important thing. Your community your
重要的事情。你的社区
network is everything. And the absolute
网络至关重要。以及绝对的
answer is you have to keep putting into
答案是你必须不断投入
the network
网络
cuz if you try and um extract from the
因为如果你尝试从……中提取
network it collapses.
网络崩溃了。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. because then you're just that guy
是的。因为那样你就只是个普通人了。
who's making the phone call after 10
10点以后是谁打的电话
years saying, "Hey, Stephen, can I get
多年来我一直说，“嘿，斯蒂芬，我能……”
some money from you because I've run out
我需要你给我一些钱，因为我没钱了。
of cash?"
现金？
&gt;&gt; The last thing I wanted to talk about is
我最后想谈的是……
the UK and the US and geographies
英国和美国以及地理位置
generally and how much that plays a role
总体而言，以及这发挥了多大作用
because right now there's lots of
因为现在有很多
political social conversations about the
关于政治和社会对话
UK. People are a little bit doomer about
英国。人们对未来有点悲观。
the UK. Some people are optimistic about
英国。有些人对未来持乐观态度。
the US, some aren't. How much do you
美国有些国家不是这样。你多少钱
think about geographies when you're
当你……的时候，想想地理。
thinking about your wealth creation,
思考如何创造财富，
your finance strategy? Does it play a
你的财务策略是什么？它是否发挥了作用？
role?
角色？
&gt;&gt; So, I was fortunate enough to live in
所以，我很幸运能住在
London for a little bit over a month or
在伦敦待了一个多月，或者
so. And I did a number of podcasts out
所以。我还做了一些播客节目。
there and well, I guess I could just ask
嗯，我想我可以直接问。
you. The interesting thing about these
你。这些有趣的地方在于
podcasts is when I was talking to them,
我跟他们聊天的时候就在播客里。
what they told me is that the majority
他们告诉我，大多数人
of their listener base is in the United
他们的听众群体主要在美国。
States. The majority of their money
各州。他们的大部分资金
comes from the United States. the
来自美国。这
majority of their sponsors come from the
他们的大部分赞助商来自……
United States. It's not from the UK. And
美国。它不是英国的。和
I thought that was very interesting
我觉得这很有意思。
because it's a it's a huge market. But
因为这是一个巨大的市场。但
what they were saying is people who are
他们说的是那些人
really looking to grow in the United
真心希望在美国发展壮大
Kingdom, a lot of them at least, just
王国，至少很多王国，就是这样
from what I heard, would prefer to earn
据我所知，他更愿意赚钱。
from the United States because the
来自美国，因为
dollar figures are much higher. Now, I
美元数字要高得多。现在，我
don't have a lot of global experience
缺乏全球经验
outside of that, but I do think that the
除此之外，但我确实认为
United States is more friendly for
美国对……更友好
people that are interested in wealth
对财富感兴趣的人
growth, wealth accumulation. Uh maybe
增长，财富积累。呃，也许吧
not the best. There's taxfree countries
不是最好的。有些国家免税。
out there, but in terms of for somebody
外面确实存在这种情况，但就某些人来说……
who is more entrepreneurial in that
谁在这方面更有创业精神
sense, I think you have a lot of
我觉得你很有见地。
opportunities here that you don't have
这里有一些你没有的机会。
other places.
其他地方。
&gt;&gt; What do you think, Ram?
拉姆，你怎么看？
&gt;&gt; I'm a huge believer in uh geographic
我非常相信地理因素。
location for a number of different
多个不同地点
reasons. So, I've lived in the UK,
原因。我曾在英国生活过，
India, Spain, and the Cayman Islands. I
印度、西班牙和开曼群岛。我
spent most my working career on this
我职业生涯的大部分时间都投入到了这项工作中。
side of the pond in the US. Spain is
美国大西洋彼岸。西班牙是
lifestyle arbitrage.
生活方式套利。
The cost of living is even probably half
生活成本甚至可能只有原来的一半。
that of the UK and a third of that what
英国的那个，还有其中的三分之一是什么
it is in the US or the Cayman Islands.
它位于美国或开曼群岛。
300 days of sunshine, incredible people,
300天的阳光，令人惊叹的人们，
culture, climate, cost is very cheap,
文化、气候、生活成本非常低廉
rent is cheap, to buy is cheap,
租房便宜，买房也便宜。
everything. Perfect lifestyle arbitrage.
一切。完美的生活方式套利机会。
Problem is network. you're not
问题出在网络上。你不
surrounded by people who are ambitious
身边都是雄心勃勃的人
doing different stuff. In a globalized
做不同的事情。在全球化的背景下
world now where we can work online, it's
如今的世界已经发展到我们可以在线工作的状态，这真是太好了。
actually doable. So, we're seeing a lot
实际上可行。所以，我们看到了很多。
of Americans moving down to Latin
美国人移居拉丁美洲
America. That's the arbitrage here, uh,
美国。这就是套利机会所在，嗯。
or Colombia as well. So, into South
或者哥伦比亚也行。所以，进入南方
America, Latin America, it's cheap, high
美国、拉丁美洲，价格便宜，价格高昂
quality of life, relatively safe, and if
生活质量高，相对安全，而且如果
you're in a business where you can work
你身处一个可以工作的行业
online, okay, you you can get to your
在线，好的，你可以访问你的
end goal, your coastfire thing super
最终目标，你的海岸火超级
fast by doing that. If you want to your
这样做速度很快。如果你想……
point, if you want intellectual capital,
关键在于，如果你想要知识资本，
there is only one place in the world
世界上只有一个地方
that has it in such high density, the
它密度如此之高，
US. Capital and intellectual capital.
我们。资本和知识资本。
Asia has it, India has it. You know,
亚洲有，印度有。你知道，
it's all around, but they're all missing
它们无处不在，但却都不见了。
different forms of it. So, it's using
它的不同形式。所以，它正在使用
that for your end goals.
这符合你的最终目标。
&gt;&gt; What about the UK?
英国的情况如何？
&gt;&gt; I can't do it because
我做不到，因为
the UK's attitude now has become we just
英国现在的态度已经变成了我们只是
can't have nice things. They don't want
不能拥有美好的事物。他们不想要
to, if I speak to my friends, they don't
而且，如果我和朋友们说起这件事，他们也不会。
want to invest. They they just want to
想投资。他们，他们只是想
have the bigger house and and the next
拥有更大的房子，以及下一个
car on lease. People are institutionally
租赁车辆。人们在制度上
unhappy in the UK right now and there
现在在英国过得不太开心，而且
has been for a while. And so we don't
已经有一段时间了。所以我们不
have a culture of entrepreneurialism
拥有创业文化
left. It's been stamped out Europe too.
左边。这种现象在欧洲也已被根除。
So it's not just the UK. Everywhere in
所以这不仅仅发生在英国。到处
Europe, the same thing has happened.
同样的事情也发生在欧洲。
People just don't believe they can have
人们就是不相信他们能拥有
nice things anymore. When you think
美好的事物已不复存在。当你思考的时候
about the narrative
关于叙事
that you understand of the UK, like what
你对英国的了解，比如什么？
is the the message? So, if it was like a
这就是信息吗？所以，如果它就像……
marketing slogan, the UK, you're an
营销口号：英国，你是
investor, you're an entrepreneur, what
投资者，你也是企业家，你呢？
in your head when you think of the UK,
当你想到英国时，你脑海中会浮现出什么？
what comes out?
出来的是什么？
&gt;&gt; What is it in reality or what would be
实际上它是什么？或者说，它会是什么？
how would you sell the UK to others?
你会如何向其他国家推销英国？
&gt;&gt; No, I'm saying like what do you think of
不，我是问你觉得怎么样？
what do you think the narrative of the
你认为这个故事的叙述方式是什么？
UK is right now as an investor and
英国目前正处于投资者的位置
entrepreneur?
企业家？
&gt;&gt; I think it just feels like a backwater.
我觉得那里就像个偏僻落后的地方。
&gt;&gt; Backwater. Yeah, it's an economic
偏僻的地方。是的，这是经济问题。
backwater.
偏僻的地方。
&gt;&gt; So, don't forget in the late 90s and
所以，别忘了90年代末期和
2000s, it was this entire center of the
2000年代，整个中心
world's financial industry. It was the
世界金融业。那是
center of the world's advertising
世界广告中心
industry. It was some of the, you know,
行业。你知道，那是其中的一些事。
all the creative industries. It was all
所有创意产业。这一切都是
based in London. We lost all of it.
总部位于伦敦。我们全都失去了。
&gt;&gt; Why?
为什么？
&gt;&gt; Regulation.
规定。
&gt;&gt; So, you think it's the government's
所以，你认为这是政府的
government have misstepped?
政府是否犯了错误？
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Yeah, the government misstepped
是的。是的，政府犯了错误。
and the US took the banking system back
美国重新掌控了银行体系。
because how they treated uh capital
因为他们对待资本的方式
requirements in the UK and Europe was
英国和欧洲的要求是
different than the US and they managed
与美国不同，他们做到了。
to get the Wall Street back to Wall
让华尔街回归正轨
Street. It all moved. I was working for
街道。一切都在移动。我当时在为……工作
Goldman Sachs, London was their biggest
高盛伦敦分公司是他们最大的分支机构。
office. Same for JP Morgan, Morgan
办公室。摩根大通也是如此。
Stanley, everybody. And we just stopped
斯坦利，各位。然后我们就停了下来
it and now we're seeing it again. We've
它发生了，现在我们又看到了。我们已经
got new industries rising. We've got AI,
新兴产业正在崛起。我们已经拥有人工智能，
crypto, you know, AI came out of
加密货币，你知道，人工智能就是从那里诞生的。
Cambridge. I think it was, you know, the
剑桥。我想那是，你知道，那
Google Deep Mind. And I think it was
谷歌DeepMind。我觉得是
Cambridge University for most of that
大部分时间都在剑桥大学就读。
stuff. And we dropped the ball. We
东西。我们搞砸了。我们
dropped the ball in the finance
在财务方面犯了错。
industry. We dropped the ball in AI. We
行业。我们在人工智能领域犯了错。我们
get this massive talent density coming
让这种高密度的人才涌现
out of Oxford and Cambridge, Imperial
毕业于牛津大学和剑桥大学，帝国理工学院
College and all these others. And we we
大学以及其他所有相关经历。我们
don't use it. They all move to the US.
不要使用它。他们都移居美国。
We had the crypto industry of which we
我们拥有加密货币行业，我们
were part of that. We we dropped that
我们是其中的一份子。我们放弃了那个
ball too. We dropped the whole ball on
球也是。我们彻底搞砸了
everything. And Europe is actively
一切。欧洲正在积极行动
shutting the door on every opportunity
错失一切机会
um by saying we don't want to do this
嗯，意思是说我们不想这样做。
there. Don't forget they're a nation of
那里。别忘了他们是一个民族
old people now, most most of Europe. So
现在欧洲大部分地区都是老年人。所以
they rather just not have any change.
他们宁愿不要零钱。
But if we go back to that economic
但如果我们回到经济层面，就会发现这一点。
formula for GDP growth, population
GDP增长公式，人口
growth is the key driver. You need a
增长是关键驱动力。你需要一个
growing population over time, but it
人口随时间增长，但是
just needs to be in a done in the right
只需要以正确的方式完成即可
way. So they're blaming that, but the
方式。所以他们把责任推卸给那件事，但是
whole economic machine is because
整个经济机器之所以如此运转，是因为
nobody's had kids. That's the pro the
没有人有孩子。这就是优点
demographic problem is the structure of
人口问题是结构性问题
everything. And the problem is is
一切。问题在于……
nobody's had kids. So you don't have
没有人有孩子。所以你没有
economic growth. So then you try and
经济增长。所以你试着……
bring in new workers to create growth.
引进新员工以促进增长。
You don't want that. So they get thrown
你不想那样。所以他们就被扔了
out. Meanwhile, the economy slows down.
出去。与此同时，经济增长放缓。
People get pulled back. They don't want
人们被拉了回去。他们不想要
to take risk anymore. The whole system
不再冒险了。整个系统
is now having to pay for the National
现在不得不为国家支付费用
Health Service to pay for these old
医疗服务机构将支付这些老年人的费用
people. There's not enough kids to
人们。孩子不够多
support all of that. The governments are
我完全支持。各国政府是
getting more in debt. Bond yields are
负债越来越多。债券收益率是
going up. Everyone's like, "What's going
向上。大家都在问：“发生了什么事？”
on?" It's all been a function of
“继续？”这一切都取决于
demographics from day one.
从一开始就关注人口统计数据。
&gt;&gt; Closing arguments. Um Humphrey, closing
结案陈词。嗯，汉弗莱，结束。
position. What's the most important
位置。最重要的是什么？
thing people should be thinking about?
人们应该思考什么？
How would you round off? Is there
你会如何取整？有没有
anything that I didn't ask you that I
还有什么我没问过你的吗？
should have asked you?
我应该问问你吗？
&gt;&gt; Yeah, I think that my my personal
是的，我认为我的个人
philosophy is just that personal finance
哲学就是个人理财。
just comes down to your income minus
归根结底就是你的收入减去
your expenses. So, know those two
你的开支。所以，要知道这两个人。
intimately. Know how to drive both of
亲密地。会开这两种车
those two. And then just really watch
那两个人。然后就好好看看。
what you spend your money on, right?
你把钱花在哪儿了，对吧？
Like the car pay the average car payment
就像支付平均汽车月供一样
in America is 745 a month. Stay away
在美国是每月745美元。远离
from that if you can. Try to try to be
如果可以的话，就从那里开始吧。努力尝试成为
reasonable. Everything is about about
合理的。一切都与……有关
being consistent and reasonable. And I
始终如一，合情合理。我
think those small decisions compound to
想想那些小的决定会累积成什么样子。
a much brighter future.
一个更加光明的未来。
real
真实的
&gt;&gt; for me
为我
first thing is educate yourself. You
首先要做的就是自我学习。你
don't know you know we talked about what
不知道你知不知道我们谈过什么
do your finances look like? What's your
你的财务状况如何？你的
bank account look like? What are you
银行账户长什么样？你是做什么的
trying to achieve? Right? So educate
试图达成什么目标？正确的？所以要接受教育
yourself. Learn about investing. Invest
你自己。了解投资知识。投资
above all things. Investing above saving
高于一切。投资高于储蓄
is the only way you're going to get
这是你获得它的唯一途径
there because if not your money goes
因为如果不这样，你的钱就没了。
down. And then just do it. Make a trade.
向下。然后就去做。进行交易。
Make an investment. Fail. Learn. Do it
进行投资。失败。学习。去做
again. And do it again. And keep
再次。再来一次。并保持
learning, educating. And then surround
学习，教育。然后包围
yourself
你自己
by a good network. Just be whether it's
通过良好的人脉网络。无论它是什么，都无所谓。
even on Twitter, on social media, find a
即使在推特等社交媒体上，也能找到
network of people that you can learn
你可以学习的人脉网络
from. Add to the network and those
从。添加到网络和那些
things you will you'll get ahead. You
你会做的事情会让你领先一步。你
can't fail if you educate yourself. Just
只要你自学，就不会失败。只是
get started and then learn, keep doing
开始行动，然后学习，坚持下去。
it then and just grow a great network
然后就着手发展壮大人脉网络。
&gt;&gt; and buy Bitcoin
并购买比特币
&gt;&gt; obviously.
明显地。
&gt;&gt; What what what coins do you own in
你拥有哪些硬币？
crypto? So I am so this is going to get
加密货币？所以，我……所以这将会……
more contentious now. So I actually
现在争议更大了。所以，我其实
don't I own just one Bitcoin for
难道我不只有一枚比特币吗？
posterity sake.
为了后世。
&gt;&gt; Oh Okay.
哦，该死。好的。
&gt;&gt; So I own
所以我拥有
&gt;&gt; I'll delete the episode then.
那我把这集删掉。
&gt;&gt; My I am own mainly Sooie which is the
我主要拥有 Sooie，这是
which is the um the crypto network that
也就是加密网络。
came out of Facebook.
源自 Facebook。
&gt;&gt; But I'm also on the foundation as well.
但我同时也是基金会的成员。
But I actually put most of my liquid net
但我实际上把大部分液体都放进了网里
worth into that. Uh and then I own a lot
值得投入其中。嗯，然后我还有很多东西。
of digital art on Ethereum.
在以太坊上进行数字艺术创作。
&gt;&gt; Um because that's a a long-term store of
嗯，因为那是一个长期储存的……
value for me. NFTs
对我而言很有价值。 NFT
&gt;&gt; and I yeah NFTs and so I've moved around
是的，我还有NFT，所以我就四处搬家了。
a lot between you know Bitcoin,
你们之间有很多关于比特币的知识，
Ethereum, Salana and Sooie I don't trade
我不交易以太坊、Salana 和 Sooie。
so these are long-term holds I might
所以这些都是我可能会长期持有的股票。
change once every two years change my
每两年更换一次我的
allocation so but it's all generally all
分配就是这样，但总的来说都是如此
the big big tokens
大型代币
&gt;&gt; and just pre closing statements
以及结算前声明
&gt;&gt; well first off thank you Rahul Humphrey
首先，谢谢你，拉胡尔·汉弗莱。
and Stema for putting this together this
感谢 Stema 促成此事
is and to add on to everything that you
是，并且还要加上你所拥有的一切
guys said for me I think there's a lot
伙计们都说我觉得有很多。
of for lack of a better word crap um on
呃，说得不好听点，就是一堆废话。
the internet of people romanticizing and
互联网上人们浪漫化和
fantasizing how easy it is for passive
幻想被动方有多么容易
income or for insane levels of wealth
收入或惊人的财富水平
where it becomes uh sometimes hard to
有时很难
see how you could actually do that. And
看看你究竟该如何做到这一点。和
what I'd like to say is look, nothing
我想说的是，你看，没什么
comes easy, but change can always be
容易做到，但改变总是可能的。
made regardless of where you are, what
无论你身在何处，无论什么
your background is, where you come from,
你的背景，也就是你来自哪里，
but it's going to take work. And I think
但这需要付出努力。我觉得
the best thing to help your outcome to
最有利于你取得理想结果的方法是
get to where you want to go is hard
到达你想去的地方并不容易
work, sacrifice,
工作、牺牲、
put in what I call a decade of
投入我所谓的十年
sacrifice. That way you can have uh what
牺牲。那样你就可以……什么
most people dream of. And the only
这是大多数人的梦想。而唯一
reason why you're able to get there is
你之所以能到达那里，原因是
because you're willing to do what the
因为你愿意做……
majority of people are not willing to
大多数人都不愿意
do.
做。
&gt;&gt; And in a word, AI positive about it or
总之，人工智能对此持积极态度。
pessimistic?
悲观？
&gt;&gt; Positive.
积极的。
&gt;&gt; Best tool we've ever been given.
这是我们迄今为止得到的最好的工具。
&gt;&gt; Optimistic. Yeah. Okay, good.
乐观的。是的。好的。
Refreshing. Very refreshing to you.
令人耳目一新。对你来说真是耳目一新。
Thank you all so much for giving me your
非常感谢大家给我你们的……
time today. I'm I'm going to link the
今天的时间。我要把链接
top three things that you tell me we
你告诉我的最重要的三件事
should direct the audience to below. So,
应引导观众阅读以下内容。所以，
I'll ask you after this conversation to
这次谈话结束后我会问你……
give me three things where people can
请给我三件人们可以做的事情
find you. The first is going to be your
找到你。首先是你的
channels. So, your channel's on YouTube.
频道。所以，你的频道在YouTube上。
You're all very large YouTubers um and
你们都是非常有名的YouTube博主，嗯……
have incredible channels, channels that
拥有令人难以置信的频道，这些频道
I followed for many, many years. Um is
我关注了很多很多年。嗯是
there anything else that you guys would
你们还有什么想说的吗？
like me to link that you think is going
像我一样把这个链接发给你，你觉得会怎么样？
to be pertinent to the audience? Well,
要与受众相关？出色地，
we have a free newsletter for investors
我们为投资者提供免费的简讯。
that we publish every single day called
我们每天都会发布名为“
Market Briefs. I think that would be a
市场简报。我觉得那会是一个
great one.
很棒。
&gt;&gt; I'll link that one as well. Anything
我也会把那个链接发给你。任何事物
else?
别的？
&gt;&gt; Real Vision is a simple place. It's a
Real Vision 是一个简单的地方。这是一个
simple home for everybody to find what
每个人都能找到的简单家园
they need. So,
他们需要。所以，
&gt;&gt; the website realvision.com or
网站 realvision.com 或
&gt;&gt; realvision.com.
realvision.com。
&gt;&gt; Okay. And Humphrey.
好的。还有汉弗莱。
&gt;&gt; And I'm building a website right now.
我现在正在建一个网站。
That's uh basically my my guide, but
嗯，这基本上就是我的指南了，但是……
it's my guide on different financial
这是我关于不同金融领域的指南。
products. So, it's humphreguide.com.
产品。所以，网址是 humphreguide.com。
Humphregu.com.
Humphregu.com。
&gt;&gt; Appreciate it.
谢谢。
&gt;&gt; Thank you so much.
太感谢了。
[Music]
[音乐]